As I mentioned last class, there are
three major questions that will
determine how this war is fought, what
the what this war
will end up looking like, and how the
world will change.
And as I discussed last class, I'm
making three predictions about this war.
The first is United States will use
ground troops.
And this will mean that
Donald Trump will institute a national
draft. Okay? That's the first
prediction. Second prediction is that
Israel and the United States will not
use tactical nuclear weapons in this
war.
Number three is that the Al-Aqsa Mosque,
the third holiest site in the Islamic
world, will be destroyed during this
war.
Okay, so last class, I explained my
analysis and my reasoning for
my first two predictions. Today, I'll
explain my
third prediction. So, but before we
start, I just want to look at some
videos, okay? So, you understand some of
the context, some of the players in this
war. All right, so this is Senator
Blumenthal of Connecticut, and he is one
of the 100 members of the US Senate.
He's also one
of the members of the Gang of Eight.
Now,
when when you are fighting a war,
the White House has responsibility to
report its
objectives, its purpose,
how the war is progressing to eight
members
of Congress in a confidential setting,
okay? And this is um
Senator Blumenthal after he's been
debriefed by
the White House. Okay, and this is what
he has to say about the progress of the
war so far.
I emerge from this briefing
as dissatisfied
and angry, frankly,
as I have from any
past briefing
in my 15 years in the Senate.
I am
left with more questions than answers,
especially about the cost of the war.
My questions [snorts]
have been unanswered.
And I will demand answers because the
American people deserve to know.
And
I guess I am most
concerned about the threat to American
lives
of potentially deploying our sons and
daughters on the ground in Iran. We seem
to be on a path
toward deploying American troops on the
ground in Iran
to accomplish any of the potential
objectives here.
And
there is also
as disturbingly as anything else, this
factor of active Russian aid to Iran
putting in danger
American lives.
All right.
So, three things to take away from
his talk with reporters, okay? The first
thing is
>> [snorts]
>> the administration, Donald Trump, the
White House, has not articulated a
budget. How much will this war cost?
Which means that this is an open-ended
war. We don't know when this war will
end.
And so, we don't know what the
commitment is, and so we don't know how
much this war will cost, okay? That's
the first point he makes. The second
point he makes is we are on a path
towards the deployment of ground troops
in Iran.
Okay, and that basically means a
national draft. Now, the third thing
that's crucial is he says that they know
for a fact that Russia is already
involved
in this war aiding Iran.
Okay? So, that's the three main
takeaways
from
um
Okay, so this is um
um the foreign minister of Iran, Zarif,
talking to NBC News. All right. And NBC
News is going to ask Zarif, "Hey,
there's talk United States already of
ground troops being used against
uh Iran, okay?" Now, I want you to
observe his response and then the
response of the journalist.
President Trump has not ruled out boots
on the ground in Iran. Are you afraid of
a [snorts] US invasion in your country?
No, we are waiting for them.
You you were waiting for the US military
to invade, the ground troops?
Yes.
Because [clears throat] we we are
confident that we can confront them, and
that would be a big disaster for them.
Okay, do you understand? Okay.
So, you're saying that that Iran is
ready and willing to take on the US
military if there were to be ground
troops?
Well, we were ready for this. Okay, so
again, certain things to appreciate.
First of all, the foreign minister,
Zarif, he is not at all concerned about
ground troops. In fact, he basically
said, "It's a trap for you guys. You
come in, we've been preparing for about
20 years for this, we will destroy you."
Another thing that you will notice is
the journalist is completely surprised
by the answer. He's shocked into
silence. He has asked again, "Wait, are
you saying you're ready for ground
troops?"
And so, this shows you that within
Washington, D.C., okay, within
the Trump administration, within the
foreign policy elite, within the media
elite, they haven't really thought this
through. They haven't really
considered the possibility
of losing this war. Washington, D.C.
right now, it's a bubble, okay? It's an
insular bubble where everyone just
believes the same things, and that's
very problematic um if you are to
continue fighting this war, okay?
>> [snorts]
>> All right, let's continue.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay,
this is um
um
Rabbi Schneerson.
And he is the leader, or he used to be
he he's died, but he used to be the
leader of an organization called the
Chabad Lubavitch. I'll be talking more
about Chabad Lubavitch as we go along,
okay? But I introduce you to him now.
This is the year 1990, and he is talking
to Benjamin Netanyahu, who is who is a
young up-and-coming
politician in Israel, okay? And so,
let's look at the conversation.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay, so what's going on here? Okay, so
as an up-and-coming politician,
Netanyahu is going to a rabbi, and the
rabbis are the most powerful people in
the Jewish society. He basically says,
"Will you give me your blessing? Will
you support me in my political
endeavors?" The rabbi says, "Yes." They
also talk about how things are
progressing, okay? So, another way of
saying this is that there's almost like
a plan in motion to achieve certain
religious objectives, and things are
going well. But the
Rabbi Schneerson says,
"But they're not going fast enough,
because we need the Messiah,
the great leader of the Jewish people,
to come, and we can set in motion things
that will force the coming of the
Messiah. So, let's speed things up,
Netanyahu."
Okay? So, what this is, I'll explain
later on, okay? But I want you to be
aware of this, who these people are.
Rabbi Schneerson is very important for