A couple quick announcements before we
start class.
Next Thursday will be our last class and
we will do the final examination
next Thursday. It'll be the same format
as the midterm examination where you can
prepare some questions and we will
review what we've learned so far in
class.
Um if you are on YouTube and you want to
ask some questions, please leave the
question behind. um in the comment
section and my wife will go over and
sect um some questions for us to do next
Thursday. Next Tuesday we will do an
overview of everything we've learned so
far and make certain predictions about
the next 5 to 10 years. Okay? So next
week will be our last week. Um today I
want to talk about Putin in Beijing. So
he came to Beijing
um Tuesday evening. He had a full day
yesterday and then he left last night.
And um as you can see, President Putin
and President C are very good friends.
They went to a conference hall where
they unveiled a photo of the two being
very close. Um, this is President
Putin's 25th visit to China and in
November he's coming back to Shenzhen to
attend APAC and that'll be his 26. He's
a very good friend of China's and the
two are very close. This is the two of
them at an education conference
announcing a year of education exchange
between Russia and China. And the goal
is to enhance people-to-people
um connections between China and Russia.
The major
um
output of the meeting was
their different perspectives
on the multipolar world. Okay. So um
this is a part of President C's speech
and this is a part of Putin uh President
Putin's speech and this is um this is
actually AI translation. So the transl
translation is very bad but I will point
out certain things. Okay. So both are
committed to
a multipolar world and what uh President
C and President Putin both want are more
exchanges okay bilateral student
exchanges
uh deepen interactions in universities
do more research together. He also is
afraid of the turbulence in the world
and he's very much afraid of a return to
the law of the jungle where might is
right. So it's very important for the
world to work together in order to
maintain the rulesbased international uh
order. And what President C says is that
as prudent members of the UN Security
Council, China and Russia will work
together to uphold the authority of the
UN international justice and oppose all
manifestations of unilateralism and
hijgemony. Um resurrecting signs of
fascism and militarism. Okay. And this
specifically refers to Germany and
Japan.
Okay. So he sees um the possibility of
nationalism, a resurgence of nationalism
in Japan as a threat to the peace in
East Asia into the world in general.
Okay. So China is most resol resolutely
opposed to the remilitarization of uh
Japan. Putin says the same thing same
things almost but the tone is very
different. Okay. So um first of all
Putin is much actually more specific
than presidency about areas of
cooperation. Okay. So for example uh the
tent Russia
China summer games and also cooperation
in between different media outlets. Um
and he also talks about how it's
important to
maintain independent autonomous foreign
policies at the same time work together
to stabilize the global um stage working
together for peace and universal
prosperity. This is the logic behind
Moscow and Beijing's joint defense of
international law and the provisions of
the UN charter in their entirety
comprehensive and inter relationship.
Okay. So it sounds like they're saying
the same thing but again the emphasis is
different. Whereas in China, China's
very very much focus on maintaining a
status quo a rules based national order
but in the UN at the very top and for
the UN
China and Russia will work towards
um ensuring global stability for
President Putin. What's important is
that China and Russia they take the lead
in leading the multipolar world. Okay.
So these are two very different
conceptions of how the world should be
run where the China the Chinese system
is let's just maintain the way things
are and we'll play a supportive role
whereas Putin is like no Russia and
China should be the leaders of this new
multipolar world. China can be the
leader and will be a junior partner but
we need to take the initiative in
promoting global stability. Okay. Um
this is much more clearer. Okay. where
this is actually a joint statement
between Russia and China where they
advocate
uh multipolar world and Russia and China
undertake and call on the international
community to adhere to the following
basic principles in their relations with
one another. Number one
uh maintaining open trade okay
maintaining sovereignty of different
nations maintaining
decision- making through consensus okay
primary the United Nations maintaining
authority of the UN and respecting the
civilizations of each different nation
state so refusing to prioritize one
civilization over another. All right.
So, this is something that both Russia
and China agree to. Now, this is
actually a much better translation of
President C's words about the
multi-polar world. Okay, so let's read
it together. The world today is far from
tranquil.
Unilateralism and hedgemanism are doing
grave harm and the world faces the
danger of sliding back to the law of the
jungle. As permanent members of the UN
Security Council, China and Russia must
firmly carry out the mission and
responsibility of major countries,
defend the authority of their nations,
international fairness and justice,
oppose all unilateral bullying and acts
that turn the will of history backward,
and especially oppose all provocations
that negate that negate the victorious
outcomes of World War II or that seek to
reverse the verdict on and summon back
the spirits of fascism and militarism,
jointly pushing for the building of a
more just and reasonable glob. global
governance system. Okay. All right. So,
this is a lot of words, but I will
emphasize certain takeaways. First of
all, what President C is saying is that
there were three major winners of World
War II, the United States, Russia, and
China. And we must ensure that these
three nations who won World War II are
still in charge. Okay. Okay. This is
really important to understand. First of
all, US, Russia, and China are allies,
not enemies, right? Because right now a
lot of people think that China and the
United States are in competition to rule
the world. And President C says, "No,
that's not true. We're allies because we
won World War II together."
All right. Second, he sees the real
enemies as those who are trying to
overturn the World War II order. And
those nations of course are Japan,
Germany, and Israel.
And the last thing he will point out is
that all unilateralism and hedgemonism
are bad.
Okay? If you act by yourself and you
declare war against other nations,
that's bad. So obviously the United
States attacking Venezuela is bad.
Obviously the United States attacking
Iran is bad.
But
what about Russia attacking Ukraine?
Well, according to this framework, this
is also bad. Okay,
according to this logic of what he said
specifically, this is also bad.
So it seems as though China and Russia
are best friends and they will unify
against United States together. But this
statement reveals that actually things
aren't as simple as they seem. All
right.
Also, what's important for us to
understand is that yes, there are many
areas where China and Russia can work
together, but the cooperation is not
going as smoothly as one would imagine.
Okay. So, let's look at some some some
examples. First of all, the economic
cooperation between China, United
States, it is booming.
Uh what's happening is that China needs
a lot of energy and resources from
Russia. So you you would think that they
would build infrastructure as soon as
possible to make this trade as smooth as
possible, right? Especially with this
war going on in the Middle East,
blocking China's access to the Middle
East. uh energy
but
um and the main pillar of this
corporation is something called the
power cyber barrier 2. Okay, as you can
see it extends all the way from the
north of Russia to Shanghai. It's a huge
project
and everyone has assumed that at this
meeting the first thing that they would
accomplish is signing anou an agreement
to build this pipeline and they have not
done so
and a lot of it is because
China does not want to become too
dependent on Russia because obviously if
you build this pipeline then you must
buy a lot of energy from Russia. and but
they want to still negotiate over the
price as well as the volume. Okay,
so that's one area. Second area is Iran.
As you can see, the Russians are
absolutely supportive of the Iranians.
Right? So what Vlamir Putin says is
this absolute unprovoked aggression of
US bombing against Iran has no basis and
notification whatsoever. For our part,
we are making our efforts to assist the
Iranian people. Okay, this so this is
this was last June actually when America
bombed Iran.
Um the Chinese on the other hand are
much more nuanced and much more
diplomatic. So President C says um
Israel's military operation against Iran
has caused a sudden escalation of
tensions in the Middle East. Uh mil
conflicts are not the solution of
problems.
Okay. So the Chinese are much more muted
and this shows us that whereas the
Russians are much more clear about their
regional alliances, China does not want
to participate in disputes among
different nations. Okay.
All right. So
one area of cooperation
uh between Russia and China is trade
routes. All right. So as we discussed
previously uh in this class, what the
Americans want to do is they want to
block China from um accessing global
trade and they can do that by closing
off the straight of Mala. Okay, there's
something called the Malaca dilemma for
China where if the Americans were to
close out the straight of Malaa,
China Chinese trade would collapse. So
the solution is for China to build a
another route to the north called the
northern sea route with Russia. Okay?
But the problem with this is that now
you're completely dependent on the
Russians because you're going through
Russian territory. Okay? So it's not an
advantage of China to say, you know
what, screw you America. We're going to
work with the Russians. They're actually
better off balancing
Russia and China. That way they keep
both of these routes open. Okay. This is
the most economical, this is the most
strategic way of um accessing global
trade. Okay.
Um but the further you look
there are certain tension points in the
relationship between Russia and China.
First of all, this relationship clearly
favors China. Okay, so this is a map, a
chart of Russia exports to China. And as
you can see, it's mainly just energy,
coal, LNG, crude oil. Okay, that's the
extent of Russia's exports to China. And
what does China export to Russia? Mainly
vehicles, electronics, and machinery.
Okay. So basically what China does is it
takes Russian resources, converts them
into manufacturing goods, machinery in
its factories and then exports it back
to Russia. This is a very bad deal for
Russia. It's a good deal for China, but
it's a bad deal for Russia. Okay, so
that's one point of tension. Another
point of tension is the dependence.
Okay. So basically
um China China and Russia may be best
friends but look at this. Okay. So
Russia's share in Chinese imports is
only 5%.
And then Russia's share in Chinese
exports is only 3%. So economically
Russia and China are not that close.
The problem though is that Russia is
highly dependent on its relationship
with China because all these economic
sanctions imposed on it by by the west.
Okay. So as you can see what's happened
um after February 2020 2022
uh when Putin invaded Ukraine and the
wester sections on Russia the
relationship
the economic dependence on China has
increased a lot where be where in the
beginning of the war
Russia didn't have that much in ruining
B but now the ruin B accounts for
over 40% % of Russian imports. Okay.
All right. Another thing is that
Chinese investors aren't that interested
in going to Russia and investing in
Russia. Okay. So, uh before the war,
this is the war. Okay. This is the war.
Um there was some okay but there weren't
that many and then as you can see after
the war it dropped precipitously
okay so why and as you can see from this
map okay maybe the Chinese are
in the Russian far east and that makes
sense because it's close to China but as
you can see the further you go out okay
here there's really no real investments.
Chinese aren't that interested in
investing in Russia. Okay. And why is
that? Well,
um there are different different reasons
we can speculate. Okay. The first
reason, and this this is really
important, is that the Chinese are
respecting Western sanctions on Russia.
If you do business with the Russians,
then the West can choose to debank you,
remove you from the global financial
system. And Chinese investors care more
about their relationship with the West
than they they they than they care about
with Russia. Okay, that's point one.
Point two is that Russia is not that
friendly to foreign investors. Uh Russia
is a very much a closed system. Um and
it's very hard to do business in Russia.
If you're United States and you put your
money in United States, you know, you'll
be you'll be protected legally and
contractually. If the person screws you
over, you can go sue the person in a
court of law and you can probably win
the case. Whereas in Russia, well, if
you get screwed over, too bad. Okay. Uh
Russia is still very much a mafia um
system. Then the third reason and this
is actually something that that is
really problematic is that um
Chinese are much more interested in USD
than they are in the ruble. Okay?
They're much more interested in
accumulating US dollars than they are in
ruble. And this is the central dilemma
of the US, sorry, of the Russia China
relationship where yes, you can
get Chinese to go visit Russia. You can
announce a lot of
um cooperation, but at the end of the
day, Chinese investors want USD and not
ruble. Okay, here's another um chart
where Yes. Okay. As you can see,
Chinese are going more and more Chinese
are going to Russia. Okay. All right.
So, right now you have about 50,000
Chinese studying in Russia. But this
does not compare at all to the Americans
where the when when when at when Chinese
have enough money to go study in America
starting in 2008, you can see a huge
boom. Okay? Right?
There's maybe six uh 60,000 Chinese who
are learning Russian in China while
everyone else is learning English. Okay?
So at the end of the day, Chinese people
are much more interested in the west
than they are in Russia. So in other
words
um you the relationship between Russia
and China seems to be top down
where it's mandated from the government
but the relationship between the United
States and China seems to be bottom up
where people
are choosing to work with the Americans
and so this is not really an equal
relationship.
So what I want what I want to look at
today is why is this a case? Why is it
that the Chinese want to go to America
and what can Putin do about it and what
will Putin do about it? Okay, so these
are the two questions that we're going
to look at. First of all, why is the
relationship like this? Second of all,
what is Putin's strategy of dealing with
this? Okay. All right. So to answer
this, we need to go back to World War
II. So this this is the end of World War
II and America has won the war. Okay. So
this is United States, USA.
This is Europe
and this is
uh East Asia. Okay. Japan basically,
but also Taiwan and Korea. Okay. All
right. So um
war World War II has ended and the
United States has a problem. It's got
all these factories that produce tanks,
machine guns, airplanes, and now the war
is over. So what are you going to do
with these factories? You can't just
tell everyone to go home and not work.
Okay? So they make a deal with the
Europeans and these Asians. Basically,
the deal is this. The Europeans will
agree
to buy
manufactured goods from the Americans,
television sets, radio, bicycles, cars.
But then the Europeans and the Japanese
are like, "We don't have any money." And
and the Americans are like, "Don't
worry, we'll lend you the money." Okay?
Not only will you will we give you the
goods, but we'll lend you the money to
buy the goods. Okay? And this is um and
of course the money is the US dollar. So
the US dollar is basically a contract,
right?
And because the Americans are lending US
dollars to the Europeans and the
Japanese and the East Asians, they want
the US dollars to be actually worth
something, right? So the US dollars is
pegged to gold, the gold standard,
meaning
the Americans can at any time
force the Japanese and Europeans
to
give their gold in exchange for the US
dollars. Okay, does that make sense?
And so this is a really good deal for
the Americans. And this is what we call
the bread and wood system. Okay, bread
and woods.
where the Americans would facilitate
global trade in order to maintain
demanufacturing power
and they would lend other nations the US
dollars to participate in this trade and
US dollars would be backed by gold.
Okay. So from 1950
to 1970,
this was a great deal for America. And
this led to probably the greatest wealth
creation in the world where if you were
just like a average white American male,
you had the best life possible. Okay,
this led to tremendous prosperity in
America.
But with prosperity comes corruption and
complacency.
Okay. So what happened was that the
Americans started to work hard. But then
the Europeans and the Japanese like we
need to work harder because we need to
rebuild ourselves and we need to pay off
this American debt. Okay? So Europe
start to work really hard. The Japanese
work really harder. And then what
happened was that the Europeans and the
Japanese start to make products that
were actually not only cheaper
than the Americans could make but also
better. Okay. So then what it started to
happen was that instead of America
lending money to the Europeans and the
Japanese to buy things from them, they
start to borrow money in order to
purchase the European and Japanese
manufactured goods. Okay. So now this
relationship goes backwards.
All right.
Now USA went from a credit nation to a
debtor nation.
But not only that, but the Americans
recognized that you know what, we can
print as much money as we want. So we
can spend as much money as we want. And
so the Americans start started to do
stupid things like start a war in
Vietnam that he could not win. Like send
a man to the moon for no particular
reason. like start like and the
Americans start to spend way too much
money and it's by 1970 the entire world
recognized that you know what America
owes us a lot of money but they probably
can't pay it off with gold. Okay. And
then 1971
Richard Nixon says you're absolutely
right. Okay. We can't pay you off with
gold. So we're going to move off the
gold standard.
Okay. Okay, so this creates a problem
now because everyone's sitting on this
US dollar and it's actually worth
nothing. So to solve this problem, what
Nixon did was he brought in
to the system
okay the GCC
Saudi Arabia basically uh as well as
China
to create more demand for the for the US
dollar. Okay. So this created the petro
dollar
because from now on Saudi Arabia would
only sell its oil in US dollars.
Okay? And so this kept the system going.
The thing to appreciate about this is
the Americans did this not because it
was strategic, not because it showed
long-term thinking, but because the
Americans by now have become addicted
to the US dollar. Do you understand this
idea? This is really important for you
guys to understand. At this point in
history,
the US dollar was the global reserve
currency.
The global reserve currency is unique in
human history. We've never had the idea
of a global reserve currency where one
currency could be the basis for value of
all other currencies. Okay? Never has
this happened before. What happened?
because of an accident of World War II
when Americans won and can impose their
system on everyone else. Okay? And
before it was tied to gold and they went
off the gold standard. So this is a
complete accident of history and it's
terrible for America for many reasons.
Okay? The first reason is that it's the
guaranter
of global trade.
What does that mean to be a guaranteer
of global trade? Well, first of all, it
means you have to print a lot of US
dollars, okay? Access liquidity,
okay? You have to print a lot of US
dollars so people can use US dollars and
this causes inflation in your system
and it's hard to manage. Okay? Second
problem is something called an open
capital account.
What does open capital account means? It
means like I can change the US dollar
anytime I want. So money can come into
the country but it can also flee the
country. Okay. And that's really
problematic if you're trying to control
a nation's currency.
All right. The third thing
is financialization
where because there's so much demand for
US dollars because US dollars is so
complex to manage your economy shifts
from manufacturing to financialization.
Financialization just means gambling.
Okay. So this has been terrible for
America, the American economy.
The problem is that once you have easy
money, it becomes addictive. Okay? And
so the way the way to protect the system
is by expansion
war.
You don't care if expanding your system
makes any sense. You don't care if
expanding your system is good for your
nation. All you want to do is expand it
in order to create more demand for US
dollar because you're so addicted to it.
Okay? And you have to go fight wars in
order to protect the US dollar. Right?
So this is what leads us to China. So to
create China, what what America did was
destroy its middle class and transfer
its manufacturing sector to China. It it
gave China technology
capital as well as market access. Okay.
And the entire intention was to create
more demand for the US dollar.
Okay. And this also explains the war in
Iran
where
Iran is not part of the system and so
America wants to destroy Iran in order
to make everyone else more dependent on
the system. Okay. All right.
Now, why did China agree to to
participate in the system?
Because the US dollar solve for for
China a a huge problem. Okay. Huge
problem is this. The US dollar I need
you guys to appreciate this. It
monetized
power.
Okay, so I'm the elite in China and I
control millions of people. But so what?
Who cares? What the dollar did was it en
enable me to monetize my power. Meaning
now that I could take this power and
store its value in the US dollar and
then export it to United States where it
would be safe. Does that make sense to
you guys? Okay, this is what it did. It
monetized power in China. Now the elite
could
use their power over the people and they
get rich in America.
Okay? So in other words,
there were two major beneficiaries
of this system
that was created even though this system
doesn't really make any sense. The first
of course is the American elite,
American financial elite. The second is
the Chinese political elite.
Okay? And this explains why it's so hard
for Putin and for Russia to form an
alliance with
China
because the elite the mentality is
to use their power and monetize it
through the US dollar. So what matters
is the US dollar, not the relationship
with Russia. Okay, does that make sense?
Any questions so far? Yeah.
Um, so I I think like it also aligns
with the like the international
education of Chinese which the rich
people and the elites that they send
their kids to America but not the
Russia.
>> Yeah, that that's exactly right. Okay,
so if you think about it, the entire
point of society in China right now is
to is to generate as much US dollars as
possible. Okay. So, sending a child to
United States in order to learn English,
in order to get the American degree, in
order to accommodatize to American
society is part of the strategy.
Hey, do you understand? Because women be
by itself has no value. If you convert B
into US dollars, that has value.
Okay? Does that make sense? Okay. So,
that so that that's what explains the
relationship between the United States
and China and why it's so hard for
Russia to break into this relationship.
There's there's actually nothing the
Russian can offer the Chinese elite. All
right. Okay.
Uh in fact, the Chinese elite think
Russia is a problem because because of
its uh because of its militarism
throughout the world. All right. So
Putin's so Putin if he wants to
establish a new world order what he
needs to do is ultly destroy
the US dollar as the global reserve
currency.
Okay, that is his mission. That is his
game. If he really wants to destroy the
American empire, he needs to destroy the
value of the US dollar. Okay? And the
way the way he does that is by
destroying demand for the US dollar.
Okay, does that make sense? All right,
so we're gonna go over
Putin's game, his grand plan to destroy
the US dollar.
Okay, actually before I do that, one
thing that I need to make clear to you
guys is that
not all Americans think this is a good
thing that the United States has a world
reserve currency. In fact, most
Americans, if you explain the system to
them, they'll be like, "Yeah, we don't
want to be the world reserve currency
because one, it causes corruption. It it
causes all these corrupt people to come
to our country. It causes all these
illegal immigrants to come to our
country. It causes us to go fight wars
in Iran.
It causes us to support Israel. So yeah,
we don't want to be the world reserve
currency. The problem though is that
they're addicted to it because it's such
easy money. Okay, so this is a
contradiction. On one hand, the
Americans know that the world reserve
currency is bad for them, but on the
other hand, they're addicted to it.
Okay, so America's basically a drug
addict. And so what do you do? Well, the
only thing you can do is something
called a force
withdrawal. Okay.
a force withdrawal,
which means that you just deny America's
capacity to print money. Okay? And the
way you do that is by destroying global
demand for the dollar.
Does that make sense? This will cause a
lot of pain in America in the short
term, basically economic depression,
civil war. the long term, this may be
the only solution to save America. Okay.
All right. So, let's go over Putin's
grand strategy for
um
um destroying the US dollar. I will also
point out that of all the world leaders
in the world, I would say only Vladimir
Putin seems to be strategic. Okay. The
guy actually is able to think long term
and execute with perfect timing. He's
he's he's a chess player. Okay. And he's
really the only world leader that's able
to think so far ahead and plan so
strategically. So, um let's go over his
strategy. Basically, strategy is very
simple. There are lots of different
nations that have been sanctioned by the
Americans. How can I form a relationship
with these nation states in order to
create volatility in the world to
destabilize global trade and therefore
destabilize the US dollar? Okay. Also,
there are some nation states that
participate in the system but who are
not happy about the system. So, how can
I actually break them away from
um dependence on America? All right. So
these are nations that have been
sanctioned by the Americans including
Russia,
uh Iran, okay, uh North Korea,
Venezuela, Syria, Barus, Mimer, okay? So
my a civil war, forget about them.
Venezuela has been conquered by the
Americans. Syria is destroyed. Okay, so
basically there are four countries left.
Russia, Belarus, Iran, North Korea. So
these four are going to work together in
order to destabilize
the global order in order to destroy the
American empire. Okay. All right. So the
key is Iran and North Korea. Okay. We've
already talked a lot about Iran. So so
today I want to talk more about North
Korea. So um
right now
Russia and North Korea have become very
very close. So last year, oh sorry,
sorry, this is actually two years ago.
June uh 2024, Putin visited North Korea
and signed a mutual defense pact with
North North Korea. This is a very very
big deal because what a mutual defense
pact means is that in the case that
North Korea is attacked, Russia must
militarily come to the defense of North
Korea. If Russia is attacked, North
Korea must come to the fence of Russia.
Okay, this is a big deal because
previously
North Korea had a mutual defense pact
with China signed in 1961
after the Korean War.
And so you would think that North Korea
doesn't really need Russia because North
Korea already has China to protect it.
So why is Vladimir Putin signing a
mutual defense pact with um Kim Jong-un?
This is very strange. Okay. Well, I
think if we wait a couple years, we'll
know the answer.
All right. Another thing to keep in mind
is that um Kim Jong-un has been very
supportive of Russia's war in Ukraine.
In fact, he sent 10,000 troops
to uh Ukraine. And the thing about the
North Koreans is that at first they're
not very well trained. They're not very
disciplined.
But the thing about the North Koreans is
they fight to the end. Okay? They have a
policy of not surrendering to the enemy.
If you do surren surrender to the enemy,
guess what happens to your family back
in North Korea? Okay? So the thing about
the North Koreans, remember, is that
yes, they're poor. They're not techn
technologically suff sophisticated, but
their soldiers are willing to fight to
the bitter end. And that's actually the
key to winning a war. All right. So, um,
everyone makes fun of North Korea, okay?
Because it's a very poor place. So, if
you look, if you compare North Korea to
South Korea, um,
the GDP per person is only $771. Okay,
that's it. That's it.
Whereas in North Korea, it's over
33,000.
It's one of the highest in the world.
Look at this map, okay, of a satellite
image of the Korean Peninsula at night.
This is South Korea,
okay? This is North Korea. Pretty big
difference, guys. Huge difference,
right?
But in a war,
this place would defeat this place.
Okay? Why? Because in this class, what
you're taught is game theory.
And if you look at how wars are fought
and who wins wars,
societies that win wars have three
characteristics, okay? They have energy,
they're open, and they have cohesion.
Now, what's important for us to
understand is that the poorer you are,
the more likely you are to be energetic,
open, and cohesive.
Okay? And you're like, "That's
South Korea is wealthy. It has
technology.
It has a lot of weaponry. It has
American support." The problem with um
western capitalistic societies is that
they tend to be very individualistic
as well as complacent
and unequal. Okay? And you can tell
because of the birth rate, right? Where
in North Korea the fertility rate is
still 1.81. It's not great, but look at
South Korea. 0.81.
Okay. So in 50 years time, South Korea
will
lose 80% of its people. North Korea will
also lose people. But just if there's no
war, if we just keep on going,
eventually South Korea will go to zero
and North Korea will still be around.
Okay? But the other difference is that
when you're poor, you're not afraid to
die,
right? You have nothing to lose. Whereas
if you're rich, well, you're you want to
live. Okay? So all North Korea has to do
is basically say, you know what, we have
artillery
and this is Soul. Okay? You can see how
close Soul is to the border. So all
North Korea has to do is tell the
Koreans, you either pay us a lot of
money or we'll go attack you,
right? It's that simple. And and the
South Koreans will be like, we'll give
you money. Just please don't attack us.
And what what this is going to do is
create a lot of tension in Southeast
Asia. It's it's going to have to bring
in Japan as well as well as the United
States.
Okay. So now Putin's defense pact with
North Korea makes a lot of sense
because if North Korea just creates a
problem in the Korean Peninsula,
this is going to be a huge problem for
Japan and United States. And remember,
United States is already distracted in
Iran. It doesn't have the forces in
order to defend South Korea.
Okay, this this is going to create a lot
instability.
All right, let's move on.
Germany, guys. Okay, so
um after Russia invaded Ukraine,
Europe and United States responded by
imposing sanctions on Russia.
The problem is that Germany was
dependent on cheap Russian energy to
fuel its economy.
And because you lost this Russian
energy, you had no choice now but to buy
American LG at 50% more uh 50% markup.
Okay, you can tell from this chart the
impact on Europe's economy where okay
um in 2019 they weren't buying that much
from the Americans but by 2025 they're
buying a lot from the Americans and
again this is 50% more than Russian LNG.
This has been terrible for especially
the German economy. Okay. So, um this is
the red. The dark red is are the
Germans. Okay. And as you can see, the
decline has been pretty steep, far more
steep steeper than the um French, the
Italians, the Spanish, and the British.
So, the Germans are really hurting from
this war.
Okay. All right.
The other thing is that there's been a
lot of immigration
to
um Europe. Okay. So in certain places of
Europe especially uh Scandinavia
the population of immigrants has gone as
high as 20%. Okay. In Sweden uh Germany
is also a under a lot of stress. So
there are two there's two these two
trends. Okay. more immigrants coming to
Europe which is threatening the local
identity as well as this war in Ukraine.
So these so AFD
okay AFD
uh which opposes immigration and which
opposes this war in Ukraine they've seen
a surge in popularity. Okay. And
honestly, if there were fair elections
in Germany,
at one point the AFD is going to win.
Okay, so what this means is that the
Germans are choosing instead to
fight a war. Okay. So, in 2016, you can
see the German military expenditure
wasn't that great, but now they're going
to invest a lot more in the military.
Why? Because the plan is by 20 2029 for
the Germans to have troops in Ukraine.
Europe is moving towards total war.
Okay? Stretching the entire society
for war against Russia.
Russia. Evan says that Russia is now
under a lot of e economic pressure.
Okay. And it's true that the Russians
have in fact spend a great deal more
money on the military. Okay. So you can
see how after the war started you have
this huge bump
um in military spending in the Russian
Federation. But the thing to keep in
mind is that it's still pretty low as
part of its GDP. Okay. So the green is
Saudi Arabia. Uh so this Saudi Arabia
spends over 10% of its GDP on the
military. The Chinese spend about 2 to
3%. Okay? The United States spends 5 to
4%.
The Russians spend about the same. Okay?
So in other words, the Russians still
have a long way to go. In fact, Putin
still maintains that the war in Ukraine
is a special military operation. It's
not a fullscale war. If the moment that
Putin declares war, the entire economy
shifts to total war. We we can expect a
to a complete surge in
um spending on the military. Okay.
Russia hasn't reached Russia hasn't
reached that point yet.
Now,
um, what is Russia's plan for Europe?
Eur Russ Putin doesn't actually want to
fight Europe. Um, because it would be
disastrous for both Russia and for
Europe, but he understands that there's
a civil war brewing in Europe where
these right-wing parties like the AFD,
they're surging in in um popularity
because they oppose war and because they
oppose immigrants. So all Putin has to
do is force Germany into a war and drag
this war out, create a war of attrition.
Why? Because as this war drags on, it's
going to create a lot of political
tension back at home, especially if
you're drafting young men to fight this
war. Okay? And if that were to happen,
eventually uh right-wing political
parties, FD would come into power. And
how does Putin know this? Because this
has this has historically been true.
This this is what happened in Russia
during World War I when the
came into power. It almost happened in
Germany. Okay. When communist almost
came to power in Germany. All right. So
war creates political tensions and the
the longer the war drags on uh the more
the greater the tension is. Okay. So
basically what Putin wants to do is
create a civil war in Europe, allow
these right-wing pro-Russia parties to
come into power and then form an
alliance between Europe, Germany and
Russia. Okay.
So um part one of the plan is to create
as much political tension in Southeast
Asia as possible by using North Korea.
Part two of this plan is go to war with
Europe in order to destabilize Europe
politically and allow these right-wing
parties to come to power and then form
an alliance with them. Okay.
All right.
Now, let's go on
to the global south. Okay. So the thing
about the global south is that Russia
has been very supportive of the global
south especially countries in Africa.
Okay. Um
after war started when Russia invaded
Ukraine support
um
for Putin in the global south increased
dramatically
as this map tells you. Okay. Now the
question is wait a minute here Russia
invaded Ukraine. So why would people
around the world support Russia?
And the answer is because of narrative.
Okay, from a western perspective,
Ukraine is this innocent country and
Russia is the aggressor. So clearly
Russia isn't wrong.
But if you are not part of the west, if
you're part of the south, what you will
appreciate is that the west is this
imperial bully and Russia is standing up
for itself. Okay? NATO NATO was
expanding too far. uh Ukraine was being
co-opted by the west and so Russia was
trying to defend itself and thank God
that Putin and Russia and Russia now can
set up against the Americans. Okay?
Because we in the south have been
bullied by the Americans all this time.
So the support for the Russians are
particularly high in Africa which has
been subject to western imperialism for
the past 20 years. Okay. So this is a
level of cooperation
uh between Russia and African countries.
As you can see there is a lot of trade
going on but at the same time there's
also military cooperation. There's
nuclear power plant construction.
There's also oil exploration and nickel
uh nickel production. Also there are a
lot of Russian mercenaries Russian
mercenaries in Africa. Okay. and they're
usually fighting against USbacked groups
uh in order to control the continent.
Um, China is also heavily active in
Africa. The thing about China is that
it's very much focused on economic
development as opposed to military
intervention. The Russians use a full
spectrum strategy in Africa. So, they're
trying to win hearts and minds. We know
that because the Russians spend a lot of
effort on propaganda. Okay? So the the
Russian flag is where they they have
propaganda efforts and you can as you
can see China is not that heavily
invested in propaganda in Africa.
All right.
So what Putin is also trying to do is
create a narrative that Russia is
liberating the world from Western
imperialism. And this has particular uh
strength in place like Africa which has
been vict which has been a victim of uh
western imperialism for a long long
time. Okay. All right.
India. Okay.
So India for the longest time has been
neutral. So what's been happening is
that India and Russia have becoming very
very close. The impetus for their close
relationship is after the war in
Ukraine, Russian oil became sanctioned.
So the way to evade sanctions was for
Russia to sell its oil to India which
would then sell its oil around the
world. Okay. So what what we'll see is a
very strong relationship between Russia
and India develop over next few years.
What Russia wants from India are
laborers.
Why? Because
um because of this war, Russia is now
short of manpower. So it needs people to
to run its factories eventually. It's
going to win this war in Ukraine. It's
going to need people to go build rebuild
uh Ukraine. Okay. So what we can expect
that Russia and India will become very
very close these past these next 10 to
20 years primarily because Russia wants
to invest in relationship between uh
Russia and India.
Um,
Iran is the key to Russia creating a new
world order. Why? Because first of all,
as you can see, Iran is really the
center of global trade. So if um Russia
wants to access Africa, it wants to
access India, it wants to access Central
Asia, Iran is very important
strategically. Okay. It's also very easy
for uh Russia to trade with
Iran because of the Caspian Sea. Okay.
All right. So, basically um
Russia understands that Iran is the key
to
uh global trade, Russia's global trade
with the world. And that's why the
Americans are actually attacking Iran.
Because by attacking Iran,
uh, the Americans
can
block
Russia from global trade or at least
destabilize it. Okay, that's why one of
the major battlefronts this this
actually probably one of the two major
battlefronts in World War II. The first
is obviously Ukraine which will be
fought between Europe and Russia. second
major battlefront will be uh in Iran
fought between
uh Iran and the United States. This is
also why by the way Israel is so
important. Okay, Israel. Why is Israel
so important?
Because Israel is the fortress. Okay,
the American fortress in this area.
It's very
possible that if put in place these
cards right all these regions will fall
into the Russian sphere of influence. So
America's guar guarantee against Russian
influence is Israel and that's why the
Americans support Israel so much because
issue is key to check it to keeping
Russia in check. Okay, does that make
sense guys? All right. Um
the the last thing I'll talk about is
Japan. Okay. So the grand strategy of
the Americans is to use Japan to balance
China.
The Japanese don't like this idea. Okay?
Because for the longest time the
Japanese have become were a vassel to
the Americans and the Japanese made a
lot of sacrifice made a lot of
sacrifices to be the vassal state to
America. Okay. But now you've created a
situation where Japan has no choice but
to remmilitarize and rethink its
national priorities. The war in Iran is
forcing
Japan to rethink the global map. Okay.
So this is so Japan is heavily dependent
on energy energy imports and for most of
its history most of its recent history
it was getting its energy from the
Middle East. Okay. But obviously most of
this energy is now gone. So now you have
two options. You can either depend on
Russia or the United States. Now you
would think, well, I'll just Japan will
just buy all oil from the United States.
The United States certainly thinks so.
But the last time this happened was
before World War II. Okay. Japan before
World War II was getting 90% of its oil
from the United States. But Japan was
becoming too powerful. And so the United
States start to embargo Japan. Then
Japan had no choice but then to go
invade Southeast Asia for its oil and
attack the United States. Okay, does
that make sense? So Japan does not want
to put put in a situation where it's
completely dependent on Americans for
oil because the last time this happened,
it didn't really work out well for
Japan. Okay, so Japan has no choice in
this matter but to yes buy American LG,
but also to try to smooth things over
with Russia to start buying more oil
from Russia.
Okay. The other problem for the Japanese
is that for the longest time they've
been buying US treasuries. Okay. So, you
can see how China
um yes, China's addicted to US dollar,
but they recognize that the Americans
aren't that dependable.
Um they're printing too much money.
They're too much in debt. So, the
Chinese have been selling US dollars, US
treasuries. But the Japanese have been
increasing
um
buying US treasuries. Why is that? Why
is it that US treasuries aren't worth as
much money as before, but the Japanese
continue to buy US treasuries? And the
answer is because it's almost like a
subsidy
or a bribe to the Americans. Okay?
Right? Because the Americans have a lot
of soldiers in Japan. So Japan is a
colony and so what you do is you bribe
your the Americans to protect you but
also to just leave you alone. Okay? And
the way they do do this is something
called the yang carry trade.
Okay? And this is the silliest thing
ever. Okay? But but let let me explain
to you let let me explain to you what
this is. Okay. So, what the yen carry
trade is this.
Japanese banks
will lend
money to Japanese corporations at 0%.
Okay? Basically, three money. So, if
you're a big Japanese corporation and
you want union money, you just go to the
Japanese bank and they'll give you money
at 0% interest. What this means is you
can take this money and then go buy US
treasuries. Okay, your treasuries
at 5%.
Does that make sense? All right. And so
that that's what's led to the surge of
Japanese buying of US treasuries because
it's free money. It's literally free
money.
But the problem is that as you can
imagine, this is causing huge problems
for the Japanese economy. Okay? Okay.
And as as the political geopolitical
situation gets worse and worse, Japan
has no choice but to repatriate
its money back from the United States.
Basically selling US treasuries.
Okay. So what America needs to do is
basically force these countries like
Japan, China to continually buy US
treasuries. And that's why we have this
war in Iran.
Okay. to really control the world's
energy supply
and time is running out for America.
Okay. The reason why is that as more and
more people sell US dollars, as more as
more and more people refuse to buy US
treasuries,
certain problems arise. Okay. First is
the um debt interest.
So right now the debt is at $39
trillion.
Let's assume the interest is 5%. That
means
that the Americans have to pay two $2
trillion in interest payment alone. Does
that make sense? Okay, that's a huge
problem. Second problem is that as
people
refuse to buy US treasuries, you need to
give them a higher interest rate. Okay?
So right now 5% it has moved up to 6%.
This is this is a disaster for America.
Okay?
So
America needs to basically act now.
Okay, it needs to move
down the treasury rate. Okay, the way
you move down the treasury rate is by
forcing people to buy US treasuries from
you. Okay, so this is a war that's going
on between Russian and America, between
Putin and Trump, where Putin is trying
to get people to not buy US treasuries
and Trump is trying to force people to
buy US treasuries. Okay? And this is a
war that's being fought right now. Okay?
Any questions about what's going on?
Okay.
How will America become or how will
America end if like the world and
America is so addicted to US dollars?
>> Wait, wait. Could you ask that question
again?
>> Uh, how will America end or or like how
will America be if the world and America
are still addicted to US dollars?
because it is an addiction. Okay. It's
free and easy money.
>> Yeah. But but like what will America
become like if this trend continues?
>> If this trend continues
with this addiction.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. All right. So
right now if these trends continue okay
there's certain problems that arise okay
the first thing is that
America will print more money
okay so the debt $3900
will continue
to increase
and then the world's going to think you
can't actually pay this off, right? So
then what happens is that people stop
buying US treasuries,
then the interest rate goes up in order
to get people to buy more US treasuries
because if you don't do that, if people
don't buy US treasuries, you go into
default.
Okay, so what does default mean? Okay.
Well,
um, let let me explain how the system
works. Okay. First, so first of all,
it's a Federal Reserve that lends money
to the US government.
Okay? So, there there are different
buyers of US treasuries, but the Federal
Reserve is the biggest buyer. All right?
So let's just say you owe a China has a
trillion dollars
in US treasuries and United States says
to China, you know what? We're not going
to pay you back. Screw you guys. Okay,
does it matter? No, it doesn't matter.
Who cares? Okay, the Federal Reserve is
a different problem. Why? Because let's
just say you owe the Federal Reserve $10
trillion.
Okay, where where does this money come
from? It comes from private banks.
Okay. And who puts their money in the
banks? The people put their money in the
banks. All right. So in other words, the
American government has borrowed its
money from the American people. So if
the American government were to default
on its debt, the American people would
lose all the money in the bank. And what
would you and what would that happen?
And so what would happen after that? a
revolution would happen. Okay?
In other words, it is impossible for the
US government to default
on this debt. It would create a
revolution in America. The government
would collapse. Does that make sense?
Okay. So, now you're just forced to
um
get China to buy two $2 trillion. Do you
understand? Because you can't force the
because you because you cannot default
the debt domestically because everyone
in America will lose all their money.
Okay? So the only thing you can do is go
overseas and force people to buy US
dollars from you. And you do that
through war,
right? Does that make sense?
Okay. So Putin understands that all he
has to do is stop foreign countries from
buying US dollars and America will
collapse it in itself because because
the economics doesn't make any more
sense. Okay. It's impossible for you to
pay all that that interest pay payment.
Okay. So that that's a stark crisis that
America's facing right now. Okay. Any
more questions? Yeah, Alan.
So I'm curious about like even if Russia
really this collapses systems of current
global economies like what will be the
new position position of Russia's like
what what is the precious commodity of
Russia that can maybe give give it the
power to maybe lead the world.
>> Okay.
So, we're assuming that anyone someone
wants to be the new leader. And the
reality is that it's actually stupid to
be the world reserve currency. It's
silly to be the world leader because now
you're just forced to spend all your
resources on defending your position in
the world. Okay?
>> It's like being a high school bully.
Well, being a high school bully sounds
cool, but now you have to go fight
everyone in the school. Okay? So, no one
actually wants to be the world leader.
And America doesn't even want to be the
world leader. It's just stuck being the
world leader because of these historical
accidents. It doesn't make sense.
>> So all basically all Russia is trying to
do is it's trying to get rid of the
school bully. Once you get rid of the
school bully, there's no more bullies.
Okay? Which which means I I can do
whatever I want now. More freedom for
Russia. Now that doesn't mean that
Russia will be peaceful. Russia is going
to go is going to exert its power where
it can, but it will have more freedom of
of movement. Okay? It sees America as
its greatest threat.
And so
Russia wants to get rid of America.
China's different. China appreciates
that historically
its neighbors have been very aggressive.
Okay. Who who are who are who are
China's neighbors? The Japanese, right?
The Russians, the Vietnamese. They're
very aggressive people. So if I'm China,
I would prefer America to be the global
policeman, to be the high school bully,
right? Because honestly, if America's
not the high school bully, someone else
is going to be the bully. And I much
rather deal with America than with
Russia. Okay? So, so that's why the
relationship between Russia and China is
much more tenuous, much more unstable
than people believe it is. It is in the
mutual benefit of the two to get along
right now, but in the long term there's
eventually going to be a divorce because
their interests don't actually converge
to together. Okay. So, um Putin's plan
is just be is to remain good friends
with China. He knows that China in the
long term is going to side more of
America than with Russia. But in the
short term, Putin can do as much as he
can to make China his friend. Okay? So
he needs China to be neutral. The worst
thing that can happen is that China sees
Russia as a threat and China, United
States got together to defend the
system. Okay.
Doesn't doesn't make sense.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Uh a further question is like does
the collapse of economic systems well
affect the global police uh positions of
America because I think we previously
said that this global economy system
basically build on the Americans uh
military powers but even though this
systems collapse financially it doesn't
means that the military power of
American decrease then I why then the
like the Russia will get its like
freedoms to move Then,
>> okay, look, the reality is that your
military comes from your nation state.
Okay, your military
comes from your nation state. Why?
Because it's your nation state that
provides the weapons, the manufacturer
of the weapons, the people, the sold to
become the soldiers, the financing.
Okay? So, let's just say this nation
state is in a revolution where the
people are fighting a war against the
government. The military has no choice
but to retreat and try to crush this
revolution.
Okay, does that make sense? So, America
doesn't have
the
interest in defending the world if it
entire nation is falling apart. That's
just silly. It has to retreat. Okay.
Okay. And it's possible that America is
so stupid that it military um stays
overseas. But if that would happen, then
the military would need would still need
a nation state. Okay. And so he needs
now to move from America to different
nation states. And I imagine that if
that that were the case, the milit
military would split off and and form
help um support three other nation
states which are Japan,
Germany, and Israel.
In other words, different theaters of
American military would find a different
nation state as their host. Okay? So the
American forces in East Asia would go
and support Japan. In Europe, they go
support Germany. In the Middle East,
they go support Israel.
All right.
But they need a nation state as their
host.
Okay? Clear? All right. So, next week is
the final examination. So, if you're on
YouTube, you're watching YouTube, please
post your questions in the comment
section and my wife, my beautiful wife
will select um the very best. Okay? All
right. See you guys next week.