So Trump is in China. This happened
about um 30 minutes ago,
an hour south of US. So Trump came in
last night and this morning he met with
President C at the Great Hall of the
People. And let's just have a quick
look.
This is him getting out of his
limousine. This was brought in from the
United States by a military transport.
He brought uh his entire cabinet
including uh Marco Rubio, the secretary
of state
as well as Peter Hexev who is the
secretary of war.
Okay.
The last time an American president
visited was nine years ago, November
2017.
So this is a very historical meeting.
And as you may remember,
after Trump visited Beijing,
um
they start the trade war and we've been
in a trade war ever since. I think that
this meeting is very optimistic for US
China relations. A lot has to do with
who came with Trump. So um this is from
way boore the Chinese Twitter and what
Chinese are focusing on is who came with
Trump. So many of his family members
came with Trump including his son Eric
uh his daughter-in-law Lara.
um and they were excited about coming to
China. Team China guys. Okay. Much more
important is the number of business
executives who came with Trump. So you
have Ellen Musk of Tesla and of course
he does a lot of business in China. Tim
Cook of Apple also does a lot of
business in China. Boeing is trying to
secure a $50 billion
um sale to Chinese airlines. And so
these are are three um very important
business people. And then you have some
of the leading financial people in
America including Larry Frink of Black
Rockck, uh Steven Schwarzman of
Blackstone, uh Der Solomon of Goldman
Sachs, you have Cityroup, you have
Mastercard and Visa. Okay. And these are
the leading financial companies
in America.
And altogether these business executives
if you put all their net the company's
net worth together their companies are
worth over $12 trillion. That's a lot of
money
and these are very busy people and quite
honestly I've worked in business
negotiations.
You do not bring
these people together in one room unless
you have a mega deal to announce to the
world. Okay. So my prediction is that um
by tomorrow we should have the broad
contours of a USChina grand bargain
where the two nations reconcile their
differences and they start a new chapter
uh in world history where they work
together to stabilize the global
economy. So, what I want to do today is
discuss how we got here,
why a grand bargain will happen, and
what this grand bargain will look like.
Okay. All right.
So, let's discuss some of the events
that led to this uh meeting between C
and Trump. This is David Lee from
Twitter, okay? And he's he's talking
about like the past month what happened.
So, the first thing that happened is
that China blocked Manis. Manis is an AI
company uh that Mark Zuckerberg tried to
buy and Manis was incubated in China and
if you're an AI company
you get become very successful you want
to go United States because that's where
all the money is that's where all the
talent is that's how you become really
really big but because it was it was um
incubated in China said no you can't go
to United States because this will set a
bad president China is trying to grow
its own talent. So this shows um the AI
war being fought between China and the
United States. Okay, so that's one thing
that happened. Another thing that
happened is that the US imposed
sanctions on Chinese companies that do
business with Iran, including satellite
companies that sell commercial
intelligence to Iran on where US bases
are. um teapot refineries which take uh
Iranian oil and then convert it into
energy that China can use. Okay. And in
response, China said no, you cannot
impose sanctions on us. If you impose
sanctions on us and if people comply
with these sanctions, then we the
Chinese government will sanction these
people as well. Okay, this this there
this there this something called the
blocking
order.
And
this also seems like an escalation in
the US China trade war where previously
Chinese institutions, banks, individuals
complied with US sanctions. And this is
the first time the Chinese government
said to Chinese people, if you're a
Chinese citizen and you comply with US
sanctions, then we will sanction you.
Okay, so this is a very big deal.
um Nvidia
was not able to sell chips into China
and this is going to affect Nvidia's
bottom line. Okay, Nvidia is right now
the world's the world's most valuable
company primarily because AI depends on
their chips. Okay. Um, China invited
Iranian Foreign Minister Arachi to
Beijing because China is very interested
in the outcome of this war between
United States and Iran. Uh, right now
um, Iran is blocking the show of Humus
and China depends on 50 to 60% of its
energy needs from the Middle East. Okay.
Um, Jun Hang was not on the China list.
Okay. So before Trump took off, it was
announced that Judge Huang, who is the
head of Nvidia, would not come to China.
And this is a very big deal because in
this grand bargain, what China would
want is access to Nvidia SE uh chips,
semiconductors in order to fuel its AI.
Okay. Um the United States and six other
nations had a war game in the
Philippines and China sent 28 warships.
Okay. Uh Trump sent Iran anou
Iran make modifications and Trump said
no. Okay. So it seems like the war will
only increase in the Middle East. After
Iran had responded, China announced
Trump's state of visit. Um and then
uh
yesterday and the day before Hulong who
is the uh who was a vice premier in
China and Scott Bezen who's a church
treasury secretary met in South Korea to
try to negotiate
um a a deal. Okay. And then what's going
to happen is that Putin will visit China
after Trump leaves. So you just look at
what's happening. It seems as though
there's still a lot of friction between
the United States and China. What I want
to show you today is that all of this
you can just ignore. Okay? This is all
that's happening right now. But if we
use game theory, if we just look at the
broad contours of what's happening, we
would make much better predictions as to
what will happen. Okay? So all this I
think is just theater.
All right. The China and United States
are not actually fighting AI war. It's
all theater. They're actually working
together to promote AI. Um these
sanctions are happening but eventually
the US and China will come to a grand
bargain and they will become much more
economic integrated.
And Iran, China doesn't really care
about Iran. Okay? China care first and
foremost about
um the relationship with the United
States. And one piece of evidence for
that is that when foreign minister
Arachi went to Moscow, Putin met with
him for for 90 minutes and Putin
expressed his sympathy and support to
the Iranian people. When Aranchi came to
Beijing, he only met with his
counterpart, the U foreign minister
Wong. Okay. All right. Uh, another
important thing is that Scott Bezant is
the one who is leading the US team in
China. Scott Bezant is the Treasury
Secretary.
This goes against protocol because uh,
it's usually
the secretary of state, Marco Rubio, and
the national security adviser, who also
happens to be Marco Rubio.
This team is the one that sets the
agenda for the US China visit. Because
it's Scott Bessant, we can probably
guess that this is probably going to be
an economic negotiation and the focus is
on will be on finance. Basically, what
America wants is for China to open up
its financial sector for companies like
Black Rockck and Black Star to come in
to sell financial instruments to Chinese
people. Okay, that that's what America
wants and we'll talk about more about
this as as we go along.
All right, let's continue. Okay, so in
the geopolitical landscape,
um it seems as though America is trying
to contain China. So, uh this is Tran
and this is what China is trying to do.
China is trying to build a high-spe
speed rail network from Beijing all the
way across central Asia and into Europe.
Okay, this is a land route that Beijing
wants to take in order to maintain trade
with Europe. As you can tell from this
map, Tran is the pivot or the hub of
this trade network. Okay, without Tran,
Beijing could not access Europe.
Um it and then Moscow also sees Tran as
very important as well for its north
south trade axis. Without Tran, Beijing
is completely reliant on Russia. Beijing
does not want to become reliant on
Russia. Beijing sees itself as the third
axis of power in the world. All right?
You have the United States, you have
Russia, and then you have China. From a
geopolitical perspective,
China doesn't want to become partners
with either United States or or or
Russia. It it wants to become
independent. It wants to create its own
sphere of influence. Okay? And that's
why Iran is very very important. So a
lot of geopolitical
analysts believe that Beijing is forced
to support Iran in this war. And what I
want to show you is that's not actually
the case. All right. China's China's may
want to become independent of the United
States and Russia, but it cannot
actually.
All right. Um, now there's a rumor
a couple of days ago that one deal that
Trump and C will will sign in Beijing is
Sidin Ping will commit $1 trillion
$1 trillion investment into America
primarily factories that manufacture EV
cars. This is a huge deal. Okay. And
Laura Laura uh Ingraham who works at Fox
News, she thinks it's a bad thing. She
thinks that this is about uh China
coming in and trying to buy out the uh
United States. As I'll show you later,
this is Okay, I think this
deal will happen, but this is a deal
that shows that China is is ultimately
dependent on America as opposed to China
wants to take over America. Okay.
All right. So, um, how can we understand
the Trump visit? Well, again, in this
class, what I want to show you is that
historical analogies is a really
powerful way to understand the present.
So the Trump visit today is analogous
to Nixon's visit in 1972.
Okay. So you you you don't know this but
before 1972
America was hostile towards
China primarily because of Taiwan where
during the Chinese civil war the
Americans were very supportive of uh
Changhai shed and the KMT they lost they
went to Taiwan and when that happened
America said that first of all we will
only recognize Taiwan as the official
government of China. Second of all, we
will refuse to do any business with the
PRC.
And third of all, we will help Taiwan
eventually try to take over uh uh China.
1972 when Nixon visited this marked a
radical departure
from 20 years
of
um American foreign policy. Okay. And
the question then is why would he do
that? And the answer is in 1971
the Nixon shock. So if you talk to
historians, they'll give you lots and
lots of different reasons as to why
Nixon visited uh China. The main reason
in their perspective
is that
um Harry Kissinger who was national
security advisor to Richard Nixon, he
was trying to triangulate
uh between China and the Soviet Union,
right? he was trying to get China on the
side of the United States in order to um
defeat the Soviet Union. That's not
true. That's something that historians
made up. The real reason is that in 1971
Nixon removed the US dollar from the
gold standard.
And now the US dollar is worth nothing.
Before you could take the dollar and
change it for gold, now it's worth
nothing. If it's worth nothing, what to
do now is create a demand for it. you
basically have to create a Ponzi scheme.
And so Nixon did two things to resolve
this issue and create the US dollar
Ponzi scheme. The first thing he did was
create something called the petro
dollar.
Okay. The petro dollar is where Saudi
Arabia and other Middle East countries
like Qatar,
UAE, they only sell their oil in US
dollars. So now before the value of US
dollars was pe was tied to gold, the
gold standard. Now the value of US
dollars is tied to oil. Okay? If you
want to buy oil and everyone wants to
buy oil, you need US dollars and there's
something called a petro dollar. Okay,
that's the first thing. Second thing
which is relevant to us is
China. Okay, opening
the strategy is to turn China into a
manufacturing base for the global
economy.
Right? So the Middle East sells oil to
the world but China now will sell
manufactured goods to the world and
China will also do so using US dollars
and these two things together create um
the current global economy.
All right. Okay. So, what I'm going to
do now is I'm going to explain to you
um why America did this. Okay. Um this
is something called the Shanghai
Communic.
This is published in 1972
and this basically spells out the basic
premise framework for all future US
China cooperation and dialogue and the
sh framework basically resolves the
Taiwan question
and with regard to Taiwan question
America practice something called
strategic ambiguity.
meaning
the United States will not be clear
about the issue of Taiwan with regard to
China. So what the United States has
been saying for a long time is we do not
support Taiwan independence. Okay,
that's a strategic ambiguity. China
would prefer the United States to say we
oppose
Taiwan independence in which case United
States is obligated now to prevent
Taiwan from becoming independent. Okay,
that's what China would prefer but
United States practices strategic
ambiguity saying we do not support. I
would not be surprised if over the next
few months
Trump radically changes
this attitude and declares that the
United States is opposed to Taiwan
independence. In fact, United States
supports the unification
of China and Taiwan. Okay, this would be
a radical sea shift from previous
administrations. And I'll explain why
later on why Trump would do this and
also why it's actually very strategic
and smart for the United States to want
to support Taiwan and China reinvig.
Okay. All right. So um let me explain
now
what the China US relationship really is
using the theories that we've learned in
this class. Okay. There's something that
you will never learn that that you will
not learn anywhere else and this is
speculation on my part. Please take it
with a grain of salt. Please question
me. Please debate me. Okay. But this is
my theory of how the US and China work
together. And once you understand this
theory, you can then go on to make
certain predictions about how United
States and China will behave moving
forward. And based on whether these
predictions are correct or not, you can
then figure out if this theory is
correct or not. Okay. All right. So the
first thing to understand and something
I've been teaching a lot in this class
is that reality
is a hallucination.
It is something that we collectively
imagine together. And again, the
analogy, the metaphor I use is Plato's
allegory cave where you imagine about a
million people
chain together and they're all looking
at a wall. Okay, this wall is empty.
Behind the wall, behind the people is
this great fire where the elite, okay,
we don't know who they are, okay? But
they project shadows
onto the wall.
And then the people who are chained
don't know what's going on behind the
scenes. They only see what's in front of
them, which is the wall. They see these
shadows and they start to create a
reality around these shadows. They think
these shadows are real and they think um
and they create mythology, religion,
an entire framework around these
shadows. Okay? And this what we call
reality.
All right. So the main message here is
that
true wealth
is our attention. The okay
our consciousness is what's true wealth.
In fact our consciousness is what's
real. Everything else is just an
illusion. Everything else is is a
shadow. Your body is a shadow. Okay? The
person in front of you is a shadow.
This blackboard is a shadow. What's real
is the thing inside your head. The your
consciousness is what's real. Now what
power is
is the capacity to direct and control
this attention. Okay. How I exert power
over you is by making you think the way
I want you to think. By making you see
what I want you to see. Okay? So I can
make you see these shadows and make you
think it's real. And that's what true
power is.
And this is this idea once you
understand it explains the reality that
we live in. Okay? So I'm going to take
this idea and apply it to reality and
show you how it works. So
at the very basis of reality is the
empire. Okay? It is the American empire
that's able to force you to sit down and
look at the wall.
Then the people manipulating the fire,
casting the shadows are the game masters
and these are the financial elite. Okay,
including the bank of financial
settlements, uh the Federal Reserve,
uh Wall Street, City of London,
basically private capital.
They together
create the conditions for this game.
They're able to direct our attention.
Okay. And the mechanism they do this
with is of course with capital. Okay. Or
US dollars.
And then from and then again we create
something called the global economy of
course right the global economy.
But in order for this game to work, it
has to the game masters have to disguise
the fact that they're really in charge.
So they create institutions
that pretend to be objective,
international, and impartial and fair,
but but are fact controlled by the game
masters. These are include include of
course the UN, the WTO,
uh the EU,
uh the World Bank, okay? Lots and lots
of these organizations.
And then in order to justify and
legitimize this system, in order to make
you think these shadows are real, um
they media,
education,
and culture
brainwash you, indoctrinate you into the
system is real when it's all just a
hallucination. Okay. And then from this
of course you have uh the legal system
to enforce the system as well as customs
and habits values and norms. Okay. So
this is an enforcement mechanism to
force you to believe that the system
system is real. Okay. uh media,
education, culture brainwashes you to
believe the system is real and then you
yourself want to enforce the system on
others through customs and norms. Okay.
Now this is a very fragile system
because it's all just a hallucination.
So there are enforcement mechanisms
okay that make sure this system is
stable and these enforcement mechanisms
are crime
intelligence spies basically spy
networks
um and science.
Okay. And they these three mechanisms
are controlled by the true powers of
this world. And they include
transnational capital, basically private
capital, secret societies
and elite families.
And what binds them together? They're
basically software. Their operating
system is what we call the occult. Okay?
And we'll say more about the occult
later on. All right? Okay. Okay. So this
is how the world is designed. Again,
this is all a hallucination.
One thing that you don't appreciate
about the system is that from this
hallucination, I can actually project
myself onto another force and create
another hallucination. Okay, that's what
Richard Nixon did. from this system in
order to maintain the empire in order to
maintain the supremacy of the US dollar.
Okay, he created two new hallucinations
and they are the GCC and China.
Okay,
GCC
and China.
All right, so what underpinned this
system before was gold. The fact that US
dollar could always be exchanged for
gold. Once that's gone, then you need to
create new two new hallucinations in
order to disguise
the the hallucination. Okay. So, what
happened was that over the next few
decades,
this system will transport itself and
impose itself on the GCC and China.
Okay, this system here,
it will impose itself into
the GCC as well as China. In other
words, and this is really important for
you guys to understand, China is a
hallucination of a hallucination. It's
not real. Okay? I'll explain more about
this later on. Okay? All right. So
once this hilution is imposed onto the
GCC and China, this creates demand for
the US dollar. Okay? And this creates
certain stability for the US dollar and
it made China very very wealthy. Okay?
But it's all just an illusion. It's all
just a mirage. There's certain problems
with the system. First of all,
China doesn't have any creativity. Okay?
Why? Because if you're a hallucination
of a hallucination, there's nothing for
you to base yourself on. Okay? You're a
shadow of a shadow. That's the first
problem. Second problem is
um wealth
extraction. Okay. The idea here is that
whatever wealth China creates has to
return to the source
because the people inside China
appreciate that
the reming B its entire value is based
on the US dollar. So you have rem B or
US dollar. Of course you want US dollar.
Okay. And the third problem
is the fragility of this system.
Okay? Meaning that
if this system the hallucination is
unstable
then China is even more unstable because
it's a hallucination of a hallucination.
Okay. Do you understand? Okay. So once
we understand this then we begin to re
reassess what happened these past 10
years. Why do the United States and
China fight this trade war? The reason
why is that China believe that it could
be independent
of this hallucination. In fact, it could
create its own hallucination.
And the United States says no no guys no
you're coming dependent on us. So then
they start to fight this trade war. Once
this trade war happened, what happened?
A lot of money and people start to flee
China and move back to United States.
Okay.
And now what China has recognized is
okay first of all we can't actually
leave this hallucination because if this
hallucin
is actually to recouple okay
to bind ourselves even greater to the
system now I'm saying this is that the
US the global economy is under a lot of
strain there are two main beneficiaries
of the global economy the United States
and China.
So both are heavily invested in
maintaining the illusion, the
hallucination that is the global
economy. Okay? And to appreciate how
fragile all this is, think of the UAE.
Okay? The UAE.
The UAE seemed as though it was a very
prosperous place, right? Right? It had
universities from America like
Georgetown, Cornell.
It had people, the wealthiest people
flocking to Dubai. It seemed invincible.
But the moment you attack the UAE, like
Iran just lobs a missile at UAE, the
illusion shatters. And now the UAE is
gone. You understand? That's how
pecurious these hallucinations are.
one hit at the right spot, the entire
illusion is shattered. You can never
bring it back. Okay? And so that's what
China is afraid of. Now, so that's why
China and United States have to work
together because what's important is to
maintain the nature of reality itself.
The worst thing that can happen is if
people wake up from the stream because
people wake up from the stream,
everything collapses all at once.
Okay, does that make sense guys? Any
questions so far? Are we clear about
this? Okay. All right. So, how how now
that we have this theory, let's talk
about this idea concretely. Okay. All
right.
So, the United States used to be the
world's most powerful manufacturing
country. Okay. So, before it was the UK,
then you have the United States. Okay.
The United States is in the blue, right?
And then it and then China surpassed it.
This is intentional.
Okay. The intention is to use
manufacturing to extract the wealth of
China and transfer it to America. Okay.
So now China is the world's most
powerful manufacturing country. Okay.
And this this is a map that shows it
better. Okay. where China is now number
one. United States has moved on number
two. Japan and Germany are pretty flat.
This is intentional. The intention is to
bind China to the global economy to
become dependent on the global economy
and therefore save the global economy
when it's under strain. Okay. One major
consequence
of this um
uh of China's rise is the trade deficit
between
America and China. Okay. Unfortunately,
this trade deficit is a natural
consequence
of
um China's manufacturing
ascent.
Okay. Why? because the purpose is to
force China to buy more US dollars,
okay, in order to support the Ponzi
scheme. So this is a system that
benefits the Americans. When Trump came
into power in 2016, he said, "No, no,
no, no. It shows that China is taking
advantage of us."
And Trump doesn't really really
appreciate that. No, it was designed
this way. You you need to create demand
for US dollars. If China is buying a lot
of US dollars, that's a good thing,
right? China's trading real assets, the
energy of its people for fake assets,
which is just US dollars. Okay? So, it's
a great deal for America. But Trump
said, "No, this is a bad deal." And this
and this was what led to the trade war.
Okay? So, what led to the trade war is
the WTO.
So, in 1999,
China negotiated to join the WTO, the
World Trade Organization.
And this is this is what's going to make
China rich and the largest manufacturing
power in the world. But in order to join
WTO, China had to uh agree to a lot of
conditions. The two most important
conditions was
protect IP. Okay.
You have to protect other nations
intellectual property and you have to
enforce it. The other thing was
open the financial sector.
The goal is USD
ribbon B convertability.
Okay. So these are the two things
America wanted from China. First of all
to ensure that all US IP would be
protected in China vigorously. Second
thing is to allow any Chinese to convert
their money into US dollars.
as you can appreciate
these two demands actually bad for
China. Okay, so China was not very
stringent about protecting IP. This is
what led to the rise of Huawei.
Basically Huawei can take Apple IP and
make these great computers. So in the
year 2016
when Trump first came into power, Huawei
computers were actually better than
Apple computers because Huawei was was
constantly innovating and they were
trying to make the computers as cheap as
possible whereas Apple was essentially a
monopoly. Okay. And this led to United
States imposing trade sanctions on
Huawei because it was too competitive
against Apple. The second problem is
even worse because if you think about
it, if you just open up your financial
sector, all the money in China runs off
United States because Chinese appreciate
that we are a hallucination of a hall of
a hallucination. US dollars is more
valuable than means based on US dollars.
So wouldn't it make more sense to just
convert all into US dollars? But then
this would of course cause the collapse
of the Chinese economy
right so the the Chinese government
would refuse to open the financial
sector and that's what started the trade
war in 2016 sorry not 2016 in 2018 okay
2018 is when the war actually started up
to today so for the last 8 years this
war has been going on because America's
trying to protect its IP and and because
America wants trying to open up its
financial sector.
The reason why
Trump has come to China, the reason why
he's brought so many executives is
because China has essentially agreed to
open up its financial sector. Okay? I
I'll discuss this later on, but you you
have to appreciate how this war started
and why and why it's going to end.
All right? Now the thing about this war
is that for the past eight years China
and United States have been attacking
each other. There are two there are two
main mechanisms in which China attacked
the United States. The first mechanism
is by restricting
the supply of rare earth minerals to the
United States because as you can see
from this chart, China actually produces
most of the rare earth minerals. Now you
may not know this but actually rare
earths aren't that rare. The problem is
in the extraction. It is very expensive.
It is very enormously costly. China is
willing to pay pay these costs. The rest
of the world isn't. That's why China has
essentially a monopoly over lithium,
cobalt, graphite and other rare earths
that the EV industry, the solar
industry, the semiconductor industry are
heavily dependent on. Okay, that's the
first attack vector. Second attack
vector is the China appreciates that
China's value to the global economy is
that it purchases a lot of US dollars.
So then China started to buy more gold.
Okay. So you can see how uh the US
treasuries went down but then gold went
way up. Okay. And so this is the way
that China is trying to exert pressure
on the United States. The problem is
that China is much more vulnerable to
attack than the United States. Okay, the
United States is is a hallucination, but
China is a hallucination of a of a
hallucination. The first thing to
appreciate is that China's
energy dependence is huge. China spastes
sorry, China uses twice as much energy
as America for its manufacturing sector
in order to create exports. Therefore,
China is vulnerable to embargos and
sanctions. Okay? And so what America is
doing right now with this war in the
middle in the Middle East by um
kidnapping Maduro in Venezuela, it's
basically choking China off from its
energy energy supply. Okay, that's one
problem. Second problem is that China is
very export orientated. Okay, so the
entire economy is just basically on
exporting manufactured goods cheaply to
the rest of the world. And you and you
can tell because most of the world's
business ports are actually based in
China. Okay, the business is Shanghai uh
followed by um Singapore, Ningbo,
Shenzhen, Chinga, Guangjo. Okay, so four
four sorry five of the world's top six
ex export hubs are based in China that
shows you China's dependence on exports
but if ch if America's controlling the
seas and controlling choke points like
the mala and um the sh of hummus and
traalolar pan of canal this creates a
huge problem for China okay and the
third thing is how much resources China
uses. China in only three years time,
okay, from 2011 to tw 2013
use more cement than America did in 100
years.
That's crazy to think about.
All right.
So, this shows you how dependent China
is on the global economy. It it also
shows you how dependent China is on the
USD. Okay? Because it's only because the
rem can be exchanged for the USD that
allows China to purchase so many
resources from um abroad.
All right.
The reality is that China is too
dependent on America. This is something
that Chinese policy makers have been
have been trying to change for the past
10 years. It doesn't work because what
Chinese policymakers don't understand is
that you're in a hallucination of a
hallucination.
Okay? You only exist because America
created you. All right? So this is
consumer confidence. You can see um so
is when the trade war started. Okay. And
at this time
uh people are still okay. They're still
bearing the brunt of it. But then COVID
happened, right? And then you saw this
massive drop and it never really
recovered, guys. All right. It never
really recovered. Consumer confidence.
People don't believe the economy is
doing well. People are not willing to
buy things. People aren't working.
People are losing income,
right?
The economy is not doing well. At the
same time, this is really interesting.
More and more Chinese students are
choosing to study abroad. Even as
economy is failing, even as though there
are less and less less opportunities to
do well in China, more and more Chinese
are going to America to study. And guess
what? Not the very best are not coming
back. Okay? There's a gap of about a
million students who stay in the west
and these are often the very best
students. All right? So I hate to say
this but if you're hallucination
hallucination you're anxious you want to
go back to the source right so you know
the is based on US dollars if you can
change the fors you will do so if you
can flee the country immigrant abroad
you will do so
all right this is a pretty stark
data okay so um This shows you the
current account balance. Current
account.
Current account just basically means how
much Chinese Chinese have in the bank
due to trade. This
um is
the trade account. Okay. How much
Chinese actually traded. The the blue
tracks the current account. Okay. how
much Chinese have in the bank because of
the trade. The red tracks the actual
trade.
Okay, as you can see, for most of
China's history up until about, you
know, uh 2022,
it tracks pretty closely.
But starting in 2022, there's this
divergence, a huge divergence. You're
talking about five $500 billion a year,
guys.
Why is this happening?
Capital flight, money laundering. People
are using exports in order to move their
money out of the country. It's very it's
a very simple thing where okay, maybe
um
uh I buy a refrigerator from you, right?
It should be $500. We agree $500, but
you charge me $1,000.
Why? basically you take the $500 and you
put that money on my behalf into a US
real estate. You buy property or buy
stocks from me. Okay, does that make
sense? It's all just money laundering.
Okay, so in other words, what's really
driving China's export mania? A lot of
it is money laundering as people try to
flee the country.
Okay, so this is not good for China.
All right. Um, another major problem in
China is the household savings rate
where it's the highest in the world.
Okay, the highest in the world. Why is
chi why are Chinese um savers why are
they saving 40% of their income? Well, a
lot of reason is because Chinese aren't
that wealthy. Okay. So, even though the
Chinese economy has boommed these past
30, 40 years, the Chinese individual has
not seen a huge improvement
in his
um standard of living. Okay.
And so there is
not a great confidence in the future and
that's why Chinese save a lot of their
money and there are that actual that
that many investment vehicles as well.
So from a US perspective, this is a
great opportunity, right?
If Chinese are saving all this money, if
you're a financeier, if you're like
Blackstone or Block, you're like, why
not give it to me and I'll invest the
money for you and give you bigger
returns,
right? This is why they're here in China
because they want this. They want all
that capital stored in in Chinese banks,
not doing anything. They're like, give
it to us and we'll make you more money.
Okay.
All right.
Um,
so
this shows you the capital account. All
this is saying is that you can't
actually convert your room B into other
currencies. So most countries
have
full
uh open capital accounts. Okay. the the
black um is most countries.
The
bottom quarter of nations have closed
accounts and China is part of the
uh quarter that have closed accounts.
Okay. So, Chinese can actually take
their money and leave the country.
Okay. So
the other thing that I want you guys to
understand is from a US perspective,
there's still a lot of potential in
China. And the reason why is China still
has a lot of debt capacity.
Debt capacity just means your ability to
carry debt. Why? Because China doesn't
have much debt relative to other
nations. Look at this. Okay, China
in terms of like assets and liabilities
don't have much invested abroad. You
compare that with like other countries
like Japan, United States, Germany,
United Kingdom, they have a lot invested
abroad.
China doesn't have that much invested
abroad. So in theory, you can encourage
the Chinese to buy more things abroad,
which would which would help the global
economy, right? In theory. Now what's
interesting is that China doesn't invest
much abroad relative to other rich
nations but China doesn't invest much
abroad relative to all nations. Okay so
this is China it's about the same as
India which doesn't have that much
capital then like if Indonesia, Turkey,
Mexico actually invests more abroad than
China does. Brazil,
Russia, Saudi Arabia invests a lot.
South Africa invests a lot more than
China. Okay. So again from a US finan
financial perspective, China is a last
great opportunity
in the world. That's why they're coming
here. Okay. They want to strike a deal
where they can financialize the China
the Chinese economy. Basically use uh
the Chinese economy as collateral to
engage in financial speculation
everywhere in the world. Okay. So, let
me explain how they're going to do so.
All right.
So, China has
a closed capital account.
Why do you have a closed capital
account? Because you know for a fact
that if you open it, Chinese take their
B and convert it all into US dollars.
All right? And that causes your economy
to collapse. your bank system to
collapse. So,
so what's the solution here? Okay, first
of all, what we need to understand
something and this is like really
important for you guys to appreciate.
Banks
create money out of thin air.
Okay, money is just an illusion. So the
example is let's just say you're a
depositor
and you put a million dollars into a
bank. Okay? And the the way the bank
makes makes money is by lending to
entrepreneurs, right? So you then as a
bank you give a million dollars a loan
to an to a restaurant entrepreneur.
Okay? And this is how banks work. And
you think that okay well if the pot put
a million dollars in the bank the bank
then loans it to the to the restaurant
entrepreneur then in theory the bank
should have zero
in the bank right no the bank now has $2
million.
Okay.
The banks are allowed according to
accounting, they're allowed to collect
money every time they issue a loan. So,
not only they keep that million dollars
from the depositor, but they also are
able to print a million dollars to give
to the restaurant entrepreneur. Does
that make sense to you guys?
Okay. Do you guys want want to know why
this is the case?
Okay, I'll tell you anyway. Okay. All
right. Okay. So, before what were what
were banks? Banks were just merchants.
Okay. A merchant alliance.
Why? Because merchants needed capital in
order to trade. So, they came together
and they create their own bank. Okay?
So, they were an alliance. And so, what
merchants would do is basically deposit
their gold
into this alliance so that it can be
distributed elsewhere. Okay. Now, the
problem with gold is that it's heavy.
It's hard to transport. It's also
dangerous because you're pirates. Okay?
So, the way that they use the way that
they use gold in order to create um um
exchanges in order to create business is
they use receipts. Receipts
are contracts.
So rather than me give you the gold
physically, I just give you a piece of
paper saying that I guarantee that this
paper can be redeemed for gold at my
bank. Okay? Does that make sense? All
right. And then you have to keep track
of these exchanges.
So they create something called double
entry bookkeeping, which is basically
assets and liabilities.
Okay? And that's double entry book book
bookkeeping, something that we still use
today.
So let's just say I have a million
dollars in gold.
Okay. Well, that's easy. I just put it
into assets, right?
Okay. Then someone comes and says, I
need I need to borrow a million dollars
of gold. I'm like, fine, I'll give you a
receipt for it. Not a problem. My
problem is, do I put the receipt in
liabilities or assets?
Assets, of course. Right.
And that's how the system works
and system we still use today. That's
why banks are allowed to create money
out of thin air because of double entry
bookkeeping. Okay. Are you guys clear
clear about this?
>> Yeah.
Is it because that the banks have powers
to print money when they uh make loans
or because I think like if
some people deposit their money into the
bank and the bank need to give it back
it might be lie into the liability.
>> Okay. All right. All right. You don't
you don't understand what's going on.
Okay. All right. Listen. It's it's not
that hard. Okay. I have gold. I put the
gold into the bank. People come to
borrow the gold, right? Then I give a
paper saying this is gold basic. It's
it's a money. Okay. Money.
Okay. Is this money a debt or a
liability?
It doesn't make sense. It doesn't make
sense as a liability because I don't owe
that thing. Okay. And the fact that I
can use this money in order to create
more money creates means it's an asset.
Okay, does that make sense? All right.
So, so now this becomes a basis of the
global banking system. All right. So,
let let me show you how. All right.
So, what happens is this. You have these
banks
in America in the world. They're private
banks. They're run by people who put all
their money in the banks. Okay, you have
the US government. You have the
government.
Okay,
US government does not have any money.
The US government wants to borrow money.
The question then is like how do you
borrow money? If you borrow money from
these banks individually, that's too
hard. Okay. So, what happens is this.
What happens is 1913
the banks got together
and create something called the Federal
Reserve right federal reserve don't it's
not hard it's just a cartel of federal
banks in America okay do you understand
now can just work for the Federal
Reserve and borrow money directly from
the Federal Reserve which represents all
the banks in America
Okay. So, how does the US government
sell like borrow money from from the
Federal Reserve? It issues bonds. That's
called US treasuries.
Okay? So, the Federal Reserve can print
money to buy US treasuries and then this
money goes to US government
and US government can then pay for
expenses. Okay? Does it make sense? All
right. Now this system is fine. The
problem is that the US government spends
a lot of money. It fights wars. It wants
to send man to the moon. It wants people
to have a good life. Okay. So today,
America has $39 trillion in debt.
And you're like, well, who cares? Well,
the problem is this. The problem is the
interest rate, which is about 5%.
Okay. To because in order to get the
Federal Reserve, these private banks to
lend you the money, you have to give
them an interest rate. Otherwise, why
would they give why would they lend you
the money, right? Okay. So, in other
words, 5% means that the US government
has to pay the Federal Reserve about $2
trillion
a year. Where's that $2 trillion a year?
it has to borrow more money from the
Federal Reserve.
All right? So, this system is really,
really unstable.
So, now your problem is like, how do I
solve this problem? You solve this
problem by getting more people to buy US
treasuries.
Okay? Does that make sense? All right.
So you can get governments
to buy US treasuries, including the
Chinese government, the Japanese
government, the the UK government. Okay?
And that's what that's what what's been
happening. The problem is they only have
a certain amount of money they can
borrow. So how do you get rid of this
problem? You get you get rid of this
problem by getting more people to buy
um US treasuries. And who are these
people? Everyone in the world. You, me,
everyone in the world. Okay, this what
we call retail.
So previously it was only institutions
that want to buy US treasuries.
And what they what what the strategy now
is to get everyone to buy
your treasuries. how you create a new
financial mechanism called stable coins.
Okay, stable coins
and and the two most popular stable
coins are something called tether
and circle. Okay. And the idea is very
simple. The idea is stable coins are
backed by US treasuries,
meaning tea and circle have to buy US
treasuries in order to sell stable coins
and they can sell stable coins to anyone
and everyone.
Okay, including in China
which has 40%
savings rate.
How through institutions like um Apple,
Black Rockck,
Visa? Okay, does this make sense? Now
you get around the problem of the closed
capital account. Closed capital closed
capital account means you cannot use
rubing B to buy US dollars. But with
stable coins, you can use now use rub B
to buy tether or circle. Do you
understand?
Okay. So now what the US government is
going to do is they're going to transfer
that debt
onto the Chinese people.
Okay.
Okay. And so you're like, "Okay, wait,
wait a minute here. $39 trillion is a
lot of money, man. Chinese people don't
have $39 trillion.
Ch America will never ever get rid rid
of this debt." Okay? But there's a
mechanism American can use to control
this debt. And this debt and this is
called financial repression.
How does this work? Very simple. Okay.
So, um, US treasuries
are at 5%. Right?
Really simple. I'm going to make this
0%. Guys,
you're like, wait a minute here. No, no,
no. I don't understand this. If it is
0%, I'm going to buy yours treasuries.
The answer, the solution is I'll make
you buy it, guys. Okay? I force you to
buy it.
How do I force you to buy it? By passing
laws called the Genius Act
and the Clarity Act,
which compels stable coins
to use US treasuries as a basis of their
digital currency. And again, remember if
you're Chinese, if you can keep B at 5%
a year or US dollar at 0% a year, what
do you choose? You choose the US dollar
at 0% a year. Does that make sense,
guys? Okay. So, that's the solution.
Financial repression where I drop the
interest rate of US treasuries to
nothing, which case inflation
will destroy the debt over 50 years. And
I force people to buy it by passing laws
that force companies to back the digital
currency with US treasuries.
Forcing them buy US treasuries. Doesn't
make sense, guys. Okay. And why? And why
do they want to do this? Because now
they can access a Chinese consumer. They
can sell digital currency to Chinese
consumers. That's the grand plan.
Okay. And you're like, "Okay, wait a
minute here.
Why would China agree to such a stupid
deal? Well, there are actually lots of
reasons. Okay, the first major reason is
Taiwan.
Okay, so again,
the United States doesn't really need
Taiwan. Taiwan is over here and what
Taiwan does that's very important for U
for United States strategically is it
blocks
China from the Pacific. Okay. Something
called the first island chain. It's part
of the first island chain. It that's in
the blue.
So that's why Chinese American policy
makers think Taiwan is important. But
you think about it, okay? If you're
American, you're like, "Wait a minute
here." Okay, let let's just say I lose
Taiwan. Let's say I say to China,
I want Taiwan to return to the
motherland. Okay, what happens now?
Well, now you create a problem because
Taiwan now can block
this area. Okay? It can separate
Southeast Asia into two parts. South
Korea and Japan on one part, the
Philippines, Southeast Asia, Singapore
another part. Okay? Do you guys see this
map? You can now divide Southeast Asia
into two. This is important. Why?
Because guess what? Japan, South Korea
gets most of their energy through the SH
Maka. You basically block off South
Korea and Japan from a lot of the global
economy.
In which case, there's actually no way
in hell South Korea and Japan agree to
let Taiwan return to China. Doesn't make
sense. So by saying by the United States
saying hey I want China and Taiwan to
marry again what you've done is you've
now transferred the Taiwan problem from
you the United States to South Korea and
Japan you understand that's why
strategically it makes perfect sense for
Trump to say Taiwan belongs to China.
Okay.
Okay. So Taiwan issue pro problem is
solved. Now there's another there's
another issue in that China as we
discussed is very dependent on energy
and food from South America. Okay. So
you can see this is South America
and you can see all these projects in
the yellow that China is building. Okay.
So the pink is something that's already
built or under construction. The yellow
are planned. It's these are huge
projects.
Okay. So, what America has done is
basically taken over Venezuela.
Hey, and Trump
announced this like I think two days
ago. We're going to make Venezuela the
51st state. What? Why? Why would Why
would we want to do that? Because now he
blocks China from South America. And if
you look at this map, this tells you
energy supply. Okay? So if you So this
is war in the Middle East which means
that the Middle East you can forget
about. So China now can get energy from
Russia or the Western Hemisphere. China
doesn't want to depend entirely on
Russia. China will buy more Russian oil
but it does not want to become entirely
dependent on Russia. Also Russia cannot
actually meet all of China's energy
needs. Okay. So now China is forced to
negotiate with the United States to have
access to the to to the Western
Hemisphere. Does China care? The answer
is no. China only cares about stability
and price. Stability and cost. I want to
get things at a fair price and I want
this to be a stable and predictable
relationship. If I'm trying to I would
prefer if America control the entire
Western Hemisphere because now I I I can
just negotiate with one government as
opposed to like all these other
governments many of whom are corrupt.
Does it make sense guys? So would China
agree to this? Absolutely. China has
actually no problem with America
controlling the Western Hemisphere if it
means stability and cost are controlled.
Okay,
does this make sense to you guys? Okay.
Um yeah,
>> but does China hold attitude like about
America controlling Venezuela because
like using morals like they said they
can't
>> No, no, no, no, no, no, no. But
>> will they do this?
>> China doesn't care.
I don't guys don't talk about
sovereignty, right, morality in this
class, okay? It's all game theory. I
don't care about these things.
Game theory is people are going to
behave in their best interest. It's that
simple. Okay. No morality, no human
rights, no sovereignty. All right. Okay.
So, China doesn't care who controls
Venezuela as long it's a stable place
where China can get cheap oil. It
doesn't make sense.
Okay. All right. The last thing is AI.
Okay. All right. So, as you can see, the
United States is the world's leader in
AI simply because it has the most data
centers. In fact, America plans to build
more and more data centers. China is
trying to compete, but its data center
development is constrained by the fact
that it has limited access to
semiconductors,
to chips.
And so
China wants more chips from the United
States
and the United States can say yes. But
you're like, "No, no, no, wait, wait,
wait, no, no, no. Doesn't that mean that
China could one day overtake the United
States?
Could China just reverse engineer and
steal the IP from these semiconductors?"
No. That's not how semiconductors work.
Semiconductors are so sophisticated that
it's an entire global supply chain.
Okay. These semiconductors are designed
in California. Then they are sent to
Taiwan to be manufactured.
Then they're sent onto the Philippines
to be
value added. Then sent to China to be
added to components. Then they're sold
to Europe. And all the while you have to
extract resources from Africa, from
South America in order to feed these
semiconductors. Do you understand? So in
other words, there's actually no way
that one nation, only one nation can
control the entire supply chain. So as
long as America can control the trade
network, America will always have the
advantage in semiconductors.
Okay? There's actually no way China can
reverse the production of the
semiconductors because it's too
sophisticated. It's too expensive.
Only only one country can specialize
only one field.
Okay. Doesn't make sense. Okay. So
that's why this guy is important. Okay.
Jensen Huang or Nvidia
before
he was not supposed to come to China.
Okay. It was announced he was not coming
to China.
Then as Trump was flying through Alaska
to refuel, he got on board in Alaska. It
was a last minute addition. But not only
that, but there were two business people
that were with Trump on his plane. Alan
Musk and Janu. Okay. So what happened?
So I work in business negotiation. I'll
tell you exactly what happened. What
happened was that Scott Bessant and
Hulong they were negotiating this grand
bargain just the contours of this grand
bargain in South Korea. China wants
first and foremost Nvidia chips. Scott
Besson wants first and foremost access
to the Chinese financial market. Okay,
there was there was an impass. So Trump
just basically said I'm not I'm not
going to bring this guy. Okay. And then
as Trump was going to come to China,
there was a breakthrough and Trump's
like, "Okay, as a sign of goodwill, I
will now bring him." Okay, that this how
business negotiations work. This is
confusing for people because usually we
don't want business people to run
politics to run diplomacy because they
are unpredictable. Okay, but this is how
business negotions work.
All right. So this is just the uh basic
framework for how the US grand bargain
will turn out in my opinion. Okay. So to
summarize what China wants is access to
cheap energy of the western hemisphere.
It wants Nvidia chips to fuel its AI
um
um and it wants access to the US market.
Okay, those those are three things that
China wants. America wants access to
Chinese financial markets. Basically, it
wants Chinese consumers to buy stable
coins in order to finance the US debt.
It wants to better control China's AI
development. Why? Because with AI, China
and America are not competitors. They're
partners. Because, as I told you last
class, the entire entire part of AI is
to create a surveillance state. Okay.
Now, America has technology, but China
has a lot of people and there's no
privacy here. So, in other words, what
what America can do is use China as a
lab in order to test out surveillance
technology that you could not test out
in America.
Okay. So, America wants access to
China's uh AI market. And the third
thing that um America wants is Chinese
manufacturing.
Why? Because Chinese man manufacturing
is the best in the world. So, not only
does America want China to continue
manufacturing in order to buy US
dollars, but also wants to import
manufacturing, Chinese manufacturing
into America and to Venezuela as well,
right? Because Venezuela has all these
resources that can be extracted and into
manufactured goods. The Americans don't
want to do it because it's too
expensive. It's too hard work. But the
Chinese will do this. Okay? So this is
what the grand bargain will look like.
Any questions?
Okay. So these are predictions. This is
the way I see I see the situation and
we'll know in a couple couple days if
I'm right or wrong. Okay. So we'll talk
next week.