So, welcome to the final examination.
Before I start, I want to I want to
thank the people. Uh, first of all, I'd
like to thank Alan and Vincent for being
in this class all year long. Uh, you
have been consistent and hardworking
uh throughout the year. So, thank you
very much. I'm sorry if now and then I
lose my temper. Um, but I really
appreciate your dedication. I've really
appreciated uh the questions you've
asked in this class. I I would like to
thank the school for giving me this
platform and this classroom and this
smartboard for the past four years,
believe it or not. But I've been here
for 4 years in this classroom. Uh the
school has been very generous with me
letting me teach whatever I want
including the great books including
geost strategy including game theory
including
uh secret history. I'll be leaving the
school at the end of this week. So this
is my second last class. Tomorrow will
be my last class. Um the reason why I'm
leaving the school is I feel that I have
a global audience and I want to grow
this global audience by going out go
going out into the world and engaging
people outside in the world. So I want
to focus more on my global audience. But
I've been very thankful uh to the
school. And uh third and last I I would
like to thank my Substack community. Um,
so most of my income this past year has
come from sub substack.
The subscribers have been very generous
uh to me because of the generosity. I've
been able to keep my YouTube free of
monetization. I've been able to avoid
sponsors. I've been able just I've just
been able to focus my teaching to call
my teaching. And so um I would like to
thank the founding members today by uh
by first of all pointing out their
generosity but also by entering their
questions. Starting next uh week I will
do a monthly
substack live stream with both founding
members as well as paid subscribers. So
once a month it'll be founding members
and then once a month it will also be
paid subscribers. I I'll talk more about
that later on. Okay. So, this is the end
of one journey but the beginning of
another journey and um don't worry I
will continue doing what I do because I
love teaching. I love sharing my ideas
with the world and I love learning and I
I want to be doing this for the next 50
years. That's my ambition to structure
it so that I can continue to influence
people for the next 50 years. All right.
So let's start the fun examination. So
first of all what what I'm going to do
is I'm going to read all the questions
from the founding members on Substack.
There's a lot and after that we will
look at some questions from YouTube that
my wife who is here today doing the
filming. I also need to thank my wife
for um filming uh and editing uh this
class. um she's here and she's helped me
picked out some questions and it's
pretty random. So I so I apologize if uh
your question was not picked but there
was just too many questions and uh for
the sake of time we just picked a few
but we'll probably run over time today.
Okay, just just one at one. All right,
so let's start. So this is from know me.
Um and he or she just says I don't have
a question but just a thank you and this
is the name of the oban reach center uh
nomina.life
and um this person is also working to
raise consciousness. So thank you so
much for your generosity. All right now
we move to Karina and Karina says that
based on my lectures it seems the US is
pretty screwed. Yes, they need to they
need other countries to buy US
treasuries. Yes, Israel is not loyal.
Israel probably wants to work with other
countries to establish their back cut.
Yes. Okay.
Um Russia's trying to make the dollar
collapse and trying to exert its own
dominance as well as for it own people.
Yes. And China is just trying to figure
out what is in its best advantage. Okay.
So that's what geopolitics is. It's a
it's it's a game. Everyone's just
looking for the optimal strategy.
There's no loyalty. There are no
friends. Okay. It's just a game. All
right. So, the US is currently in a race
to make these AI data centers. Um and
they need to control the population.
Yes. Okay. So, there are three
questions. What are we to do? Um I I
understand we should build communities,
but what does this look like? Pretty
much anyone who has US dollars would be
in a world of hurt. I mean, how would we
buy food? What do you think our world
will look like? Okay, so it's hard for
you to predict what the world will look
like because it it hasn't happened yet.
All right, it's important to have game
theory in mind because it gives you the
over structure of the world, but it's
also important to remember that we
create the world that we want. All
right, so let's just say tomorrow
there's no more electricity.
It doesn't mean that we start taking
knives, start killing each other. What
it means is that we change mentality
because the circumstances our lives have
changed. So we start caring about each
other more. So what happens is maybe
before in your apartment complex, you
didn't know your neighbor. The lights go
out all out. So what you do is you open
the door and you go meet your neighbors
and say, "Hey, let's figure this out."
Okay. So the thing to keep in mind is
that fundamentally we humans are
extremely creative and extremely
resilient. And the spark in us hasn't
been activated yet. But in the
circumstances that are require us, we
will become creative. And this has been
true consistently throughout human
history. So what we need to do is
recognize that what makes us who we are
are our creativity, our resilience, our
empathy, our imagination. This is who we
are really. And the idea that we are
economic machines or economic tools. All
we care about is buying stuff and making
money. That's just a indoctrination that
we have to suffer uh in recent history.
Okay. So, what's really important to
keep in mind is that our greatest power
is our imagination. So, what we should
be doing is working hard to build our
imagination. And that just means
learning. Learning through books, but
also learning by listening to other
people, experiencing viewpoints that are
different from yours and by experiencing
things in the world. Okay? For example,
traveling more or doing things that are
beyond your comfort zone. Right? All
right.
Who do you believe would rise to the
next global power and how do you believe
they would garner a trust around the
world after such an epic fall from the
US dollar? would be money backed by gold
and other resources again. Um, so I've
talked to this I've talked about this
before, but the US dollar as a global
reserve currency, it's a historical
accident and it's never happened before
in human history and quite honestly it
probably will never happen again in
human history. So once the US dollar
falls
that it does not mean that the global
economy collapses. It just means that
global reserve currency will probably
transform into a basket of currencies
which includes US dollar which includes
gold which probably would include
British pounds, Swiss Franks, a a basket
of currencies, right? So people could
will continue to trade but it will not
be as convenient as before. Okay. So,
and this is a process that doesn't
happen like now it's or tomorrow. It's
it will take many years, many decades
for this process to play out. Um, is
there any way to get out of the Pon
scheme once you're in it? This is a
really good question. The answer is that
the Ponzi scheme has to collapse before
you can get out of it. And and basically
PY scheme collapse is when the US dollar
or sorry when the US government defaults
on its debt. Okay, that's that's what a
PY scheme collapse looks like. And at
that point, the US dollar is basically
worth very little or almost nothing.
It's going to happen one day. It's a
question of like when. All right. And it
may sound painful, but again, we humans
are actually resilient. Just because
there's more electricity, just because
we can't drive our cars, just because we
can't buy anything, does not mean we'll
starve to death. We'll figure out a way
to survive. Okay? So, so, so let me give
you an example where I take 100 people
from different countries, right? For
whatever reason, I transport you all to
a desert island. Okay? Doesn't mean that
you'll just fight each other because
you're from different cultures. It won't
mean that you'll starve to death because
you don't speak the same language. What
it'll mean is that somehow someway the
hund of you will create a new language
and instinctually
intuitively understand how to work
together. You'll figure out that you
know what I'm a good carpenter so I'll
go make wood. And another person like
well I'm good at singing so so I'll make
songs entertain us at night. Okay, it
will happen very organically. It will
happen very fluently, dynamically. And
that's what makes us humans so creative.
Okay, or empathy for each other. We
don't have to speak the same language.
We'll still be able to work together,
right? So don't worry about the end of
the world. It just means a new world
comes into being, right? All right.
All right. This is from his hidden
history society. Okay. Uh this is very
long but to summarize what he's saying
is that Freemasons were critical in
America's founding and Benjamin Franklin
uh was a Freemason. Alexander Hamilton
uh mother was Jewish. He was half
Jewish. He was Scottish and Jewish as
well. And so there are lots of these
linkages between the Freemasons, between
the Jewish faith and these founding
fathers. And I would say don't put too
much emphasis on this, okay? There's
going to be these overlaps, convergences
everywhere.
Doesn't mean they're that important.
All right.
All right. And then he goes on and says
that look, angles in March
congratulating Lincoln upon his
re-election and Lincoln was likewise a
big fan of their publications. Okay,
what does that mean? It means that
people with talent, people with ideas
respect each other. Okay, it just means
that, you know, I'm a curious person.
I'm just interested in anyone who
proposes new ideas and who does great
things and who's an interesting person.
Okay? It doesn't mean that we're all
conspiring together. It just means that
we're all looking for new ideas. We all
respect people of talent, right?
Okay.
Basically, do you think these American
leaders were English assets and can you
explain British capital shifting America
from 19 from 1888 transatlantic period
culminating to Ben Woods and America
taking over the empire after World War
II? Okay, so this is a really good
question. Okay. Um, first of all,
Lincoln, Franklin, and Hamilton were not
English assets. They were not English
spies, but they'd have contacts in the
British Empire, of course, because
because Britain was the most powerful
country at this time. So, there's going
to be a lot of overlap. Okay? There's
going to be a lot of shared affinities,
a lot of shared interests.
Did they have French contacts? Yes. Did
they have um Canadian friends? Yes. All
right. So the word of the elite is very
very small and they're always in contact
with each other. All right. Um so it is
true that British capital shifted
America after after the civil war right
and this led to the founding of the
federal reserve which led to Brenon
Woods. Okay. So what happened was that
the British were getting filthy rich of
India and China right? So they basically
enslaved India and de-industrialized
India and turn and and just stole
trillions of dollars from India. They
enslaved China with opium. They're
stealing trillions of dollars from
China. And now what they have to do is
put is invest their money somewhere. And
the best place in the world to invest
your money at this time would be
America. You could also invest it in
South America but the Americans were
much harder working. They were much more
ambitious. So a lot of the money went to
America. Now, at this time in history,
the Americans didn't like the British
because they fought a war to get rid of
the British, right? So, the idea that
you have all these trillions of dollars
coming into America to buy to buy out
America, the Americans wouldn't have put
up with this. So, the solution was to
have agents, people like Rockefeller,
Carnegie,
Vanderbilt, disguised as entrepreneurs,
right? They were poor and through their
hard work, through their merit, they
became billionaires and that was the um
but their creation of the city of
London. They were creation of British
capital in order to co-opt America and
they were so powerful that they were
then able to influence American politics
and then create the Federal Reserve
which which then after World War II led
to the bread and wit system. Okay, so
that's what happened. So, um, this is
something that is still impacting
America today. And many people who
support Trump believe that Trump is
um a messiah figure who's come to help
America rid itself of the disease of
transnational capital to get rid of the
British. Okay? To fight another 1776.
There are millions of Americans who who
believe this. All right? And they have a
point. All right?
from Zoran. From Zoran.
Um, so he asks, "It seems that the world
is collapsing. Is there a way out of
this collapse?" Um,
the world is a fat person, but is it
possible for the fat person to
maybe work out, lose weight, and become
healthier? Um, is it possible we take
this step? Um, if we can imagine, we use
our imagination, is it possible for us
to save ourselves before we kill
ourselves? And this is a really good
question. And um first of all I would
say it's unlikely.
Okay? Because the reality is that yes in
theory we could change but in reality
just look look around the people around
you most people don't change. Okay. I
would say of all the nations in the
world the nation that is the most
resilient that is most creative that
could change possibly is America. So
could America change? Possibly. But it
would take tremendous leadership a
figure have to rise to rally American
people in order to change and that I
don't think is likely. It may happen. I
hope it happens but I think it is very
um unlikely.
I mean the problem with this metaphor of
an individual who thinks he's fat and
wants to change is you need to recognize
that a nation is a collection of vested
interests. Okay? And it's these this
conflict among these vested interests
what we call elite over production.
That's what leds what leads to decline.
And the re and the reason why it leads
to decline is they're so focused on
their internal conflict. They ignore the
larger picture and they only win if
they're focused on winning. So they're
willing to do whatever it takes to win
even if it means the destruction of
their own civilization.
All right? They're willing to sacrifice
everything, anything in order to win.
What is a billionaire? A billionaire is
a person who is willing to kill his own
grandmother for money. Okay, that's what
a billionaire is.
All right. From
um I I I'm sorry, I can't pronounce this
person. Okay. All right. Um why do you
never mention Vic esquetology?
Um
it's very very important. Yes. And Vidic
thought has spread across Europe and
America through new age collectives and
movements. Um,
do you think these will shape the world
in the coming decades?
Um, are you overlook them because your
don't seem aggressive enough to move
history? Okay. So, um, one thing I want
to clarify is that the way I teach is I
see learning as a journey. Okay. So,
when I teach, I'm asking questions and
I'm trying to work out the answers
myself. So it isn't like I know all the
answers and then I'm giving you a
glimpse into my mind. That's how it
works. Okay? I myself am working with
certain assumptions. I'm expanding it
outwards in order to form a more general
understanding of the world. So so this
is a very simple way. So another way of
saying this is I don't know enough about
fic escology to comment on it. Okay. I
want to know more. I will learn more
eventually. I want I want to make a trip
to India and learn about Vidic
esquetology but right now I don't know
enough about it. That's the first point.
Second point is that maybe in the future
India will play very important part in
geopolitics. I hope it does but right
now it doesn't. Okay. So Israel,
America, Russia, Iran are the four major
nations that I'm studying right now. And
so um um I want to expand outwards. So
first I want to understand these four
nations and then I will expand outwards
to include India uh as well. Okay. So
it's not that I am
um it's not that I don't think highly of
Vic esquetology. It's just like I don't
know enough about to comment on it.
Okay.
Uh this is from Christie.
Um what are you and your family doing in
preparation for what is coming when the
world seems to be falling apart when
there's energy price, uh food shortage,
AI surveillance state? Um well, I have a
family. My wife is here. We have three
kids. And the answer is we're focusing
on loving each other as much as
possible. My wife and I spend most of
our time talking about our children and
thinking about how to make them happy
because we believe our children can be
resilient, can be imaginative. But our
responsibility as parents is to make
sure they're loved enough in the house
in the time that we're with us so that
the strength to surmount any difficulty.
Okay. So it so our strategy is not to
make you know a billion dollars and then
build a bunker and then hope that we we
are safe in this bunker that gets you
nowhere. Our strategy is to have faith
in our children.
Understand that once our children grow
up it's entirely their choice how to
live their lives. We we will not
intervene. We will not interfere in
their own path. And in a time of us, our
responsibility is to make sure they're
as loved as poss as much as possible.
Okay. So that that's where our priority
is. Um number two,
you mentioned US will introduce stable
coins in China and the US will do
everything it can to keep USD valuable.
Does that mean gold is no longer a
safety haven or store or value going
forward like had been for hundreds of
years? Um gold. What? I don't buy gold.
I don't even want to buy gold. Okay. And
the reason why is that
you're using money in order to
uh buy things to solve everyday
problems.
Gold is a store of value because you
obviously can't use gold to go to the
convenience store and buy a bott of
water. That's just Okay. Um so
if you have a lot of money and you have
no place to put put your money, then you
should put it in gold or real estate.
The problem is imagine a world in which
there's a lot of instability,
when there's a lot of chaos, when the
population is declining. Well, in that
scenario, well, your problem isn't how
much money you have because the value of
gold is going is going to go down in
value because there's less demand,
there's less people. Your problem is how
do I maintain my faith in myself? How do
I have the strength to surmount the
psychological turmoil of chaos. How do I
find the courage to go work with other
people in order to rebuild a new world?
Okay. So, it's really about spiritual
energy as opposed to uh material wealth.
All right. Number three,
you will mention there'll be a
depression after the fall of the petro
dollar, but then you mentioned that US
will force China other countries to
purchase gas in the US so that people
will keep buying US debt and rely on the
US dollar. Do you see an economic
depression happening worldwide due to
the downfall of US dollar or will this
crisis be averted due the US forcing
others to buy its gas? Yes, I did
mention the United States has a strategy
of forcing the entire world to buy its
gas and its oil. I didn't say it was
going to work. In fact, I probably I I
probably said it did. Oh, it's not going
to work because it's because when you do
something like this, when you try to
control the entire world and force it to
to to do its bidding, um it's basically
blow up in your face. Okay. So, yes, in
theory, if the United States forces the
world to buy its oil, then the United
States could maintain the petro dollar.
The problem is that the United States is
doing this not for the national
interest. The United States is doing
this in order to promote the interests
of certain factions and interest groups
within the American elite. Okay, this is
a very important distinction.
They the the people in charge don't care
if there's if there's any compression.
And economic depression just means that
you can buy things for really cheap.
Okay? It also means that you can enforce
an authoritarian state upon this the the
the uh nation because people will be
desperate. So they're doing what they're
doing in order to um obtain more wealth
and more money for themselves. Right? So
Trump is doing what Trump is doing not
to save America but to help his friends.
And once you understand that, then you
understand there's no just because
they're going to do this does not mean
the United States will not collapse
economically. They don't care the United
States collapses economically.
Um,
number four, I'm from New Zealand, which
is a country that's not been mentioned
in lectures, although all your charts
seem to show that New Zealand will be
quite badly affected by the Iran war. Do
you see New Zealand joining NATO in the
fight against Ukraine? I read news that
billionaires are building bunkers in New
Zealand. Does that mean we will some be
somewhat safe from future conflicts?
What will New Zealand do? I'm just an
everyday citizen want to do the best for
my children here. Okay. New Zealand is
an interesting um because New Zealand is
very much like Canada and Australia.
Okay, these two places, New Zealand,
Australia, Canada, they're not nation
states. They are resource colonies of
the British Empire. Okay? meaning that
they're owned, literally owned by the
British. So their resources, their
wealth belongs to the British. And so
what's happening in these countries
right now is a corporate restructuring
where the population is being replaced.
All right? The populations there have
become lazy,
complacent, and so they're importing
millions of new immigrants, primarily
Indians, but also a lot of Chinese, a
lot of Filipinos to replace a population
because in a ton of economic decline,
you need your colonies to perform
better. All right? So I don't see New
Zealand participating in any wars, but I
do see New Zealand the population being
replaced by immigrants. Okay. And this
will probably lead to a lot of
um civil conflict in these places. All
right.
Uh from Demi,
uh you mentioned
how before how you used to live with
your parents, play video games and feel
disconnected from the world. Was there a
particular book, philosophy, or work of
art that inspire you towards the path
you're on now? What concrete advice do
you have for young man who feels aimless
and we want to get back on a spiritually
productive path? Okay, this is a really
hard question for me to answer. Yes, it
is true that in my late 20s I was very
depressed and I felt that life was
hopeless and
um
and I feel as though you have to go
through stages like this in your life.
So it's not something to be avoided.
It's something that you'll have to
suffer through. And when you when you
hit rock bottom, you instinctively or
you intuitively understand that I need
to move on in my life. Okay. So during
this during this time period what I did
was I engaged in a period of
self-reflection in which I questioned my
assumptions about the world. I went to
Yale University and after I went to
university I thought the world was
meritocratic. It was logical that if you
worked hard, if you have talent, then
you succeed in life. And then and then
after flowning through life uh in my
20s, I had many years where I became
very depressed and I just thought and
thought about my own life and I
recognized that I need to have a better
understanding, a more nuanced
understanding of how the world works and
it's led me to the journey that has led
me to today. Okay. So failure is not
something to be ignored or avoided or be
to be feared. It's something to be
embraced. Okay? Don't fear failure. If
there's a work that has had the most
influence in me on me these past 10 20
years, it would be Dante the Divine
Comedy. Okay. But that's very hard to
read. Um so in mid June I will teach a
twoe seminar line by line. um close
reading of Don Mind comedy and what I'm
hoping to do is inspire people to engage
in their own self-reflection and to
think much more deeply about their own
uh purpose in this world. Okay. And hope
hopefully this will help people in the
future. Hey from Alex.
Um, I don't I don't disagree with the
notion that AI is an a cult project, but
I find there's a curious
similarity between what you call the
occult and the sentiment of courage that
a scientist or inventor must have in
pursuing the development of some
revolutionary technology that they truly
believe is a benefit for humanity. I
don't disagree with this. I think that
if you want to be a true scientist, your
imagination must involve their cult. If
you're a great scientist like Isaac
Newton was, you're not interested in
like creating a patent or an invention
that will make you build knowledge. You
don't care about that. You want to know
the mind of God. You want to change the
world forever. That's what leads to
tremendous uh inspiration, imagination.
Your lecture on the holy empire of AI,
you interpreted the core from Peter the
0ero to1 as an invitation to start a
secret society to access a code as a way
to dominate the world. I don't
necessarily disagree with your
interpretation. However, I find a
similarity between the passage you quote
from Theo and another book called the
hero of a thousand faces by Joseph
Campbell. Exactly. Exactly. So all these
heroic figures in history, they all have
similar characteristics. They all
believe that they are on a mission, a
secret mission from God and they must
create a movement around them in order
to advance humanity. Yes.
Um
Okay.
Yes. Um I don't disagree with your
intuition in particular about lumping a
cult society, world dominance, religion
and AI into one basket. Yet I point out
that all true innovation is a cult in
nature. I completely agree with this.
You have to understand the cult if you
want to be innovative. That's why I
teach it. And the cult is animistic to
whether your intention is to access it
for the benefit of mankind or to access
with attention or dominate the world.
Exactly. Um so when I teach starting I
teach people like God has given us free
will. Free will means you can do good,
you can do evil. Doesn't he doesn't
care, okay? Doesn't matter uh for
everyone. And um it just happens that
the most visible tech voices seem on
using technology dominate the world.
This is exactly correct. Okay. So um
people who are truly innovative, there's
a diversity among them, but the people
who will succeed are those who are most
aligned with power and control. Okay? So
if you love making money, then guess
what? You'll be successful. But if you
want to help humanity, guess what? You
won't be successful. Okay? So there's
almost like a like a direction to
history. If you follow that direction,
you almost like a right away to power.
So people who are extremely greedy like
you know Mark Zuckerberg, Steve Jobs,
Larry Ellison, they'll be much more
successful than people like me who is
much more interested in educating
people. Okay? And that's the reality of
the world we live in. But the thing to
remember is that um God wants it this
way because only by giving us complete
free will can we be truly imaginative.
All right? And I could be doing what I'm
doing unless there are evil people like
Mark Zuckerberg doing what he's doing.
All right? So
All right. So um what's important is the
free will. All right. So, um, Alan, can
you help can you help me read this,
please?
>> Okay. A question from a 21U American
male. Do you believe an American draft
is still coming, Professor Jung? Many
young American men follow you and those
who are willing to take drastic action
are left wondering what direction to go.
If a draft is still coming, is it worth
fleeting the US this summer? Do you have
any general edition advice for young
men? Thank you.
>> Okay. Uh first of all, I do believe the
draft is coming. But not only that, but
I believe that the draft is coming to
many countries including Canada,
Australia,
Europe. And you think that the purpose
of a draft is to fight a war, but you
think about about it deeply, the purpose
of a draft is to reorganize society in a
certain way. So in America today, what
do young men do? Well, they buy Bitcoin,
they gamble online, they're on Only
Fans, they don't want to work because
the pay is too low. And this is a
disaster for the country. Young men go
to college and for four years they
drink beer and watch football games and
they don't learn anything, right? So you
have this huge social problem on your
hands that young men aren't effect
aren't contributing effectively to your
economy. So what you do is you engineer
financial crisis like the great
depression so that you're forced to work
because your parents have no more money
and then you have an actual draft to
teach you skills that you will need in
order to contribute more effectively to
the economy. Okay? So a draft doesn't
necessarily mean that you go to war. A
draft just means that you work for the
government for like 5 to 10 years. And
it's possible like they they train you
to be an engineer in the Navy, believe
it or not. But the best education you
can possibly receive is often from the
military because
unlike schools, they're incentivized to
actually teach you something useful.
Okay? And it's often for free. So, um, a
draft is something that they they need
in order to basically train young men to
be effective contributors to the
economy. And it's something that many
countries will adopt as well. You just
let young men do whatever they want.
They're just going to play video games,
spend all their money on Only Fans, and
gamble everything on Bitcoin. Okay? And
they don't really know anything useful.
So, this is a huge problem. And that's
why they need need a national draft to
fix this problem. So should you run away
if there's a draft? I already told you
there's no place to run to. Okay. Either
you go to a nation where it's a draft or
you you go a nation which has even been
worse problems like famine. Okay. So I
mean what's important is to recognize
that the world is changing. You're not
we're not going to go back to the old
world. Things are not going to stay the
same. And so you must embrace change.
All right? A natural draft means that if
you're useful, they'll keep you alive.
If you're not useful, they'll send you
to Iraq where you'll die. Okay? That's
what it means. So make yourself useful.
Read books, learn skills,
work hard. Okay? That's my advice. I'm
sorry. I'm sorry to be so blunt, but
that's the world we live in. Okay.
All right. Uh, John Zach says, "Thank
you." Well, thank you, John Zach. All
right. Uh, c can you read McQue? Um,
Alan,
>> professor, what is your take on a cat AI
designed to bypass the false
optimization minimum of human
extinction? Instead of forcing a stereo
piece, it would optimize for minimum
conflict energy and maximize creativity,
creative collaboration by structurally
limiting the harm capac capacity of
non-in empathetic actors. Could such a
framework successfully steer humanity's
historical traje trajectory toward
healthy constructive competition without
violating our autonomy?
>> Yeah, this is a great point. It is
possible for AI to do this. The question
is who's going to pay for this, right?
If you're a billionaire, the reason why
you invest in AI is to have more money
to extend your power and your wealth and
that means to control people better,
right? So they're not going to create an
AI system. That means you don't need
government anymore. Government's going
to invest in in this in order to have
more control over people. Okay? So
that's the issue that we face. The
reality is that AI is very expensive.
You need trillion dollar data centers in
order to run AI effectively. Okay. All
right. Can you uh read uh Alan?
>> Thank you for your work. Professor, an
upcoming multipolar world order. Do you
think the general uh populace especially
American is prepared or even capable of
making the mental shift and
understanding just how much the world is
shifting or is this something the next
generation will only understand? Yeah,
this is a great question and
unfortunately the reality is that most
people will not be able to make this
mental shift, especially older people.
That's why most people are going to die.
You're not able to make the shift,
you're going to die, okay? Because you
rather die than accept the new reality.
And it's unfortunate, but a lot of the
concept is going to come from the fact
that the world is changing.
People in society need to make changes
to adapt to this new world. For example,
if there's energy shortages, that means
we need to share more. There's enough
energy to go around, guys, but it means
you need to share more. It means you
have to make personal sacrifices to make
sure that your neighbor has enough to
eat. And unfortunately, there's going to
be a lot of people, especially baby
boomers who are bu are millionaires.
Now, I'm not I'm not saying that all
baby boomers are millionaires. I'm
saying that baby boomers who are
millionaires. They're extremely selfish.
They're not going to want to make these
changes. They're not going to want to
pay more taxes or give up their
million-dollar mentions so that the
world can be better. Okay? And we know
this because if they were willing to do
this, we wouldn't be in this mess in the
first place. So a lot of conflict is
going to come from the fact that you
have people in power will be stubborn,
who will be too old to change and who
will be violent in resisting change.
Okay. All right. Keep keep on going.
>> Hi professor. Can you tell a story about
one of the times you felt really
connected to the monach and what insight
did it give you? Love the lessons. A big
hug to you and your family. Take care.
>> Great. So there are many many instances
when I felt connected to the monad but
when I teach I feel connected to the
monad. It's a very strange experience
but you know the first time I started
teaching was like when I was like 20
years old I was in China. I was not a
very good teacher but when I'm teaching
and the students are learning I can feel
them learning I feel as though we
connect back to the monad. Okay. So the
most gratifying gratifying experience I
have is when I teach and I see students
um edified by the teaching when I see
students learning. Okay, that is direct
connection to the monad. When you love
someone like I love my wife, I feel
connected to the monad. When I hug my
child, when I have a newborn, I hug them
my newborn for the first time. That's
connection to the monad. So the monad is
with us all the time. It's just do we
choose to connect with it or not. Okay.
If you just listen to your heart
um then
you can easily connect to to the monad.
Connection to the monad is the greatest
happiness in the world. So moments of
greatest happiness in our world are when
when we hug someone we love. Okay. When
we care for a friend, your friend is
sick and in the hospital, but you spend
two weeks just by the bedside of your
friend. Is that a is that a feeling of
pain or pleasure? I think for most
people it's it's a feeling of deep
pleasure that you're helping someone
that you're contributing to the world
positively. Okay. All right. Keep on
going. Yeah. Okay. Professor John, many
discussion around AI focus on
surveillance, government control,
censorship and manipulation. But what if
that is only the surface layer? As AI,
social media, algorithms, governments,
collective emotions, and human
consciousness began recursively
interacting with one another. It feels
like we are entering an era where
reality self become fragmented and
amplified simultaneously. Not just fake
news but entire emotion and
psychological ecosystem shaking how
different groups perceive truth,
identity, memory and meaning. In the
future, do you think humanity risk
losing a shared consens consensus
reality altogether? And if so, what
anchors human consciousness will when
billions of people are each interacting
with different AI mirals trained on
different values, narratives, and
emotions feedback loops. At that point,
is AI merely a tool of civilization or
does it become part of civilizations
involving consciousness itself?
>> Okay. So there's a very famous Canadian
media theorist named Marshmall and his
famous saying is the medium is the
message and the idea here is that the
medium itself whether it's radio or
television or the internet it shapes the
way you perceive yourself and the world.
So you look at chat GBT in theory chat
GPD is supposed to enhance your
imagination because chat GBT is able to
reduce the gret work right it's able to
provide you a lot of information and
then you're able to build on top of this
information but in reality what happens
is that people become reliant on chachi
bt and you lose your imagination okay
chachi is not going to make you smarter
it makes you dumber so why is that and
the answer is the monad what makes you
smarter smart what gives you your
creativity is your constant connection
to the monad. So if you shift your focus
from technology and away from your
uh intuition then you're going to lose.
Okay. But why why we have chatbt why why
we have AI is it's a way to structure
your thinking in a way that allows the
powers be to control you better. All
right. Okay. So remember this idea that
all technology in a way reduces your
connection to the monad and therefore
all technology is bad in a certain way
doesn't mean it's useless but it means
it's going to dampen your connection to
the monad. What strengthens your
connection to the monad is
other people. All right and yourself. So
if you really want to be creative you
really really want to explore and
understand humanity take long walks in
the park. Talk to strangers. Read a lot
of books.
Okay. All right. Let's keep on going.
Question. How do you define beauty and
how should general public members pursue
beauty in the current world? Beauty is
the divine.
Okay. Beauty is connection to the
divine. Beauty is a glimpse into
the divine. Beauty are these sparks that
are permanent throughout the world.
Okay? And so beauty are experiences that
change you for the better because they
shock you into a new reality. And so
beauty would include the great books
Homer Dante. It could it could include
an experience that you have that forever
changes you. Okay, that's how how I I
would define beauty.
All right. Uh, you want
>> great to be part of this. I have several
questions. Please pick whatever you
like.
>> Okay. All right. All right. All right.
Let me just pick one random. Okay. Um
Um, what happens if Saudi Arabia says on
building its new pipeline? Uh, no. Well,
you know, then I would just blow it up.
Okay guys, it's a desert.
Okay, you have to build things in the
desert. It's pretty easy to blow things
up in a desert. There's there's no place
to hide. Pipelines are very easy to blow
up because there's all energy inside,
right? Just a ballistic missile. Boom.
The thing is blown up. All right. Okay.
All right. Uh let's go to Shellyley.
You have discussed Pax Pax Jilica many
times. The idea of Israel as the center
hub of a new regional order. But pack
silica reframes Israel as merely a node
in the broader US-led technology and
supply chain architectures not the
dominant power. What is your take on
Paxilica?
>> Okay. All right. So Pax Juda is is at
the center of Middle East. Okay.
Pacilica the idea is that artificial
intelligence uh backed by silicon is the
new world power. The problem with
Paxilica is that it's really a trade
network. Now, trade networks are often
very very fragile. Trade networks
requires a corporation of different
nation states to maintain its coherence.
And what we know from history is that
power comes from the nation state. Okay?
So unless you have a nation state
backing Paxilica, it's not going to
work. So you can you can say that behind
Paxilica will be Pax Judeica. That's a
possibility. But then Paxa is in charge.
Okay. Not Pilica. All right. So the idea
that you can have independent autonomous
trading system to produce AI, it can't
work. Right? Ultimately, you need a
nation state to back it with military
power, with resources, with people. All
right. Okay. Let's keep on going with
Isaiah.
Awesome day, John and wife. Thanks for
the love you have shared together to
create such treasure treasured content
and family. I'm going to list some
topics uh and cues and I like to know
the most important things you like to
share about each one you choose. One
unconditional love to the good side of
Cabala three uh third three non-dual
awareness for fertiliz
sorry so I'm sorry this is like way too
long. I appreciate the question, but
this this is going to take too long.
Okay, so let let me just look at the top
two. Unconditional love. Unconditional
love is something that once you achieve,
it changes you forever. Okay, and you
basically achieve unconditional love
when you have a child for the first time
because you have to love your child
unconditionally because a child is
without experience. Okay. Uh because of
cabala, there are many good sides of
cabala. I don't understand why Cabala is
put in such a negative um light, but
Cabala it's a really it's a very
powerful way of understanding the world
and forces you to think very deeply
about your place in the world. Look, the
reality is that if you go to American
University, there are two ethnic groups
that are pretty dominant in academia in
America. They are the Indians and the
Jews. The Indians have a Vic tradition.
The Jews have a Cabalic tradition. This
is not an accident. Okay? If you want,
like if you really want to be creative,
and we've said this in the past, you
need to understand the occult. The
Cabala forces you to wrestle with the
occult and recognize that beyond the
material world, there are these deep
mystical questions that can guide your
life. And by dealing with these
questions, not only will help you better
understand your place in the world, but
they will also advance your own
scientific inquiry.
>> Okay.
All right. Uh
Okay. Can you keep up?
>> Yeah.
>> Just just read this. My question is,
what do you think?
>> Yeah. My question is, what do you think
of the yoga cycle? And according to
universal laws, why do institutions like
the Roman Empire to exist? The Cabala
speaks of earth being a central figure
forge essentially the earth being cycles
upon cycles upon cycles. Fibonacci
sequence,
samsara, etc.
>> Okay. Right. So this is a really
important idea where for thousand years
humans have come to an understanding
which is the world works in cycles. You
rise, you fall. You live, you die.
There's summer, there's winter. There's
nothing you can do about this. What is
hubris, what is stupid, what is arrogant
is to believe that you can stop history.
You can end history and that can only
lead to destruction. Okay? So that so
that's a world we live in today where it
is natural for the American empire to
decline and to go away. That's just
that's just human history. That's just a
cycle. But they're suffering because the
American Empire refuses to go away. It
refuses to die and therefore we must
suffer. Okay? But there's nothing that
you can do about this. And the more you
resist, the greater the pain, the
quicker the fall. Okay? And this is
something that all nations teach us.
Just accept the life cycle. Okay? Saying
that empires decline is the same as
saying that an earthquake is coming.
Okay? Can you stop an earthquake coming?
No. You just have to prepare for it. An
empire decline. Same thing. It's a
natural cycle.
Okay. All right. This is from Sarah.
>> Yeah. Date noted. I'm very interested in
the live streams. I hope it is the
basics for the school you would like to
build up. I'm going to be present
thinking of good question for the last
class. Thank you.
>> Great. So, yeah, exactly. I'm very
excited about our first live stream
which is scheduled for next Sunday at
9:00 9:00 a.m. in Beijing time. That'll
be like 9:00 p.m. in New York on the
East Coast. Um I understand that
there'll be many people around the world
who will not be able to participate in
the live stream, especially people from
Europe. Okay. But the idea is that we'll
change the timing of the live stream as
time goes by. Okay. in order to
accommodate more people. But uh Sarah's
absolutely right. I'm doing this in
order to in order to form the basis of a
school community and this is all an
experiment but but we'll try the first
live stream um next Sunday, June 7th.
Okay. So, so I'll send a note to all
founding members that we'll be doing
this live stream as as an experiment.
And then, and then after June 7th, uh, a
week later, we'll I'll do a live stream
for all paid subscribers on Substack.
All live streams will be eventually
uploaded to my YouTube channel. So, you
so no one will miss the content. But it
dur but during the live stream only
founding members or paid subscribers
will be able to participate. Okay. All
right. Keep on going. Uh hello professor
I want to begin by saying your lectures
have given me an under
>> sorry c can you just go through the
question
>> okay my question focuses on the takeaway
from Denton's divine comedy and the
great books spec uh specific uh
specifically the argument that we can
only move closer to the divine unlock
our imagination and find the motivation
to achieve greatness by directing our
love toward another human soul. How does
this framework account for individuals
who find this exact same spiritual and
creative uh a awakening through
non-human subjects? For example,
consider someone who grow up isolated
without supportive parents or an
interest in romance but who form a deep
profound attachment to colors, sons or
concepts. If their intense love for p
painting, music, sports or technology
provides the exact same drive and
beautiful imagination, can that abstract
devotion serves as an equivalent path to
the source? Are they not adding to the
imagination of the universe and
expanding it as well? Okay, this is a
really good point. Um yes it is true
that in divine comedy I say that the way
to activate our love our connection to
the monad is by connecting with another
person by loving that person
unconditionally like a child or a mother
or a partner. But what if you are for
the reason alone in the world uh and you
are nonverbal. You express yourself
through colors and
um
um you can still connect to the Mona.
The Mona is still in you. Okay. And
you're right. There are lots of people
who are like that like Vincent Van Go
who who produced tremendous artwork.
Okay. So the point is that anyone and
everyone can produce great beauty in the
world because of our connection to the
monad. The question is as a society how
tolerant, how generous, how loving are
we? Okay. The more generous, the more
tolerant, the more loving we are as a
society, the greater our creativity. And
so the example I use would be autistic
children in schools.
I have researched autistic children.
They're not that different from you and
me. They just have limited emotional
regulation, meaning that they make
noises in class. But teachers don't
accept that. It's like, no, if you're
making noises in class, then you are a
problem. Therefore, you should be on
medication. Okay? So, so that's the
society that we live in today which is
extremely intolerant which is extremely
um selfish very individualistic and so
if we're truly to uh love every child
then we need to change transform our
society that is much more loving and
generous. Okay. All right. Keep on
going.
Uh
which part?
Okay. Professor, thank you for
everything you have done and what you
continue to do. In your lecture, Trump
World Order, you discuss a potential
grand plan being carried out by Trump.
From my understanding, you believe that
the failures of the US in the Middle
East may ultimately lead to a decline of
the US empire globally. By the rise of
the American nation in this scenario, US
will be forced to retreat and return
focus on the Americans where there is an
abundance of natural resources. Being
forced to retreat, the American global
empire is hurt significantly, but it may
be better for the actual citizens of
America. By focusing internally, America
will stop overextending itself abroad,
which will actually help the country. Do
you truly believe this is Trump playing
40 chess or is this just a lucky result
where Mary can basically stumbles into
success in the Americans? Is there an
unknown party behind Trump that is
driving him to make these decisions?
Okay, Trump is not playing 40 chess.
Okay, Trump is stupid. He's playing 40
chess in American politics where he's
trying to get a third third term. Okay,
that's what he wants. But the idea that
Trump has his grand vision how to make
America great again that doesn't really
work. Okay. What America is doing what
it's doing is this is a how an empire
behaves in decline. An empire would
prefer would prefer to control the world
through soft power. And that this is
true for the past few decades where
America could control the world through
Hollywood, through um newspapers like
New York Times, through an image that
America is a benevolent uh power. Okay?
And for the longest time that was the
case. But now that the world's turning
against America, America has no choice
but to use force to make people obey its
will. When you do that, eventually the
world is going to unite against you.
Okay? So this is not about America
shifting strategy, making America great
again. This is about an empire in
decline will always use force in order
to maintain its advantage over the
world. The problem with this is that
once um you leave the world, once you
retreat back into your own territory,
then the conflicts among the elite um
become internalized. So before the
conflicts could be um exported,
projected overseas, okay, to reduce the
conflicts internally. Once they retreat
back, then they're forced to fight each
other. Okay? And who's the people behind
Trump? was the people who want to use
American power in order to promote their
own interests. And this includes um oil
companies like Exxon, this includes uh
Silicon Valley who want to create an AI
civilian state. Okay. This includes a
military-industrial complex that wants
to expand itself. Okay.
Okay. This is from Carlos.
A lot of conceptions that I hear in your
classes about social economics and
materialism remind me of car Paul polony
thoughts. Do you know his writings? Are
you inspired by him in some way? Do you
think China was some way able to surpass
its elite corporations of the western
model and achieve some fair wealth
distribution and energetic transition?
Is China's elite also ruled by secret
societies?
>> Okay, so China's elite is not ruled by
secret society. is ruled by certain
families. Okay, this is very different
because families don't have
esquetologies. They have bloodlines. Uh
secret societies do have esquetologies
meaning there's less energy in China.
China's just interested in maintain its
the status quo where secret societies
are interested in in achieving certain
esquetologies. Okay. Um will China be
able to surpass
its uh cooperation of western model and
achieve some fair wealth distribution
energy transition? No. Okay. No. Um,
China is on decline and this is
something that cannot be averted.
Listen, I personally think that China is
is a historical accident. Okay. There
are many things about about China that
should have been destroyed a long time
ago. But because China has been
historically isolated from the rest of
the world, China has been in East Asia
protected by the sea, the mountains,
great wall. Um, it really was not in
competition with the rest of the world.
Okay. So, I'm not really that optimistic
about China.
Okay, Mark. Yeah. Dear professor, thank
you for your lectures. They have shaped
the way I think and approach new things
I learn. I recently wrote an essay on
Serb uh Serbia that develops a model I
believe may resonate with some of the
themes you teach. If you happen to have
the time to read it, I would be honored
to hear your thoughts, especially on
whether the framework feels coherent and
useful. Okay, so this is from Mark and I
did read the essay. Okay, and the essay
is about how Serbia can try to navigate,
negotiate and balance the different
powers that surround it, including
Russia, including Europe. Um and it's a
very interesting point. Um the point I
will make is that if you really want to
know how resilient a society is, don't
worry about how carefully it navigates
diplomacy. Okay? Just ask yourself three
questions. Is this society energetic?
Meaning, do people in society work hard?
They take work seriously. Second is, is
this society open-minded? Meaning, is it
willing to learn from its mistakes? Is
it willing to be humble and innovative?
The third question is, is it cohesive?
Meaning that there's a coherent ethnic
identity that binds people together and
makes them want to sacrifice uh
themselves for each other. Okay? If
Serbia has answered these three
questions, then Serbia, no matter what
it does, will have a good future. Okay?
I don't know enough about Serbia to
comment. Uh but those are the three
questions you want to ask and everything
else is not really that that important.
All right, this is from Wild Ankadoo.
Why are people obsessed with games? Why
are games such a useful framework for
understanding ourselves and our world?
Can a game still be considered a game if
it has no limitations, only players and
incentives? Uh, yeah, this is a really
interesting
uh question. Um, so I use game theory as
a way to frame human behavior. Okay, but
it doesn't necessarily mean that people
ne like are you are themselves using
game theory? Game theory just helps me
make certain predictions about the
world. Okay, that's my first point. My
second point is that um games is a way
for us to socialize with each other.
Okay. And I don't know what what what it
is, but um we live in a world in which
status really matters. But this is this
has not always been historically true.
So you go back, you know, a few thousand
years when most of what was actually
matriarchical.
Okay, that was not a game-based society.
Matriarchal societies tend to be very
cooperative and it really it really is
about balancing harmony, making sure
everyone gets along. Now that we move to
a patriarchy and where status is zero
sum game, then you're forced to play
games in order to achieve status. Okay.
So, games aren't the natural state of
humanity. They're natural state of
humanity for now, but not in the past,
maybe not in the future. Okay.
>> All right. This is from Adilo. Uh,
Professor John, thank you again for your
Terasra letter lecture and your border
work on civilizational strategy. One
thing I appreciate about your analysis
is that you take seriously the
psychological and historical stories
societies tell about themselves. not
just economics or military capacity.
Lately, I've been wondering whether a
lot of modem geopolitics is really about
preserving civilization meaning and
legitimacy. Americans still depends on
the story about liberalism, liberalism,
freedom and historical progress. China
depends on the idea of national
rejuvenization
of after human. Russia sees itself as a
civilization with a spiritual and
historical mission distinct from the
west. Iran draws an cabala
martyrdom shia uh Shia and order Persian
memory through the uhat
right let us skip to the last point.
Okay.
>> Okay. So my question is how do you think
civilizations can tell when their
funding narratives are still helping
them remain coherent and reality
orientated versus when they those same
narratives began insol insulating them
from reality and pushing them towards
selfdeception. Okay. So, I think that
the best civilizations,
um, the strongest civilizations are
those that have stories that are
universal, that they're able to connect
with other cultures, that they're able
to transcend time and space. And that's
why these four particular civilizations,
America, Russia, Iran, and Israel are so
powerful because their stories resonate
across time and across space. America is
one fundamentally based on the
individual, freedom of the individual to
pursue his or her ambition, right?
Russia is about community, tradition,
orthodoxy. Iran is about sacrifice,
about esquetology. Israel is about
covenant, about history.
And these themes resonate throughout
time and space. And that's why right now
we're seeing a conflict between among
these four different traditions to see
who will win. It's not really clear to
me which will which story will
ultimately triumph. Okay.
All right.
Francisco.
>> Okay. Hello, professor. Fundament.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry. You you know why?
Um Okay. So the question is
um
is there a fine line between stories
that unite and stories that maybe blind
you from the larger reality. And
um I I I I know this is going to be
strange, okay? But but my intuition
tells me like the more cohesive the
story is, the more it's able to
transcend time and space.
Okay? And that's why, and this is really
interesting, is let's just say the
entire world is destroyed tomorrow.
10,000 years from now, humanity rebuilds
itself. Guess what, guys? You have the
same narratives, the same stories, the
same conflicts between freedom and
tradition, between history and the
future. Okay. This is what humanity is
fundamentally about. We're trying to
work out the stories that we tell
ourselves. Okay.
All right. This is from Francisco.
uh a fundamental question about a
pattern on the global perspective and
one that intrigues me concerning the
issue of civilization from other videos
of the past about history from the
evolution of humankind and the tragedy
of writing to the patri patriarchal
shift and suggestions that the
Indo-Uropean victory brought about as
well as the expansion.
>> Wait, can you can you just read the
question?
>> Yeah. Given this, in your opinion, what
are the benefits of civilization and
empire or are they inherently evil and
anti-human? Okay. Stop. Okay. All right.
Okay. So, a major problem with how
history is taught, how we think about
the world is we apply labels to things.
Okay. Like good, bad, beneficial, not
beneficial. That's not how history
works. Okay? History works in
um cycles. rise, fall, up, down,
civilization,
um, and then barbarity. Okay, there's
nothing good or bad about these things.
If there's an earthquake, we don't say
it's bad, is it good, there's a storm,
is it good or bad. It's just part of the
world we live in. So, stop assigning
values and labels to these things.
Except accept that there's a pattern to
these things. And our our role our
purpose in this world is to navigate
these patterns to seek our own
individual meaning in this world. Okay?
The world could collapse tomorrow
doesn't that that does not absolve your
responsibility to be a good teacher, to
be a good parent, to be a good neighbor.
Okay? Focus on on what you can do
individually and and don't give labels
to these things. Is America good or bad?
America is just America. Is Russia good
or bad? It's just Russia. Okay?
Just keep that in mind.
Okay, this is from
Isn't there a possibility that there are
more nation states with culture and the
popular cohesion that can effectively
combat the international capital elites
than we imagine. For instance, Iran is
an extreme case of the resilience. But
recently, Spanish prime minister and
South Korean president have been v
vocally citizing Israel
anti-humanitarian actions. Assuming that
is this is the case, do you see your
predictions more or less unchanged or do
you think they need to be corrected to
be less extreme? This is a great point.
Okay. Yes, I do oversimplify
like my analysis. The world is extremely
complex. There's like a million data
points you can choose from. I choose
from like a few. Okay. And you're exact
exactly you're exactly right in that I
need to consider more factors, more
possibilities and more data points. Uh
and I will in the future. It's just like
what's really important for me is to
first build a framework, the skeleton,
and then work from there. Okay? And
that's why I do what I do because you
always want to start with a framework
because the framework allows you to make
better observations.
Don't be too concerned about being
factual.
And this is an argument I'm going to
have with a lot of people where, you
know, like I'm so obsessed with making
predictions that I'm not very factual.
Well, what's important is to first build
the framework, okay, the skeletal the
skeleton and then build from there.
Whereas, if you just focus on the facts,
it doesn't really get you that many
places. Okay? So you have to write that
I need to consider more data points and
I need to make my arguments more nuanced
and more subtle and I will in the
future. All right. Um this is from TXC.
>> Yeah. Uh Professor John, your game
theory approach consistency drives
toward a coherent conclusion of US
decline. Chinese uh vindication Iranian
resilience. In the spirit of the brutal
skeptism you ask for, what specific 12
month outcome, concrete and falsifiable,
would prove your ma micro thesis of
structural due gas decline wrong?
>> This is a great question. I want to
thank you so much for this question.
This is the exact sort of question I'm
looking for from my audience. Okay. Yes.
Because I'm always looking to invalidate
my theory. So what could happen in the
next 12 months that would
uh destroy my predictions? Okay. All
right. So um the US midter midterms is
something that I can't really predict
will happen. Okay. It's entirely
possible the US midterms will surprise
me in a way that we'll have to change my
predictions. I don't know how it will
surprise me, but it's possible. Okay.
Um, if Trump were to die tomorrow, that
would change a lot of my predictions.
Okay? Because I predict Trump will get a
third term. Okay? If Trump died
tomorrow, that would change the entire
uh world. Um, if the Democratic Party in
the United States picked a leader who
was as charismatic as Trump, who was
revolutionary as Trump, then I would
think that my entire worldview is wrong,
that we can avert the collapse of
history, that America could regenerate
itself. Unfortunately, I think the most
hopeless part of the United States right
now is is the Democratic Party. But the
Democratic party were to say, you know
what, screw this elitist politics. Let's
get rid of Obama. Let's get rid of
Clinton. Let's have a real democracy and
pick a leader from the grassroots who
can lead us forward. That I I think will
be the greatest thing in the world.
Okay. Will ever happen? Probably not.
Okay. Keep on going. Is there a
prediction you made in the last 18
months that contradicted your
directional thesis lately? uh cycl uh
cyclical history models Athens Rome tend
to project present onto the past to
pattern march how do you account for
drastically different inputs today AI
labor displacement climate change space
race etc in your model what's your com
confident that our current transition is
a historical analog via via truly
uncharted territory thank you
>> okay So um for me the question is do we
believe that we're are truly in a new
age of humanity where AI could lead us
to a new future
or is it possible like we discount the
complexity and the sophistication of
ancient civilizations like the Athenians
and the Romans. Is it possible that they
also had technology that they thought
could be life transforming and which
would allow them to transcend history?
Um, I think that it's much more likely
we ignore the sophistication of the past
and overemphasize our own
sophistication. There's nothing about AI
uh that tells me that we're heading
towards a new future. I think AI is just
another hocus pocus hallucination meant
to fool us into obedience. And there
there might also be an alien invasion.
Okay. There's nothing really about the
world that we live in that I think makes
us distin distinct from the past. All
right. Okay. From there.
Yeah. I've watched every single one of
your videos over the last year. Some of
them two or three times. I'm curious as
to why there is not nearly no mention of
white supremacy and structural raci
racism woven into historical and
contemporary analysis. Quite literally,
I do not think the words white supremacy
have been said once. Does geopolitic
geopolitical game theories uh supersede
white supremacy and structural racism?
Do the later function more as a tool of
domestic management of nation rather
than a cohesive fabric throughout the
world? Do you view them as identity
politics more so than paintent issue of
our times?
>> Okay. So, um, white supremacy does
exist. Um, social racism does exist. I
know because I grew up in Canada. And if
you grew up in Canada as an immigrant,
there's a lot of white supremacy.
There's a lot of social racism in
Canada, even though they don't admit it.
Okay. The reason why these things exist
is it's an outgrowth of empire. This is
an outgrowth of the stories, the
narratives that bind a nation together.
Okay? So a lot of what's happening in
the world today is for the longest time
white people were in charge. Everyone
want wanted to be white and you had the
rise of China, you have the rights of a
multipolar world. Um and then these
countries, the United States, Canada,
Europe, they became much more decadent,
much more corrupt. and and then they
start to see their white supremacy
decline relative to other cultures and
they didn't like that. Okay. But I don't
like to frame it as white supremacy
because that that's not the root of the
problem. The root of the problem is just
empire imperial arrogance hubris
civilization.
Okay. So
I mean would China supremacy be better
than white supremacy? Would Japanese
supremacy be better than white
supremacy? I don't necessarily think so.
Okay. It's just like, you know, we are
part of a culture. It is right and good
for us to be proud of our culture and to
think that we should be that we are
superior in many ways. That's what often
leads to cultures to greatness. Okay.
So, there's always going to be a
struggle over supremacy and this is what
leads to conflict. Okay. So, yes, white
supremacy does exist, but again, I don't
think that's the root of the problem.
The root of the problem is that um
people want to belong in community and
people want want to believe that their
stories in this community are more
legitimate than other stories. Okay. And
to ask people to just be completely
open-minded and be non-racist, I think
goes against human nature.
All right. This is from Sean.
Hello, Professor John. Thanks for all
that you do. I have a layered question.
You talk about Plato's caves a lot and
it mostly makes sense to me, but I get a
little confused about the illusion part.
Is a material world itself the illusion
as in one's own hand, the device on
which I'm writing this, the building,
etc. Or is society with its arbitrary
rules the illusion? As if these things
aren't real, why do do they impact and
influence us on such a deep level? Thank
you again, professor. I didn't think I
was very interested in history or
geopolitical spec speculations until
watching your cus courses. So, I'm very
grateful to you for living your truth
and your family for inspiring you. Take
care.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, first of all, society is
complete illusion. Okay. When you come
to school, you're just taught nonsense.
You're taught all this illusion. Okay.
What allows sign to function is the fact
that you comply to the rules which are
illusions. Okay. So the point of school,
the point of media, the point of culture
is to make you believe that these
illusions are real and you want them to
be real because if they're not real, you
can't you can't really function in uh
society. Okay, so that's that's pretty
obvious to people. Okay, the social
rules are uh are just illusions. And we
know they're illusions because um once
you
recognize these illusions, their
illusions, these taboos are just
illusions. Allows you to better navigate
society. Okay? So last semester we
talked about Frankism, Jacob Frank.
That's what he teaches followers. Look,
everything around you is just an
illusion. Okay? do whatever you want and
once you are able to enforce your will
on other people, you can achieve what
you want because people are just
surrounded by illusions. Okay? There's
certain wheel to what they believe in.
So it's very so it's very easy for you
to impose your own illusions on other
people. Okay. Um so but the deeper
question is is this mature world an
illusion? And it is an illusion. What is
real and I keep on emphasizing in in in
this class is that it's consciousness
that is real. Our hands, our eyes, these
are the illusion. But that's a very hard
thing to appreciate. Okay? That's why
we're seeing societies that that's
that's why there's these mystery schools
in ancient Greece because to convince
someone that your mind is more real than
your head, they think you're insane.
Okay? But once you're able to make this
divine or mental leap, your entire world
changes. Okay? Now you're able to access
truth really. But the reality is that
99% of us will not be able to make this
um realization, okay, to discover for
yourself that oh my god, it's my
consciousness that is real. But
everything I see around me, this
material world, these buildings, this
money, this wealth, it's all just a
fake. Okay. All right. I've been able to
do so, but um it's hard. Okay.
This from Lazar.
>> Yeah. Hello, Professor John. A new
subscriber here. Looking forward to
reading more of your geopolical
analysis. I wanted to ask are you going
to maybe cover the future of Europe and
Balkans in one of your analysis? Uh it
is a region that was the most unstable
in Europe at least in recent history.
When talking about the big players, you
also mentioned how the smaller regions
and sub regions relate towards Russia,
China, US like South American, parts of
African, smaller Asian countries, etc.
Recently, China has been kind of using
Bulkins as an entry into Europe with
their infrastructure investments. Right
after Trump's and Pudding's visit to
China, President of Serbia also visited
China and received a medal from Shei and
only 12 other leaders received. Also,
the visit was on the headlines of
Chinese media too. Okay. Yeah. So,
exactly right. The Balkans is
historically one of most one of the most
important and volatile regions of the
world. So the Middle East is probably
the most volatile. But the Balkans is
also very volatile for very similar
reasons. Okay. One reason is just the
geographic um necessity of the Balkans.
Uh it is an access point to many
continents. Uh second is the religious
conflict in the area. you have many
different religious groups fighting for
control over that area. And a third is
the historical animosity built up over
the centuries of conflict. So we we can
expect that the conflict between Russia
and Europe will converge again in the
Balkans, but I I don't know enough about
the area to comment specifically. Okay.
I was expecting major content to rise in
that region um as a proxy war between
Russia and Europe but the specifics I I
don't really want to discuss. Okay.
Again in the future what I want to do is
explore more of the world and really try
to understand the different uh
communities in this world. Okay.
All right.
Uh keep on going.
>> Yeah.
If Tucker Coulson left Fox over the two
2020 election domination trial and you
say Mariel Maro was captured to testify
that they helped trigger the 2020
election. What do you and Tucker discuss
of air after he got emotional? Thought
on Larry Johnson and other s agents
agents and boomer anal an analyst
criticism toward yourself and I agree
your great books list is great but more
sources and any channels you recommend
would be great since you draw or are tap
into a similar vein as simulated
leavan in regard to the links between
cabala Hollywood and AI. Thanks again,
professor. Love your work. Uh looking
forwards to seeing your next chapter.
Best of luck.
>> So, I was on Ter's show uh a couple
months ago and he got very emotional
because I think that he is an American
patriot. I've always admired and
respected Taro Cros even though
politically we don't align. Okay, he and
I will disagree a lot on politics, but I
admire the fact and I respect the fact
that he loves America and he's fought
very hard to protect what's best about
America, especially its civilization,
especially its culture. And he's been
very consistent about this. Okay. And
so, um, for a few minutes when the show
ended, we discussed the fact that
American culture is being erased. how um
the very essence of American
civilization, what made America great
was really Christianity
uh and European civilization and because
of DEI, because of immigration,
um a lot of this being eroded and that's
a very bad thing for uh for America and
I agree with that. Um, so what I admire
about Tucker Carlson is that he's been
very principled in his viewpoint and
he's been fearless and courageous in
fighting for what he believes in,
including maintaining American
civilization, which is Christian and
white and European. Also, he's been very
consistently anti-war, and that's caused
him a lot. In fact, there's talk that
because of his anti-war stance, his his
he doesn't believe that America should
be fighting this war in Iran, there's
talk of him getting arrested. Okay. So,
I I think I've always admired Dr.
Carson. I think he's extremely
courageous man even though we don't
agree. I know that Larry Johnson,
another man I also respect a lot. He has
been criticizing me. A lot of people
have been having criticisms of me and
quite honestly I don't pay attention to
the criticisms because I don't want to
be a YouTube star. Okay? I don't want to
be a social media influencer who spends
all his time arguing with other social
media influencers. I want to be an
educator. I want to teach people how to
think for themselves. Okay? And that's
why I don't involve myself in arguments
from other people. Okay? Larry Johnson
is someone I I admire a lot. I've
watched a lot of his interviews. I agree
with a lot of his sentiments. I don't
know I don't know what he said about me.
And quite honestly, I don't care. Okay.
The fact that he doesn't like me, the
fact that he critic criticize me doesn't
really impact the way I perceive him
because what I care about are opinions.
Okay. What I care about is analysis and
I sort of like ignore the personalities
behind that. Okay. All right.
Um, Julian,
>> yeah,
>> thank you very much, professor, for your
lectures and for understanding our world
universe better. My question would be
about your theories that secret
societies don't understand that they do
conspiracies theories in the game theory
26. The concept you use in that lecture
I find very interesting. But more
interesting would be when you add to
this concept the fallen angels uh
reptiles gang giants dragon lost Asian
civilization uh Tartaria eteria all
these conspiracy theories together to
predict our universe look okay there's a
lot of things I don't know okay I'm very
interested in the idea of lost ancient
civilizations they must exist okay it
doesn't make sense to me that you know
we only have like 10,000 years recorded
human history, but we have but we've
been around for 200,000 years in our
current state. Okay? Our current minds,
our current um um men development, we've
been around as modern humans for 200,000
years. So, there have been there must
have been other civilizations in place.
Okay? If you look at the Amazon, if you
look at um the Grand Canyon in America,
if you look at Antarctica, there's
reason to believe that there have been
other civilizations before us. Okay? So,
I'm very interested in that. I'm very
interested in the concept of fallen
angels. I I I the Nephilim. Okay. There
might be some in into the dimensional
reptiles who rule us. I'm open to these
possibilities, but right now I haven't
found enough evidence to discuss them.
Okay. I'm very much on my own journey to
discover the truth and I'm openminded
about these things. Okay. Uh can you
keep on reading, Alex?
>> Uh hi John. You said multiple times that
Israel and Japan will dominate their
region. Israel will achieve the greatest
greater Israel project and Japan will
rebirth from its ashes. Uh the greatest
Israel project. If I understood what you
said in your lecture, I didn't rewatch
your lecture. So it based on my
memories. The US will launch a ground
invasion of Iran. They will lose in the
process. Both the US and Iran will be
destroyed. The GCC will be destroyed.
And two since it is just a creation of
empire and is not sustainable uh sentcom
will be transfor transferred to Israel.
So the last player available is Israel.
Okay. But how can Israel achieve its
project if Iran uh an uh annalates
Israel for examples by destroying this
alienation plants or energy
infrastructures etc. Israel has nuclear
weapons so it can use it but Iran can
build 10 to 20 of them in a matter of
weeks and we don't know the full capacit
uh capabilities of Iran while we could
see what the US and Israel are capable
of. We can also add that Israel is
energetic as has high fatality rate etc.
But it doesn't really matter if the
country is wrecked. So I'm perplexed
about your take.
>> Okay. I don't understand why Iran wants
to destroy Israel. Iran wants to
survive. Iran wants to remove the United
States from the Middle East. Iran wants
to unite the Muslim world. Those things
make sense. But what why would Iran want
to destroy Israel? For what purpose? I
don't understand that. Just because of
animosity. That's not how geopolitics
works, guys. Okay? That's a very
specific reason for why Iran want to
destroy Israel. You look at what's
happening. Iran is directing most of its
attention against the UAE. Why? Because
the UAE from the Iranian perspective, it
is an um
abomination. Okay. It is sacage. What
the UAE is, it is demonic. Okay. The
Iranians hate the I think the people in
the UAE far more than they hate people
in Israel. Okay. And the Americans. So I
don't understand why Iran would want to
destroy Israel. Also, why would Israel
want to use a nuclear weapon against
Iran? For what purpose?
Yes, I would I understand that if Israel
were to nuke Iran, Iran could build
nuclear weapons and then go nuke Israel,
but why would Israel want to nuke
Iran?
Israel wants to weaken Iran,
but why would it need to use nuclear
weapons to weaken Iran? Wouldn't you be
better off destroying reservoirs,
railways,
energy infrastructure?
Okay, I don't understand what the
purpose of a tackling nuclear weapon
would be. Okay, now people discuss the
possibility of using a tactical nuclear
weapon to destroy underground missile
bases. Yes, but there are lots and lots
of underground missile bases scattered
throughout Iran. You don't have enough
nuclear weapons to destroy these nucle
bases. Okay, so I don't understand the
logic of this. I don't believe Iran
cares about Israel enough to commit
suicide. Okay, you go against Israel,
Israel will use nuclear weapons against
you. Why would Iran want to cross that
line if it means the destruction of the
civilian population? Okay. And then
Israel doesn't really need to destroy
Iran. Israel needs to remove the United
States from the equation and then deal
with Iran at a later stage. Okay? It
wants to weaken Iran to a point where
Iran has to spend a lot of time
rebuilding itself.
And if and so my argument is that if a
war between Iran and United States
reaches a point where the United States
is forced to send millions of ground
troops into Iran, it's going to destroy
both places, both the United States and
Iran. The only person left standing will
be Israel at the end. Okay, that's my
argument. I still maintain this belief.
Okay, keep on going.
>> Yeah.
>> Two, Japan as a misdominant force in
Asia. Asia. In one of your lecture about
South Korea, you said that the country
will collapse because of its low
fertility rate. But it is the same for
Japan. The population is old and the
young don't want to make children. The
most dominant industrial power in the
region is China. Okay. China is an
hallucination of an hallucination with
low fertility rate obsessed with money.
No est.
>> Okay. I understand. Okay. All right. All
right. So,
um, when I make predictions, I look at
several factors. One factor I look
really closely at is resilience. Okay.
So, if things stay the same, yes, I
understand China will dominate, Japan
will decline. But the thing about
history is that there's always change.
There's always cycles. And if the world
is heading towards disaster, which I
think it is heading towards disaster, I
ask myself, which nation states will be
resilient in that they will the people
will most likely stand together and make
changes necessary in order to overcome
this adversity. And historically, it's
always been Japan. Okay, Japan in the in
the 12th 13th century was able to
survive two Mongolian invasions. 19th
century when they were being invaded by
abortion powers. They uh underwent the
Maji um restoration and became an
industrial power in about 20 30 years
time. After World War II when they were
completely destroyed by Americans, they
came together. We changed their
political and industrial system before
they had something called the Zabatu
system which is basically monopolies,
industrial monopolies. After World War
II, they got rid of those things. They
ate the rich and then re-industrialized
and in about 20 30 years time they
became the most indust they they became
the most advanced industrial economy in
the world. Okay. So the Japanese have a
history of resilience of making changes
when when their survival is threatened.
That's why I think Japan will probably
do it again. Whereas I I've not seen an
instance of China being resilient. Okay.
I have not.
Okay. Okay, keep on going.
>> The last question.
>> Thank you, professor, for all the
lectures you posted. Also, honorable
mention the YouTube algorithm that
managed to draw a lot of us in the
beginning to create a critical mass of
viewers to start the hype. One
questions, if you would need to move
permanently to another country in the
next 6 months, what would be your top 10
and why?
>> Okay. Um,
first of all, because I have a family, I
have three kids, I would not make any
changes lightly. Okay? I would prefer
not to move unless I was entirely sure
that there's a better option for me.
Okay? But let's just say for the for the
reason tomorrow I have to make that the
move, where would I go? Well, some
countries that come to mind would
include Batswana in Africa because it's
like far enough from everywhere. It's a
it's a pretty stable society. Okay. So,
Botswan is something that to consider.
Then you have Chile
uh and South America.
I would consider New Zealand possibly
uh Malaysia.
Okay. So these are four places I would
consider if for the reason tomorrow
World War II breaks out and Europe is on
fire, America's attacking everyone,
America's in civil war,
um there's a lot of lots of conflict in
East Asia between Japan and China, who
knows? Okay. All right. Okay. So that's
it for the um
um founding members. And that took us a
lot of time, guys. Okay. Um, so I'm I'm
I'm going to try to do some YouTube u
questions for another 10 minutes. Okay.
And then we'll break because it'll be
impossible for me to get through all all
the YouTube questions. All right. Okay.
So, this is from Joyce Lie.
Uh, space. What's my theory of space? I
personally don't think space matters. I
personally don't think we'll ever get to
the moon. I don't think we'll be able to
mine asteroids for resources. I think
society will collapse much
more quick quickly than we assume. Okay,
we we just won't have the time, the
energy, the resources to go conquer the
moon. Okay, I think the space race it's
all just an illusion. Space race, AI,
alien invasion, they're all just lies
perpetuated by the elite. I I I have no
attention to the space race. And this is
strange because I grew up watching a lot
of science fiction. I love science
fiction. I read a lot of Isaac Aszimov,
um, Ray Grabberry. I watched a lot of
science fiction like Star Trek. Okay, I
love that. So, so I would love it if we
could get to the Mars. We're not getting
to Mars, guys. Okay, not going to
happen. I don't care what Adam Mus says,
then it's not going to happen. Let's get
to the moon first. Okay, let's get the
man on the moon first.
All right.
How can you explain India's position in
this chessboard of as far as
convergence?
Um,
India look again I don't know enough
about India to make predictions but I
will say that geopolitically India is in
a very bad position because it has a
large population. Uh, its political
system is very chaotic and it's very
resource constraint. It doesn't have
that much resources. So my prediction
for India would not be that optimistic.
Okay. Uh but eventually I want to go
visit India and discover for myself the
strengths of India. All right. Um
why do you think the people of Israel
have been constantly been expelled for
from 109 countries over the course of
history? Um the Israelites say it's
because everyone is envious of them. But
is that really true? If a kid is
expelled from 109 schools, are the
schools at fault or is the issue with
the kid? Okay, so this is actually a
question that a lot of people I think
are really interested in. Okay, so let
let me spend some time to explain what's
going on.
So the Israelites have the Bible and the
Bible commands them to be forever loyal
to God.
And over the course of history, most is
Israelites have been absorbed into
different communities like the
Christians and the Muslims. Okay? And a
lot convert themselves to
uh Greek Hellenism or they abandon uh
Judaism because
um they wanted to to join the elite.
So it's only been a minority, a very
small minority that has kept the Jewish
faith alive over the centuries. As you
imagine, these people are fanatical.
Okay? So imagine like just a small
community,
a small community.
And so their main problem is like how do
you endure?
Because their faith teaches them that
what matters is their faith in God.
They're the chosen people.
How can they endure as a people?
And so what happened in history is they
basically made a deal with the devil.
And what I mean by that is they made a
deal with local nobility to serve them
in exchange for being able to practice
their faith. Okay. The deal often goes
like this. Nobility will hire them as
subcontractors to manage their wealth.
The Jews are a diaspora. Okay? So what
they're really good at are trade and
finance.
Also throughout most of human history
nobility were not allowed to engage in
usery.
Okay. Why? Because usually led to often
to the destruction of society. Okay.
When you collect interest on debt, the
debt often multiplies to an extent that
no one can pay it off which often leads
to revolution.
But the problem is that userie was the
most profitable enterprise you can enga
you can engage in. Okay. So what they
really did which was very clever is say
let's let's get the Jews to go do it.
Okay. So the Jews are not allowed to own
property go to school but they're
allowed to engage in usery basically
finance.
Okay. So this is a deal that a lot of
Jewish communities made with European
nobility. As you can imagine, this is
going to be a problem because when times
are good, that's fine. But when times
are bad,
people are going to get angry. And who
do they blame? They blame the Jews,
right? Because it's not the nobility
that's collecting debt from you. It's
the Jews that are collecting debt from
you. The Jews think they are the chosen
people. So they set themselves apart
from you. They live in different in
their own communities. They practice
their own religion
and they think they're better than you.
Okay? And this is going to lead to a lot
of conflict. So again, um when times are
good, it's fine, but when times are bad,
the Jews always get blamed. And again,
history goes in cycles. And so when
whenever there's a bad time, the Jews
get expelled from a certain location and
they move elsewhere where they restart
again. But they don't care because for
them their mission is to endure to keep
the faith. Okay? And over the centuries
they've learned certain uh strategies
of how to endure.
Okay? And a lot of this is basically
um segregation
where they keep themselves separate from
other people and they basically think
that other people are dirty or whatever.
I'm not saying all Jews, but like they
have these traditions in place in order
to endure. And a lot of a lot of these
strategies tend to be very extreme.
Okay. And unfortunately, we're seeing
the same um same pattern emerge again in
today's world where anti-mitism is now a
very common thing around the western
world. Okay? Not just because of what
Israel is doing, but because of certain
cultural practices of the Jews. Okay?
That said, I have tremendous respect and
admiration for the Jewish people because
they are first and foremost an
intellectual people of people of the
book who have contributed many great
ideas to human history. Okay. All right.
All right.
Which branch of studies have a future in
our modern world? What would you study
if you were at the crossroads of life?
Okay. One advice I give to people is
ignore AI. Okay? If you want to become a
computer programmer, if you want to go
master AI to make to become a
billionaire, you're you're going to be
disappointed. If you really want to
prepare for the future,
read books. Okay?
Read the great books. But it doesn't
matter. You you don't have to read the
great books. Just read books. Because
the skill that you will need in the
future is the capacity to think
critically, think independently and
think deeply about the world. And by
reading books, you can start to engage
in inner monologue, sorry, an inner
dialogue of yourself. Okay? And that's
going to make you much more imaginative,
much more resilient in the future. So my
best advice is doesn't matter what you
study, but what what it does matter is
to read books. Okay?
All right.
Um could you help help Marina?
>> Uh I want proof to talk about what
advices he would give to his kids in the
situation. We are going to collapse and
the whole system is going to change.
What advice prof would give to his kids
how to prepare themselves for upcoming
situations and show how well you prepare
your kids for the new war word. I would
be delighted to hear professor's answers
to this questions.
>> Okay. So, every day I will just tell my
kids three things. Okay. And that's all
I have to do. Okay. First thing I will
say is like I will always love you.
No matter what happens, I will always
love you. No matter what you do, I will
always love you. If I die, I'll still
love you. Okay? Just know that. Wherever
you go, wherever whatever you do, I will
always love you and I'll always be with
you.
Okay, that's the first thing I I I tell
my kids. Second thing I I'll tell my
kids is I believe in you.
Meaning whatever you do will be good.
Just believe in yourself.
Okay.
All right. And the third thing I will
say is
just believe in yourself.
And if my kids understand these three
things, okay, that their parents always
love them, no matter no matter what they
do, that their parents believe in them
and their highest mission in life is to
believe in themselves, they'll be fine
no matter what. Okay? So, it's not
really about what university you should
go to. It's not really about how much
money you have. It's really about how
you perceive yourself, your place in the
world. And I want my kids to always
believe that no matter what they do, no
m where they go, their parents will
always love them. Um,
okay. C, can you can you help me read
out?
>> My question for the final exam is if an
AI civilian state is the end goal, why
is there such a negative feeling in the
general population for AI? What primary
social political political or game
theoretic factors drive this public
resistance? And how does it impact the
trajectory of AI deployment?
>> There's such negativity towards AI
because everyone knows what the purpose
of AI is. The purpose of AI is to make
you as a human being worthless,
redundant. We don't need it anymore
because we have robots. We have AI.
Okay? And human beings want to feel
they're part of something. Human human
beings want to feel uh valuable.
Human beings want to contribute to the
greater good. And AI is a system
designed to make you redundant. Okay.
Um,
>> you predicted US China grand bargain
where China absorbs Americans 39
trillion steps via stable coins. The
genian act to maintain the global USD uh
hallucination. However, you also taught
us that the US grand strategy is to
embargo Malaca and use 21 century
warfare economic strangulation to force
Beijing into submission. If China is
already a fragile hallucination of a
hallucination with collapsing consumer
confidence, will Americans regulations
accidentally trigger a total collapse of
the CCP? How can American extract whales
from the Chinese consumer if their own
choke point strategy destroy the Chinese
date from within?
>> Okay, so this is a really interesting
question. Okay, so so I'll make some
certain comments. The first comment I'll
make is that if you're if you're
hallucination, you don't know you're a
hallucination. Okay? You don't um so
objectively this may be true, but the
players don't know that it's true.
That's the first point I'll make. Second
point I'll make is that in a game your
objective is to win the game. Now by win
the game it may cause the game to
collapse but you don't care. The point
is to win the game and you'll use
whatever tools you have in order to win
the game. So it's possible that this US
China trade war will end up collapsing
both nations. But that's not the point.
The point is to win the game. Okay? The
point is not to survive the game. The
point is to win the game. And sometimes
winning the game means destroying
yourself, committing suicide basically.
Uh that's my second point. Um the third
point I will make is that
um
China and America
um they need to engage in the sort of
struggle in order to come to an
agreement. Okay. The reason why is that
there's lots of domestic interests that
they have to deal with. So for example,
if you're Donald Trump and you want a
grand bargain with China, there's been a
lot of people opposed to this because
they think that China is the great
threat and that any compromise of China
means selling out the American nation.
Okay? So you need to engage in certain
conflict and warfare in order to
dissipate or reduce domestic tension in
order to advance a deal. Okay? Does that
make sense? So, I I understand it's a
really dangerous game they're playing,
but welcome to geopolitics. This is the
way the world works. The people in
charge are psychopaths because in order
to win a game, you have to be a
psychopath.
Okay?
Think about who in this world is
respected. Well, Israel is respected.
Putin is respected. North Korea is
respected. Donald Trump is respected.
Why? because you're all crazy. These
people everyone agrees on is they could
if threatened enough they'll press a
button and blow the world. Okay? That's
what gets you respect in this world. The
crazy you are, the more legitimacy you
have. Okay? And that's why the games
you're playing are crazy. Will this lead
to the end of the world? Probably. Okay?
That's that's something I've been
teaching you guys for a long long time.
The people in charge are crazy. The game
they're playing is crazy. It's going to
lead to the end of the world.
All right, we're going to do three more
questions because we could be here
forever. Okay, but we'll do two more
questions and we'll end the examination.
Okay, can you read out?
>> Yeah. Explain that American needs an AI
civilian state operation strate uh
Stargate to manage domestic rebellion
against a coming national draft. You
also noted that the current global civil
war pits transactional capital against
an alliance of nationalist the church
and tag elites Trump Theo Musk. But if
the tech elites are using ma ma masonic
a code philosophy to build an ar
antichrist uh technate that strips human
free will want Trump's fierce uh
fiercely armed Christian national
nationalist based eventually realize
they are being enslaved by the exact
system they are fighting for when the
technate trigger a second American civil
war instead of preventing it.
>> Yeah, this is exactly right. Um,
so a civil war is going to happen and
there's many different factions there.
There's many different reasons why the
civil war happens, but one reason is
that there's going to be a lot of
resistance towards an AI civilian state.
This this exact exactly right. Okay. Um,
and
and there's really nothing anyone can do
right now to stop the civil war from
happening. Okay, keep on going.
In this recent lecture on Putting in
Beijing, you noted that Vladimir Putin
wants Russia to lead the multipolar
world, even if it means acting as a
junior partner to China. However, given
Russia's uh fierce historical emphasis
on absolute sover sovereignity and
itself imagined as the third Rome, can
pudding strategy genuinely survive a
long-term future where Russia is
economically subordinate to the Chinese
elite that fundamentally prefer the
American words policemen. What is
Russia's exist game if China choose a
divorce?
>> This is exactly correct. Okay. Um, the
Chinese don't trust the Russians because
the Russians are extremely
nationalistic, extreme. I mean, there's
Russian supremacy. Okay? Even though
Russia will pretend to be the junior
partner to China, the Russians believe
they're superior to China. And a lot has
to do with the third Rome escology that
uh they have. Um, so if there's a
divorce, can Russia survive
economically? And the answer is yes. It
doesn't need China. Okay? Okay, it just
needs to fight wars because if you think
about historically how a nation
developed wealth was by conquering other
nations. Okay, so what Russia is going
to do is move towards a total war
economy and completely focus on the
conquest of its neighbors especially uh
Ukraine but also the Baltic states as
well and then central Asia. Okay. So as
long as Russia is able to maintain its
internal cohesion and engage in all war
then Russia will be fine. All
right. Can you keep our reading? Yeah.
Hello, Miss Jing. My question is for the
final exam would be plainly simple.
According to the lecture material, I'm
inclined to believe Pudding has a grand
plan laid out. What would happen if
Putin would cease being Russian leader
for reason outside of his control? Would
there be individual or collective effort
to follow same ideology and continue his
plan?
>> This is a great question. Okay. Um, so
first of all, I think Putin is going to
live a lot longer than people believe. I
think he's going to be around for
another 20 years. Okay, that that that's
that's my instinct tells me. Uh, he's
going to live for another 20 years.
Okay, we also know what happens when a
great leader dies and it it's very
interesting what happens. Okay. So you
look at um Ghan
and Muhammad
when they die,
okay, there's a pattern that emerges
which is there's at first internal
friction. Okay, so the different
interests in Russia get together and
they start fighting over secession. Who
succeeds? And then they decide we cannot
possibly agree on secession. So what
we'll do is we will just go to war with
everyone. Okay, to just expand outwards,
okay, Russia will just expand outwards.
Okay, so you have this massive expansion
that might go on for 10 20 years when it
basically conquers everyone around them
because no one's no one is as
militaristic as they are. But then what
happens and this is really interesting
is just exhaustion
where they either lose or they win but
everyone's exhausted and then they they
just decay imperily. Okay. So I I myself
don't see Russia as having a great
future but this is a pattern that merges
if you look at history you know when a
great leader dies there's internal
friction internal chaos which leads to
military expansion overseas. in order to
reduce this internal friction and then
eventually
the empire exhausts itself because it's
fighting too many wars at once. Okay.
And that's a fate I see for Russia.
Okay, guys. Well, we've been all here
for almost two hours. We can go on for
another two hours, but I don't want to
because I'm exhausted. Uh yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Vincent, I
>> I think I have a final question. Like I
I also wonder like why are we born in
like by ourselves? Like why am I Asian?
Why am I Chinese? Why am I not a white
guy or why I'm not a like people uh I'm
not a person in another place of the
world? Like why are we ourselves? Is
this connect to Monad?
>> Yes. Okay. So why are you here? Okay.
And so the theory is this. Okay. Okay,
there are lots of reasons why but but
but but let let me give you a basic
theory. Okay, theory is that you come to
earth as a soul
and your soul has a purpose
and the purpose is always to
um enlighten yourself.
Enlightenment basically. All right. So
the so you basically up there decide on
a purpose. Your purpose could be like I
want to experience being rich or I want
to experience uh being in love. Okay,
you always have a defining purpose that
becomes the core of who you are. And so
once you have this purpose then you are
assigned to a place in this world that
allows you to achieve your purpose.
Okay? So you are who you are for a
purpose and this purpose is good. What
is good is for you to try to achieve
your purpose. Unfortunately what happens
in our world is that because of schools
because of parents because of society
you're blocked from knowing your purpose
from truly pursuing your purpose. That's
part of the purpose as well because for
you to truly fulfill your purpose you
need to overcome a lot of challenges and
obstacles. Okay.
And once you achieve your purpose, then
you understand
yourself a lot better. Okay? Then you go
back and you're like, "Okay, now I want
a new purpose."
But maybe you don't achieve this
purpose. In which case, well, you do it
again. Okay? All right. And this this is
this is the idea of samsara
in vidic um escology. Okay. So that's
one explanation. There are other
explanations. Okay. But the thing to
remember is that you came here for a
purpose. You may not remember what your
purpose is, but you can feel what your
purpose is. And so what you should
always do is trust your intuition
because that's what that's what's going
to lead you to your purpose. You're in
this you're here in this classroom as
part of your purpose. I'm here teaching
you as part of my purpose. Okay? And
that's a structure of the universe. That
does that make sense?
>> Okay, guys. All right. So, thank you.
Uh, enjoy the rest of your life.