Last semester we looked at secret
societies and esquetology, secret
history. This semester we're doing game
theory. In this class I want to connect
the two and show you how the world
works. Okay. So, first thing I want to
do is go over some popular conspiracy
theories about how the world works. And
um there are different variations. So
I'll just go over a very simplified
clear version. Okay? And remember if
there's anything you don't understand
ask a question and make sure you are
clear. Okay. So we start with the nice
templars.
Nice templars
is probably the most most successful
secret society in the world. It was
founded in the year uh 1118
as part of the crusades. So there were
Christian pilgrims who went to
Jerusalem. Along the way they would get
robbed. So Night Templars was a
volunteer organization
designated by the Vatican to protect
these pilgrims. Over time, what happened
was that the nice templars became a bank
as well where um you could deposit your
gold
with the dice templars and they would
give you a receipt and when you went to
um Jerusalem they would give you the
gold back. Okay? So they became a bank
and as over time they became an
extremely powerful organization because
they con they were convergence of
politics, military, religion and finance
and that's why in 1314
the Catholic Church and the king of
France
made them illegal. Okay. They burned
their leader Jack de mole at the stake
and accused him of blasphemy for
worshiping a false god named Baffomet.
So the Knights Templars were in
Jerusalem and Jerusalem was convergence
of all religions. So they started to
become curious about different religions
and started to engage in hermetic
philosophy, neoplatinism, gnostic
philosophy which were all considered her
heretitical uh by the Catholic Church.
Okay. So this was a ban organization.
Um and then what happened was that
people speculate that rather than
disappear the nice templars we emerge as
the Scottish right Freemasons
and why they're important is that they
would go on to
um create the position
the posformation
as well as the revolution
They conspired to create the American
revolution
as well as the French Revolution.
Basically they create modernity itself.
They came to control England and create
the bank of England
which created the mo the modern
financial system of
today. Then they went on to create World
War I, which led to World War II, and
now they're conspiring to create World
War II, which would then usher in the a
new world government. Okay, a one world
government based in Jerusalem
and it will be controlled by an AI
civilian state. And that's why we're
seeing
uh data centers built being built all
around the world. Okay. Um, people also
speculate that the night templars
were able to continue basically
how to um communicate with demons. Okay.
Interdimensional demons
or Lucifer.
And to communicate with demons, you have
to make contracts with them through
ritual sacrifice.
And they can and then what they do is
they can take possession of you
and offer you secrets. for example,
um how to live forever or how to be
young forever or how to build great
technology. Okay, they can also tell you
how to like build nuclear weapons. And
so people speculate that the entire
point of the one world government and
the Irish civilian state is to bring
into our world these interdimensional
beings so that the elite can live
forever so they can combine with the
elite. There are also people who
speculate that the nice templars go all
the way back to Rome and the 13 families
which then became part of Venice.
Okay. So there are many different
um permutations
to this conspiracy theory about how the
world works. Now, there are lots and
lots of issues with this conspiracy
theory about how the world works. Okay,
first of all, there's actually no
evidence
that any of this is true.
We don't know if demons actually exist.
There's there's actually no evidence
that demons exist. There's no evidence
that this is a giant conspiracy that
stretch back you know a thousand years.
Okay. Second thing is
the elite
don't know that this is true. Okay. The
people believe this is true but if you
actually go talk to people who have real
power they think this is complete and
utter nonsense. Okay. And the third
thing about this is that it's
anti-historical,
meaning that it is a very simplified
version of how things work. It doesn't
take into into account um other factors
as well. Also,
um what we learn in this class is game
theory and this also anti-game theory
because one thing that you learn in this
class is that when people are in power,
they become arrogant, hubris, they
become stupid. So it's very common for
things for powerful people to rise and
then have a particular fall. Okay,
that's just the iron law of history. So
for these reasons,
we know this theory is not true.
At the same time,
there are certain things about this
theory that are very compelling. Okay,
so let's go over some of them. Well, the
first thing about this theory that's
compelling is that it is very intuitive.
What intuitive just means is that if I
tell it to someone, it makes sense to
that person. It makes a lot more sense
than the history that we're taught in
school. That's kind of strange, right?
None none of this is correct, but it's
intuitive. Second of all, second of all
is that it's explanatory
and that it help even though this is not
factual, it does help us understand how
the world works. It's a very clear
explanation. The third thing that is the
most paradoxical is that it is
predictive.
Meaning
it helps us
predict how things will turn out in the
future. And so even though the elite
think this is all insane and there's no
way they're plotting to create World War
II, there's absolutely no way that
they're trying to create an a civilian
state and create a one world government.
Chances are these things will happen.
Okay, so this creates a huge paradox.
How is it that this is not factual?
Okay, this is not at all factual but it
is truthful
meaning it gives us tremendous insight
into how the world works. All right, so
this is a paradox. This is all nonsense
but it helps us predict the future.
So it's truthful. So what I'm going to
do now is try to explain to you how the
system really works. Okay. So the main
thing you you you need to understand is
that this is metaphorical
metaphorical
it is not literal
okay so what I'm going to try try to do
now is try to factually explain to you
why how the world works okay and what
you will see is that this is a
metaphorical explanation for how the
world works it's a story that people can
understand and help them appreciate the
nuance of this world. But now I'm going
to tell you how it works literally.
Okay. All right. So the first thing I'm
going to explain to you
is that there are people in this world,
they're mystics, they're cultists,
and they spend all their time trying to
figure out how the universe works. Okay?
They're trying to uncover the secrets of
the universe. And there are different
secrets, right? There's astrology.
Okay. The moving of stars can determine
people's fate. Okay? The idea of
astrology. Then you have uh alchemy.
How to turn nothing into gold. How to
turn lead into gold. Then you have um
estology. Estology is how the world will
end. What what's the point of the
universe? When will God come to the
earth? Okay, you have sacred geometry.
Think of sacred geometry as like
particle physics which is the underlying
essence of the universe. Okay. So, um a
cultist and these could be poets,
philosophers,
uh mystics, they spend all their time
thinking about what is the fundamental
truth of the universe. And then there
are people okay who seek
power,
wealth
and fame.
All right?
And what and what they recognize is that
if they really want to seek power,
wealth and fame, they need to know these
secrets as well. So what happens is that
they form secret societies
in order to access
these secrets of astrology, alchemy,
esquetology and secret geometry and then
implement in the world in order to
create power, wealth and influence for
themselves. Okay, does that make sense?
The thing to understand is that there
are many different oultist, many
different secret societies and they're
all and this all creates very different
combinations. Okay. But they're all
trying to do the same thing which is
trying to achieve an esquetology.
All right. Then the third element is
that you need certain individuals in
order to propel society forward in order
to achieve the esquetology of the secret
societies. Okay. These people are like
agents
that the secret societies sponsor. And
historically these people included
Julius Caesar.
Napoleon,
Hitler,
Stalin.
Today we have Trump and Putin.
Okay. All right. So these are agents or
maybe um meic figures or even scapegoats
that societies promote in order to push
forward a particular agenda. All right.
And remember that it looks simple but
it's not because there are different
occultists with different ideas and then
there are different societies who are
competing against each other and they're
pro promoting different individuals in
order to achieve their particular
vision. All right. What drives these
individuals like Julius Caesar,
Napoleon, Hitler, Stalin, Trump and
Putin is that they themselves believe
that that they're the real sons of God.
Okay? They're the true messiah who is
going to lead the world world forward
and the secret societies they call this
are just useful idiots. Okay. So this is
one framework for understanding the
movement of history.
All right. So now I'm going to go much
more specific. Okay. All right. So
there's another way to frame this which
is to say that in the world in society
there are different groupings. Okay.
So, think of politics,
think of finance,
science,
religion,
military.
Okay. Now, the thing about each of these
different fields or disciplines is that
you have a diversity, a range of
behavior
with different belief systems. Okay.
So
each of these different disciplines have
their own diverse
fields of belief.
At a particular point there's
convergence
a convergence
amongst these different fields. Okay.
What makes them converge is the fact
that in each field you have certain
individuals an extreme minority who seek
power,
order and control.
Okay. So again in each field you're
going to have a range
and on one extreme version are those who
hate power but on the other extreme
version are those who love power. Okay.
And those and people who love power,
order, and control of all these
different fields are going to come
together and they're going to work
together in order to achieve power,
order, and control. And we call these
people secret societies,
okay? Because they're bounded by a
similar interest. Now what's really
interesting is that over time as study
becomes much more larger these different
fields expand in size creating greater
diversity
and what happens is that this
convergence becomes much stronger in
society. The reason why is that these
different fields are not able to
coordinate together but the people
inside this convergence are able to
coordinate together which gives them a
huge advantage in society.
Okay, which means that they're able to
achieve power, order and control much uh
more
uh likely. Okay.
So what's interesting is that as society
declines,
okay, as society declines because it's
become much more bureaucratic, much too
large, much too corrupt, these societies
in fact become much more powerful over
time because they're able to stay much
more cohesive.
Okay. Now
um once these secret societies are
formed what you'll discover is that
there are huge
number of these different secret
societies okay and a different
individual can join different societies
and these secret societies can come from
the fact that they went to a certain
school or they grew up in a certain
religion or their families okay there
different combinations and these secret
societies are in combination are in
competition with each other And so the
what the criteria for the competition
are three things. Okay. Legitimacy,
authority,
and unity.
Cohesion.
Okay. Why are you more legitimate than
other secret societies? Why do you have
more authority, expertise than other
secret societies? Why are you much more
unified than other secret societies?
Okay. To solve this problem, what the
secret societies will do is they will go
back in time and re-imagine history
to show that they are connected
with the entirety of history. Okay. So
what they'll say is okay well we got
start not today in our school but
because we're connected to the
Freemasons who are then connected to the
nice templars. Okay. So they go back and
create a cosmology
that explains the origins and obviously
the further you go back in time the more
legitimate
the more authorative you are. Does that
make sense? All right. So they're going
to go back and they're going to create
their own history. And that's why
people think that they
stretch all the way back to Rome.
Okay. Or maybe Babylon.
And what allows for people to believe
that this is continuous is the fact that
the elites in each particular time
behave the same way, which is they're
all seeking power, order, and control.
And those who win out have three
particular characteristics. Okay. First
of all, these are people who are
addicted
to power. They obsess about it. They're
obsessive about it. They will do
everything possible in order to obtain
more power. And
power is expansive and all consuming.
Okay? Meaning they cannot stop but
try to obtain more power. They behave a
certain way that looks as though they
are possessed by demons.
Okay? And in fact, they do worship
demons. And the reason why is they think
they worship all gods in a search for
reason.
Okay? They are looking for the greatest
secrets of the universe. So they are
open-minded. They are looking for all
possibilities. They'll worship Lucifer.
But they also worship Baffomet. They
they worship Osiris. They worship Isis.
Okay. So now we understand how the world
works literally throughout history. The
elites have behaved the same way. Okay.
And even even though
um these elites are fighting with each
other, they are pu they are moving
forward an agenda that consolidates
power onto the hands of a few people
which gives the impression that this is
all a continuous agenda
controlled by a few people. Okay, does
it all make sense guys? All right. So
remember this is the
um metaphorical understanding of how the
world works. A world controlled by a
particular secret society, the Knights
Templars who became the Freemasons who
then became the Illuminati who control
the world today. And they're trying to
usher in a one world government u an air
surveillance state and summon demons
into this world in order to live
forever. Okay, so this is a grand
conspiracy. But again, it doesn't it
doesn't um explain why we have no
evidence why the elite don't think
they're part of this and why this is
antihistorical. Okay, but once we we
transform this into a literal
explanation and this is a literal
explanation, this explains everything.
Okay, they they don't think this is
conspiracy because they're too busy
fighting each other. They're not at the
grand scheme of things. Whereas the
people who are not involved in this game
can look at the move in history and have
can come to an intuitive understanding
of how this thing moves and it's moving
towards more control, more order and
more power.
Okay. And this helps helps us explain
why the system persists even though the
elites will rise and they will fall
because these elites are already in
competition with with each other. So
what's happening is that certain elites
are replacing other elites but they all
have the same agenda which is more
power, more order, more control. Okay?
Doesn't make sense guys. Okay? And
that's why we actually read the text
secret societies, all these thinkers,
they look as though they are building on
top of each other even though they
probably have not read and read each
other. Okay. People who seek power
are very much alike. They're different
from you and me in that they are
probably psychopaths. Okay? All they
care about is power. And so powerful
people come together in order to create
more power for themselves. Okay? Does it
make sense guys? Okay. So now what we're
going to do is we're going to go over
the evidence. Okay. So what what I want
to first do is discuss this man. His
name is Albert Pike
and he was born in year 1809 1891. And
why he's important is that he's
considered the grand architect of
American Freemasonry.
Why American Freemasonry is important is
that it's the people who control the
American government. Onethird of
American presidents were Freemasons.
Okay? And these people today control the
American military, the national security
apparatus, the CIA, the FBI. All right?
They don't call the Freemasons, but they
go back to the Freemasons. So they share
the similar ideas of the Freemasons. So
um Albert Pike is was one of the major
leaders of the American Freemasons and
he's considered the great architect
meaning that he built the system and the
ideas that underpin modern day American
Freemasonry today. His most important
work is called morals and dogma and it's
basically the standard textbook of
American Freemasonry. Okay. So, we're
going to look at a few passages from
morals and dogma. And I know they're a
bit long, but it's very important for us
to understand how they think. Okay. So,
um I'm going to read the first part and
then Alan, if you can help me read this
part. Okay. So, I I'll read the first
part.
The wealth ashlar. Okay. This is the
ashar guys, which is a stone is a people
as a mass rude and unorganized. The
society is diverse. It's chaotic. And we
the Freemasons our objective in life is
to create order out of chaos.
The perfect ashar okay or typical stone
symbol of perfection is the state. The
purpose of government is to create order
out of chaos to perfect
humanity. The rulers deriving the powers
from the consent of the govern. The
constitution and law speaking the will
of the people. The government
harmonious, symmetrical, efficient, its
powers properly distributed and totally
adjusted in equilibrium. Okay? So, think
of society as a forest. No, a forest is
chaotic. There are diseases in a forest.
It could burn down. What we really want
to do is create a temple of stone that
is perfect, that is eternal, that is
divine. Okay? We want to burn down the
forest and build a temple with our bare
hands. I know God uh was the one who
created the forest but God willed us to
perfect his work.
If we delate a cube on a on a plane
surface, okay, we have visible three
faces and nine external lines drawn
between seven points. The complete cube
has three more faces making six. Three
more lines making 12 and one more point
making eight. As the number 12 includes
the secret numbers 3 5 7 and 3 * 3 or 9
is produced by adding the secret number
3 to 9 while its own two figures one to
the unit of or monad and duad added
together make the same secret number
three. It was called the perfect number
and the cube became a symbol of
perfection. Okay. So this is God. What
we're trying to do is we're trying to
create God on earth. And how we know
it's God because it is perfection
itself. How do we know how do we know
it's perfection? because of mathematics.
Geometry. Okay, geometry is a language
of God. Once you understand geometry,
you understand how God thinks. So the
cube is perfect. So we want to turn
society into a cube. In fact, we want to
turn everyone into a cube. And how do we
do so? Artificial intelligence, guys.
Okay. Artificial intelligence. Okay. All
right. So again
uh the so the idea is we we want to read
them in order to understand the essence
of their thinking. Okay. So let's uh now
move on. Okay. Uh can you read um Alan?
Nevertheless, masonry which is morality
and philosophy must not cease to do its
duty. We never know at what moment
success awaits our efforts. Generally
when most unexpected nor with what
expect or efforts are or are not to be
attended succeed or fail masonry must
not bow to arrow or succumb under
discouragement. There was at Rome a few
Carthaginian soldiers taken prisoners
who refused to bow to flaminus and had
little of Hannibal's mag uh magnimity.
Mason should possess an equal greatness
of soul. Masonry should be an energy
finding its aim and effect in the
emlarations of mankind. So so crates so
crates should enter into an atom and
produce marcus aras.
>> In other words, bring forth from the man
of enjoyment, the man of wisdom.
Messaring should not be a mere
watchtowwer built upon mystery from
which to gaze at ease upon the world
with no other result than to be a
convenience for the curious to hold the
full cup of thought to the thirsty lips
of men to give all the true ideas of
diety to harmonize con uh conscience and
science are the province of philosophy.
Morality is faced in full bloom.
Contemplation should lead to action and
the absolute be practical. The ideal be
made air and food and drink to the human
mind. Wisdom is a sacred communion
communion. It is only on that condition
that it ceased to be a st a stereial
love of science and becomes the one and
supreme method by which to unite
humanity and arose it to concerted
action. Then philosophy become religion.
>> Okay. So, Freemasonry is the ultimate
religion. Why? Because it encompasses
all previous religions including uh
Egyptian uh hermitism. Okay. Including
the Greek mystery
cults of Pythagoras
uh including the Cabala. Okay. So it has
scor it has scouted the entire
history and found the best ideas of
humanity and put them together to create
Freemasonry. And the ultimate goal is
for each of us to become a stone stoic
unrelenting
perfect faith. And then if we build if
we put all human together and we're all
stones then we can we can create the
perfect temple of God. Okay? We can
create God on earth. So imagine a
pyramid. We're all stone in the pyramid.
And we all have responsibility to become
that stone through faith, through
practice, through reflection. Okay? So
Socrates should enter into Adam and
produce Marcus Aurelius. So the height
of humanity is reflection and reason
where we surrender our emotions to
geometry. Okay. All right. Let's keep on
going.
All right. So, does it all make sense so
far? All right. Let's keep on going. All
right. Can you uh read uh Alan? Man own
it to himself to be free. He own it to
his country to seek to give her freedom
or maintain her in that possession. It
made and uh serpatients the
enemies of the human race. It created a
general outli
of despos and desperatisms
temporary and spiritual. The sphere of
duty was immensively immensely enlarged.
Uh patriotism had henceforth a new and
vider meaning. Free government, free
thought, free conscience, free speech.
All these came to be inalienable rights
which those who had parted with them or
being robbed of them who or or whose
ancestors had lost them had the right
sum summary summarily to retake.
Unfortunately, as truth always become
perverted into falsehoods and our
falsehoods when misapplied, this truth
become the gospel of anarchy. soon after
it was first preached. Masonry early
comprehended this truth and recognized
its own enlarged duties. Its symbols
then came to have a vital meaning, but
it also assumed the must of stonemasonry
and borrow its working tools and so was
supplied with new and apt symbols. It
aided in bringing about the French
revolution, disappeared with the uh
>> juronist.
>> Gironist was born against with the
restoration of order and sustained
Napoleon because though emperor he
acknowledged the right of the people to
select its rules and was at the head of
nation refusing to receive back its old
kings.
>> Okay. Stop. Okay. All right. Okay.
Great. Okay. So what he's doing, what
Albert Pike is doing is trying to
explain the esquetology of Freemasonry.
Okay, the esquetology is this. We want
to create an empire of reason. Okay,
what what he calls a holy empire of
reason
and for that we must
create revolutions around the world.
Okay. And what he's doing is he's he's
trying to say that this is a crusade and
we go back to the time of the Knights
Templars
and we were the ones who brought about
the French Revolution and credit
Napoleon in order to achieve this holy
reason of empire. Okay. So what he's
doing is he's going back into history
and rewriting history to show that the
Freemasons were the end point of
history. the natural evolution of the
Knights Templars. Also, what he's trying
to tell tell people is that we do things
in secret because before we were the
Knights Templars, the French and the and
the Catholic Church hunted us down. So,
we had to disguise ourselves under
stonemasonry. Okay? So that's why we
took the guides of the Freemasons
because the Freemasons were just a
workers guild who built temples
and we took their shape in order to
protect ourselves and then to try to
promote our mission in secret.
Okay. All right. So this is why people
believe that the Freemasons come from
nice templars. What this is really doing
is it's trying to bring legitimacy and
authority to the Freemasons by
reimagining history as a movement
towards Freemasonry. It doesn't make
sense, guys. Okay. So, he talks about
how the Freemasons not only create the
French Revolution, they but they brought
about Napoleon
in order to try to create um a one world
government. Okay? And that failed. But
if Napoleon failed, don't worry, America
will succeed. Uh this is another passage
we will not read but he talks about how
um the Freemasons actually created
conditions for the French revolution and
conspired for generations for decades in
order to avenge the death of their lost
leader Jacqu deto in 1314. Okay. So the
Freemasons think centuries ahead and
they plan decades in advance and again
this is all to create legitimacy and
authority for their movement. This is a
rewriting of history. It is none of this
is true. Okay. All right. Let's
continue. All right. Can you read um
Alan?
The degree of rose is devoted to and
symbolize the final triumphs of tr truth
over falsehood or of liberty over
slavery of light over darkness or life
over death and of good over evil. The
great truth it includates is that
nonwithstanding the existence of evil,
God is infinitely wise, just and good.
And though the fears of of the world
precede by no rule of right and wrong
known to us in the narrowest of our
views, yet all is right. For it is a
work of God. And all evils, all
miseries, all misfortunes are but as
drops in the vast current that is
weeping on world guided by him to a
great and magnificent result. That at
the appointed time he will redeem and
regenerate the world and the principle
the power and existence of evil will
then seize. And this will be brought
about by such means and his instruments
as he chooses to employ, whether by the
merits of a redeemer that has already
appeared or a messiah that is yet waited
for by an incarnation of himself or by
an inspired prophet. It does not belong
to us as masons to decide. Let each
judge and believes for himself in the
meantime we labor to hasten the coming
of that day.
>> Okay. The degree of the roles. Okay. The
idea here is that the Freemasons and
Night Templers were so successful
because they were secret society. But
first and foremost, they were a company.
They were a hierarchy.
Okay? So they were like a triangle. And
to climb the hierarchy, you have to
constantly reinvent yourself. You have
to adopt new ideas. And based on your
performance, based on your ideology,
they will promote you to a new rank.
Okay? So in Scottish white Freemasonry,
there are 33 ranks. and you just climb
higher and higher and each each time you
you climb the rank they will teach you a
new way of understanding the world and
based on your fluidity based on your
mental flexi flexibility you'll climb
higher and higher. Okay, so they're
trying they're trying to train you into
a mastery of knowledge. Okay, and that's
why they're so successful. All right,
can you can you can can you read um
Alan? Let us in order to understand this
old thought first follow the soul in its
decent. sphere or heaven of the fixed
stars was that holy region and those uh
>> Elysian fields that were that native
doile of souls and the place to which
they recended when they had recovered
their primit primitive purity and
simplicity from that luminous region
that the soul sat forth when it joined a
journal toward the body a destination
which it did not reach until it had
undergone three degrad degradations the
design uh designated by the name of that
>> okay stop. Okay. All right. So this
passage just shows you um that the
Freemasons are trying to incorporate all
philosophies including the cabala sorry
the um cabala
the uh narcissism
and hermetic philosophy. Okay. And as a
result they try to be complete. Okay. So
the main advantage is in their
completeness. Meaning they have an
explanation for everything. So what
they're trying to tell us is that we are
first and foremost souls that came from
heaven. And why do we come to heaven? To
experience the world and we become
trapped in our bodies because our bodies
want to experience sensual pleasures but
our souls want to only experience
spiritual pleasures. So the world is a
spiritual war in ourselves between our
material selves which want sex, food and
money and our spiritual selves that seek
connection
with reason. Okay? And the way to defeat
ourselves is through geometry by turning
ourselves into a sacred cube that
connects back to the divine. All right.
Okay. Can you can you read? Um yeah Alan
>> question what is to us the chief symbol
of man's ultimate redemption and
regeneration? Answer the fraternal
super
>> supper of supper of bread which
nourished and of wine which refreshed
and ex uh
>> accelerates
>> accelerates symbol uh symbol uh
symbolical of the time which is to come
when all mankind shall be one great
harmonious brotherhood and teaching us
these great lessons that as matter
changes ever but no single odd atom is
un
>> annalated Not yet.
>> Okay. All right. Stop. Okay. All right.
So, this is the idea of fraternity. And
how do you create a fraternity? Well,
the simple way is to engage in a supper
together. Okay. Just like Jesus in the
last supper and to share communion.
Okay. Is that a communion
so that you all feel connected with each
other. But over time, because there are
certain elements of the Freemasons, nice
Templars who want power, order and
control, they engage in more extreme
practices. And so what they will do
literally is they will eat the dead
corpse of an old Freemason in order to
connect themselves to each other as well
as to their past. Okay? They believe
that the Freemasons if through
tremendous spiritual sacrifice are able
to um congregate inhabit spiritual
energy that still resides in the body.
So they will dig up the corpse and then
eat that corpse in a communion in a in a
dinner. Okay.
All right. So again, the thing about
civil societies is that those who are
the most extreme, those who are most
fanatical
will win out in the end. Okay.
All right. So can you continue? Um yeah.
You have heard more than one definition
of Freemasonry. The truest and the most
significant you have yet to hear it is
taught to the entered apprentice, the
fellow craft and the master. And it is
taught in every degree through which you
have advanced to. It is. It is a
definition of what Freemasonry is, of
what its purposes and its very essence
and spirit are. And it has for every one
of us the forces and uh sens sensit
sensity of a divine law and impose on
every one of us a solemn obligations. It
is symbolized and taught to the
apprentice as well as to you by the
compass and the square upon which as
well as upon the book of your religion
and the book of law of the Scottish
Freemasonry. You have taken so many
obligations as a knight you have been
taught by the swords the symbols of
honor and duty on which you have taken
your vows vows. It was taught you by the
balance the symbol of all equilibrium
and by the cross the symbol of
devoteness and self-sacrifice and all
that these teach and contain is taught
and contain for enter apprentice knight
and prince alike by the compass and the
square. For the apprentice the points of
the compass are beneath the square. For
the followcraft fellowcraft one is above
and one beneath. For the masters, both
are dominant and have rule, control and
umpire over the symbol of the early and
the material. Freemasonry is the
subjugations of the human that is in
men, by the divine, the conquest of the
uh appetities and passions by the moral
sense and reason. A continual effort,
struggle and welfare of the spiritual
against the material and sensual. That
victory when it has been achieved and
sec uh secured and the con conqueror may
rest upon his shield and where the
well-earned lrow is the true only
empire.
>> Okay, the true holy empire of reason.
Okay, so let me explain to you the
symbol symbolism of freemasonry. This is
a compass. Okay, what does the compass
do? Compass sets the boundaries. It
rules, right? This is a square. Okay,
the square limits. Okay. So the idea is
that when you first join Freemasonry,
you have to focus on the square which is
your own spiritual alchemy. Okay. To
discipline yourself to focus yourself to
learn how to be ruled. Okay. By the
compass. Then you reach a point where
you must rule yourself. So you must
teach others how to be disciplined, how
to be focused. And then you reach a
point when you combine the square and
the compass which is you lead the
Freemasons to control the whole world to
create the holy empire of reason. All
right. So according to different ranks
you see the symbol in a different way.
All right. The the G what does the G
stand for? Well there are three
different interpretations. Okay. there.
It stands for uh geometry of course
because of the square and the and the
compass. It stands for god or narcissism
or grand architect. Okay. So what the
free racist believe is that there is a
god but he created this world for us to
perfect by ourselves. Then god left us.
So he's the architect but that means
that we have a responsibility to
renovate
and perfect the world that we live in.
Okay. And but there's also um people
believe that the G stands for the
generative principle.
Okay. So
there's male and there's female. The the
female is a productive principle, the
thing that gives birth. The male is a
generative principle, the thing that uh
energizes the female. Okay. So what's
interesting is that if you put all this
together, you put uh generative
principle generate plus geometry, what
you get is God. Okay? And what does
generative and geometry equal? It equals
AI,
artificial intelligence. So at the very
beginning of Freemasonry, there was an
impetus, a desire among them to create
to prove that they could be God by
creating life itself. All right? Right?
In the beginning they call this golems
but now if you think about it that's why
they want to create AI
to prove that they can be god
themselves. Once you once you create AI
then you perfect the world. Okay. So
that is Freemasonry and you can see how
it gives rise now to artificial
intelligence. I'm not saying that they
plan for artificial intelligence. What
I'm saying is that the people in charge
now of art artificial intelligence
including people like Sen Altman, Peter
Theo, Larry Ellison, Ellen Musk, they
can they can go they can now go back to
to this tradition and um basically
appropriate this tradition in order to
justify
their AI civilian state. All right.
Okay. So now let's move on. This is
Zedith Bzinski
and he was national security advisor to
Jimmy Carter. Okay. Who who was
president of the United States and he's
a founder of something called the
trilateral commission
which basically tries to implement
American grand strategy
in the world
and uh this was fun this was funded by
David Rockefeller who who obviously was
one of the wealthiest most powerful
Americans to ever live. So this is a
very powerful individual and we're going
to read certain um writings from his
book between two ages
and when we read it you'll see how
similar it is to Albert Pike. Now I
don't think that Zebrainski read Albert
Pike
and he he he probably himself is he he
himself is probably not a Freemason
but again you don't have to read Albert
Pike. You don't have to be a Freemason
to think like them. These are these are
all people obsessed with power, control,
and order. And they're going to look for
elements of different religions in order
to justify their
um pursuit of power, order, and control.
Okay. So, this is from the book between
two ages.
Uh can you read um
>> Alan? the emergence of a large dominant
party alongside the more narrowly
focuses and more intensively doctrinal
uh group groupings on the right and the
left could accelerate the trend towards
such technological uh managerialism.
Such a large dominant party would
combine American society's quest for
stability with its historical affinity
for innovation. Relying on scientific
growth to produce the means for dealing
with socials. It would tap the nation's
intellectual talent for broad target
planning and exploit the existence of
doctrinal groups by using them as social
barometers and as sources of novel
ideas. persisting social crisis, the
emergence of a charismatic personality
and exploitations of mass media to
obtain public confidence would be the
stepping stones in the peacemail
transformations of United States into a
highly controlled society. In different
ways, both the doctrinal doctrinarian
and the conservative might find the
temptations inherent in the new ta
techniques of social control too
difficult to resist. The inclinations of
the doctrinal left to legitimize means
by ants could lead them to justified
more social control on the ground that
it serves progress. The conserv
conservatives uh preoccupied with public
order and fascinated by modem gra uh gat
ga gadry would be tempted to use a new
tech technique as a response to un
unrest since they would fail to
recognize that social control is not the
only way to deal with rapid social
change.
>> So this year written in the this book is
written about 1970s okay this is like 40
50 years ago. What's amazing about this
paragraph is that it perfectly describes
America today. This is not just a
prophecy. It's almost like a plan. Okay?
So his so so let me explain what what
he's saying. He's saying that democracy
is problematic. Why? Because it always
leads to polarization. You're going to
always going to have different factions
with this within this democracy who are
going to fight each other. Eventually,
you're going to reach a point where they
actually refuse to get along. That's
what's happening in America today
between the left and the right, between
the Democrats and Republicans. Okay? And
he's saying this is going to create a
series of crisis, uh, social crisis.
And the solution he believes is a
technocracy.
All right? So basically a bureaucracy in
Washington DC run by engineers who use
artificial intelligence, who use data
and statistics in order to better govern
society and who are better able to use
this social polarization in order to
better manage society. Okay. And and
this is a really really interesting
sentence. Persisting social crisis.
Okay. So what's happening in America
right now is the divide between the left
and right. The emergence of a
charismatic personality. Who's that
person? Charismatic personality. Donald
Trump, guys.
And the exploitation of mass media.
Okay. So just basically social media in
order to indoctrinate and brainwash you
to obtain public confidence would be the
stepping stones in the peace
transformation of the United States into
a highly controlled society, a AI
surveillance state.
So what he's saying is this
eventually you reach a point where the
divide will be so vast the economy will
be in such trouble
um the people will be so angry that they
will demand a Napoleon or Julius Caesar
to arise to lead them into a
dictatorship and this could be a good
thing because this could create a
technocracy which would be better able
to govern society. Okay. All right. So,
this is a continuation of the Freemason
project of trying to create order out of
chaos.
All right. And what he's saying is this.
It will be the conservatives, the
Republicans who will win out in the
civil war because they're the ones who
are occ preoccupied with public order
and gadgetry. Okay? They are the ones
who who will want the AI civilian state.
Okay? Once you have the AI state, you
now have the technocracy
and the world will be perfect.
All right? Does it make sense you guys?
What he's saying here? This is an
amazing paragraph written 40, 50 years
ago. So, I'm not saying he's a
Freemason. I'm not saying he's part of
society, but he sure thinks like a
Freemason.
All right. Let's continue.
>> All right. Can you can you
>> Yeah.
>> It was a frontier tradition that stirred
the American im imagination, created a
society of movement and growth and gave
American its integrative meath.
Scientific explorations including
exploration of space has become the
functional equivalent of American
frontier tradition and such endeavor is
immediately relevant to the educational
and scientific attainment of the
country.
>> Okay. Stop. Okay. Can you just read the
the last paragraph? To many Americans
>> to many Americans contemporary li
liberalism offers neither principles nor
progress. The crisis of American
liberalism is hence both a crisis of
confidence and of historical relevance.
>> Okay. So what he's saying here is that
democracy was a historical accident. It
was good for America before but in the
future liberalism will probably a bad
thing. Okay. Because it's too divisive.
Okay. So, so what's the solution then?
Well, you're
this is this the solution.
Can you read please?
>> Yeah.
>> That is why
>> Can you read slower, please, Alan? Okay.
You don't have to rush. Yeah. Okay. Just
just read slower. Keep on going.
>> That is why Marxism represents a further
virtual and creative stage in the
mattering of man's universal vision.
Maxism is simultaneously a victory of
the external active man over the inner
passive man and a victory of reason over
belief. It stretches stresses man's
capacity to shape his material destiny
fit.
>> Okay. Stop. Okay. All right. So this is
an amazing passage. Okay. This is a guy
who is national security adviser to
Jimmy Carter at this time. This is the
height of the cold war. America is
fighting a war with the Soviet Union and
the National Security Advisor of the
United States
to Jimmy Carter says that democracy is
bad. Marxism is good.
Okay,
Marxism is good. Why? Because it is the
end point of history.
The French Revolution was about
promoting reason over emotion.
Marxism is a natural progression of the
French Revolution. Marxism is what
promises
um a victory of reason over motion.
Okay. So what is the AI civilian state?
Ultimately it is techno Marxism.
Okay. That's what they want.
They want communism.
National security adviser to Jimmy
Carter, one of the most powerful
Americans in the world want Marxism.
Why? Because Marxism, communism is the
imple implementation of the ideas of
Freemasonry in our world. All right.
Okay. Is this clear guys?
>> All right,
>> Mr. John.
>> Yes.
>> So, but what is the tech techno Marxism?
Yeah, I'm explain. Okay. Okay.
>> All right. So, this is Larry Ellison.
And Larry Ellison probably doesn't read
books, okay? He's probably never read
read Albert Pike. He's probably never
read Zeban Pisinski, okay? But he's one
of the most powerful men in America
because he found a company called
Oracle.
Oracle,
right? And this is him with Donald Trump
announcing something called Operation
Stargate. So they're going to build the
data centers all around the United
States in order to create their AI
civilian state. Now
Larry Allison is most powerful is one of
the most powerful men in the world but
his background is very very interesting.
He found a company or Oracle at at that
time was called R I RSI. This is from a
biography of Larry Ellison called the
difference between God and Larry
Ellison. Okay. And he talks about how in
the first five years his company was
terrible. They were a database company
designed to collect data and then
organize this data in a way that was
useful to companies and to governments.
Okay? But they were so bad. If you put
data into this computer, they lost all
the data.
They were just incompetent.
But who are their clients? It's the CIA
and the Navy who had unlimited money.
Okay. So the company's incompetent
destroys data but the government kept on
supporting them. Okay. Can you read
Alan?
The funny thing was the early customers
did not really mind losing money or
data. Even though RSI never really
delivered what the CIA wanted, the
agency was not upset. Engineer Kirk
Bradley remembered a CIA employee
telling him, "We bought the things
knowing damn well it wasn't going to
work. We're buying an idea at orate tape
due George did not satisfy the Navy
either." But it did not matter. We were
buying a right flip flyer with the
expectations that we would probably have
an airline in a few years. The Navy John
scale said the Navy understood that
Oracle might crash and burn at all any
time yet it was exciting to try to make
it fly. Uh shield said with a hint of
irony. This is really confusing. Okay,
the CIA, the Navy, you're going to hire
a company because the company's going to
do it cheaper and faster and more
effectively than you can do it, right?
But what happened with Oracle is that it
cost them a lot of money. They weren't
getting what they wanted and they had to
put their own resources to create
Oracle. They had to help Oracle come
into being. So Oracle and Larry Ellison
are both creations of the CIA and the
Navy. Why would they do that?
Okay, that's a very curious question. I
don't know the answer to this. It might
be because Larry Ellison is just a
really charismatic guy. It may be
because he has relatives who work for
the CIA. It may be because he got really
lucky. Who knows? But this is a very
curious fact about how these companies
like Oracle started. All right,
we're also going to talk about this guy,
Peter Theal. Peter Theo is probably one
of the most powerful man in America
right now. I think he's actually much
more powerful than Alan Musk. Why?
because in 2016 he recognized the
potential in Donald Trump and he
supported Donald Trump's campaign. He
also saw the potential in JD Vance and
he supported uh JD Vance's uh venture
capital career as well as his Senate
race and then he promoted JD Vance as
the VP for Donald Trump. Okay. And when
you read Peter Theo even though he's
entrepreneur he actually reads like a
Freemason. It's really really strange.
Okay. So this is from his book from uh
zero to one. Okay. He's talking about
how to build a great company. What he
tells you is this. If you want to build
a great company to compete against other
companies, you're an idiot. Competition
is for losers. Capitalism is for losers.
What you want is monopoly. What you want
is communism. What you want is to
dominate.
Okay? And that means you need a secret
in order to monetize. Okay. Can you
read, Alan? Can you read slowly, please?
>> Yeah. There are two kinds of secrets.
Secrets of nature and secrets about
people. Natural secrets exist all around
us. To find them, one must study some
undiscovered aspects of the physical
world. Secrets about people are
different. There are things that people
don't know about themselves or thing
they hide because they don't want others
to know. So when thinking about what
kinds of company to build, there are two
distinct questions to ask. What secrets
is nature not telling you? What secrets
are people not telling you? If you find
a secret, your face a choice. Some are
more generous than others as false tales
vagner. The few who know what might be
learned, foolish enough to put their
whole heart on snow and reveal their
feelings to the crowd below. Mankind had
always crucified and burned. Unless you
have perfectly conventional beliefs, it
is rarely a good idea to tell everybody
everything that you know. So what do you
tell whoever you need to and no more? In
practice, there always a god golden
means between telling nobody and telling
everybody and that's a company. The best
entrepreneurs know this. Every great
business is built around the secret
that's hidden from the outside. A great
company is a conspiracy of change the
world. When you share your secret, the
re recipient becomes a fellow
conspirator. How do you build a great
company? You create a secret society.
All right? And what's and what's a
secret society? You access the occult.
Okay? If you really want to make a lot
of money, guys, don't spend your time
programming and looking for the best
technology. Don't do that. That's a
waste of time. Look at the occult.
Figure out the secrets of humanity.
Figure out the secrets of the occult and
build your company around that idea and
you will come to dominate. All right.
So, uh he also he he's very clear about
this. Okay. He what he's saying is if
you want to start a company, start a
religion first, man. Okay. Can you read
one?
>> Yeah.
>> The best startups might be considered
slightly less extreme kinds of cults.
The biggest difference is that CS tend
to be fanatically wrong about something
important. People at a successful
startup are fanatically right about
something those outside it have missed.
You're not going to learn those kinds of
secrets from consultants and you don't
need to worry if your company doesn't
make sense to conventional
professionals. Better to be called a
court or even a mafia.
>> Okay. All right. Okay. Does does make
sense? Okay. He's saying it literally
now. Start a religion or start a mafia
doesn't matter. Okay.
Um now Peter the is important because he
had he is a mentor to two individuals
Mark Zuckerberg as well as s Alman.
Remember from last from last week uh we
read Karen how's book uh empire of AI
where sen Alman says that the most
successful founders do not set off to
create companies. They are on a mission
to create something closer to religion.
All right. So he's basically um using
the words of his mentor Peter Theel.
Um this is also what Sman said, people
talk about how much energy it takes to
train an AI model, but it also takes a
lot of energy to train a human. Takes
like 20 years of life and all the food
you eat during that time before you get
smart. Okay, so these people literally
see no difference between an AI and a
human. You're just energy to be
exploited. Okay, you're just an energy
that I need to turn into a cube in order
to create my holy temple of reason. All
right, and this is Pet and this is
another friend of Peter uh Theos called
Alexander Karp who and together they
found a company called Palunteer. What
is Palanteer? Palunteer is the ultimate
AI surveillance company. Okay, so Oracle
creates databases
of information. Everything about you is
on in an Oracle database. Palunteer then
takes this information and predicts how
you'll behave.
Okay. And this is the uh Palunteer
manifesto called the technological
republic. It's it they're not
Freemasons, but they might as well be
Freemasons. Okay. So uh this is the
manifesto and it basically says that we
need to create a technocracy. That's all
it's saying. We we're going to create a
technocracy
an state and that's a good thing. All
right.
All right. And I will leave you with
this.
Peter Theal for the past few years has
been giving speeches around the world
talking about the antichrist. Okay.
What's the antichrist? How much does an
antichrist rise to power? By playing on
our fears of technology and seducing us
into decence with the antichrist's
slogan peace and safety. The antichrist
is anyone and everyone who opposes the
AI civilian state. Okay, so you might
think, "No, no, no, wait. Isn't it more
logically to believe that the AI state
IS THE ANTICHRIST?" NO. PETER T was
saying, "No, it's the opposite, guys.
It's you oppose the state, then you're
the antichrist. The antichrist is evil.
Therefore, we have to destroy these
people." Okay? Whoever prevents us from
building the ax state is pure evil. And
once you understand this then we we will
achieve our holy empire of reason.
Okay. Any questions guys?
>> So can we understand the freemasonry
which is the kingdom of reason as a kind
of brainwash?
>> Okay.
Freemasonry
is
a group of people who practice certain
things. And at the very heart of
Freemasonry is an escological vision of
trying to achieve the end of the world
which is a one world government based in
Jerusalem
and where everyone obeys this government
and if if you obey then the world is
perfect. Okay, does that make sense?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. And so how h how do you get people
to obey? AI, right?
You don't want to work out. You don't
want to study. You don't want to work
and pay taxes. Well, let's have an AI in
your head, a bicycle trip in your head
that tells you, "No, no, no, Vincent,
you should pay your taxes." No, no, no,
Vincent, you shouldn't drive drunk.
Okay? And that's the idea. It's about
alchemy, human perfection, trying to
turn you into an obedient robot that can
be programmed.
Okay? Doesn't make sense. But it's a
good thing because once we do that,
there'll be peace, there'll be
happiness, there'll be safety. It's a
good thing. Yeah. But if that was a good
thing, like what matters about human
subjectivity if the AI fully controls
you.
>> Human subjectivity is bad because it
leads to sin. It leads to errors. It
leads to confusion. You understand? If
we all think alike, the world is not
perfect. We now achieve a common
brotherhood of humanity. We now achieve
God if everyone thinks alike and that's
what AI can do for us.
Any more questions?
Okay. So Putin is coming to Beijing
tonight. So on Thursday we'll discuss
Putin, right?