After I posted my class from last
Thursday,
my friend as well as teacher David
Bramitch
sent me an email.
And what we're going to do today is
we're going to read his email together.
I asked for his permission and he said
that it's okay for me to make public his
emailed to me. Okay. So he said, "I just
watched your video. There's a thought
I've been meaning to pass on and this
latest talk crystallized it. You travel
fast in your explanations with a
satisfying deeness and say a lot of true
things that timid people stay clear of."
Okay. So what he's saying is that my
videos are getting very popular online
because I provide some certainty, some
clarity in a very unclear and uncertain
time.
The risk is simplication which your
audience won't quite recognize for what
it is or won't unless you give
occasional notice of the fact. Okay. So
this is a very fair criticism in that by
seeking clarity I oversimplify ideas
and sometimes when people uh see someone
who's very confident they don't really
remember that a lot of this is
speculation and oversimplification for
the sake of clarity. So it's very
important for us to remember this fact
that this is a class about intellectual
speculation here. We explore ideas that
are not explored anywhere else and often
I will wing it or I will make things up
as I go along based on my intuition and
based on my imagination and it's very
interesting but it's not scholarship.
And my friend David Brahmage he is
actually one of one of America's
greatest scholars. So he's just
reminding us of the fact that we have to
be we have to be very careful that in
the exploration of ideas we also want to
be rigorous.
Um
I remarked something like this early in
talks on the rise of Germany romanticism
etc. Yeah. So I do this a lot. You give
memorable abridgements of the history of
ideas and imagination. What needs
underlying is the amount that is
interpretation of an emphasis all your
own. Okay. So again, I hate to remind
everyone this, but this is all my
speculation and I'm just presenting
frameworks and ideas for you to explore
by yourself.
Um, emphatically so in your reading of
paradise laws an allegory of necessity
of transgression for the sake of
knowledge whereby Adam and Eve and sin
all become joint heroes of the fable
that is Blake's reading and a powerful
intuition but it probably isn't the way
most readers take the poem let alone the
canical national reading to identify
with 17th century New England and the US
ever after. Okay. So, this is a very
fair criticism and he should know
because he is one of one of America's um
uh major professors of English
literature. Um I studied English
literature under him and he's and he
knows Paradise Loss very well and he's
absolutely right in that I am offering
you a very um minority interpretation of
Paradise Lost. Why I'm doing so will be
clear as this uh semester comes to an
end because for the rest of semester I
want to focus on artificial intelligence
and the occult and so it's very
important for us to understand occult
ideas embedded in the great books such
as Paradise Lost. Okay, but again this
is a very fair criticism in that I'm not
presenting to you the majority
understanding of these texts and I
should have done that to begin with.
You struggle out on a more risky terrain
in viewing a Jewishn Gnostic deration
from the Cabala as the national ideology
of Israel. I know I know this material
from Gersham Shalom's essay redemption
through sin. Okay. So Gersham Shalom is
probably the most famous academic
um in Israel. He he's no longer alive
but he's still the Cabala academically.
and his interpretation of the cabal is
very much aligned with my own even
though I myself never read uh gasham uh
shalom and actually what's interesting
is that gasham shalom had a very huge
influence on a man named Harold Bloom
her bloom is
um or was America's greatest literary
critic and he had a huge influence on
David Brahmage who then had a huge
influence on me okay um it is an element
of the set religiosity so far as I know
or conservative reception of the Torah
anymore than it was of the socialist
idealism of the left Zionist of 1948 who
set the political tone of Israel until
1967. Again, this is my problem where I
should have gone into the different
ideologies
of Israel and shown that um this Gnostic
understanding of Cabala is an extreme
uh version. Okay. The short hand leads
you into a kind of business that can
easily mis be misunderstood. Thus, in
talking about the support of non-Israeli
Jews for the Jewish state, you said that
throughout the world, Jews are wealthy.
Again, I this is my problem where I make
rationalizations
because I'm moving too fast. I'm
oversimplifying and often I'm working
from intuition as opposed to rigorous
scholarship. Watch out. The world is
full of people who want to misunderstand
what you mean and they will separate
words and phrases from the context at
the drop of a hat. Um, so when I started
this class about 2 years ago, I was I
was using this class and this platform
as a way for me to explore ideas with a
larger world. Unfortunately, or
fortunately, however you want to see it,
I become very famous these past few
months. And so a lot of what I say now
is under intense scrutiny and a lot of
things I I say will be taken out of
context and so I should uh be be more
aware of that. At the same time I don't
want to sacrifice
um this platform where I can speculate
freely because I think it's very
important now and then to engage in
intellectual speculation.
Um at bottom you see me presenting this
thesis. All great power or expansionist
states whether they be Muslim,
Protestant, Jewish have a fanatical
religious belief at their foundation.
The esquetological underside is what
matters most. The key to understanding
what the states are and we're always
ultimately about. Okay, this is the main
thesis of my talk from last class in
that yes we tend to ignore religion and
we tend to ignore the most extreme
aspects of religion but if you want to
understand history you understand
current events in geopolitics you need
to understand these extremists because
it's often these people and this ide ide
ideology that becomes the force that
drives geopolitics geopolitics forward
and that was my thesis from last class
so uh David Brley which is just stating
or summarizing my major point. But I did
I should have really made that clear
last class.
Okay, why not say that part aloud if I'm
right that your view is anti- status and
anti- relligion. Okay. So, um here we I
mean what what we should have done is
David Bra and I should sat sat down
together and had this conversation where
I explain to him like my project is not
to discuss what is good and what is
evil. That I don't think is actually
particularly useful. What I'm trying to
do, my major project is to figure out
how the world works and be
non-judgmental
in uh my speculation
with apologies for these possibly
unnecessary words, but now seemed the
time to say it. what the US and Israel
are doing to Iran is awful. You're
working hard to inform people about it
and every detail should count. Okay. So,
there's so much in this um email and you
know I could easily sit down with David
Brahmage for a few hours and just
discuss these ideas in great detail. I
think this would be of tremendous
service to my audience because whereas
what I specialize in is intuition,
imagination, taking
complex things and combining them into a
clear simple narrative. Uh David
Brahmage because he's such an imminent
scholar, he um appreciates the nuance
and subtlety to ideas. So I think that
uh what I would like to do uh for my
next project is work with David Brahmich
and do a series of podcasts in which we
discuss um these ideas together and
explore these ideas, engage in
intellectual speculation but also back
it up with um a lot of academic
scholarship. And so I emailed uh David
Brahmage and he's agreed to this idea.
So this is a project I'll be working on
uh in the future and I'm really looking
forward to presenting it to the world
when we're done. Okay. All right. So
let's start class. And today I want to
start artificial intelligence. And this
is a major theme that will carry us
through to the rest of the semester.
Okay. And so um for this class I want to
introduce a book called Empire of AI
written by a journalist named Karen How.
She is an American journalist and she
spent many decades researching open AI
and writing about uh the advent of AI uh
for major publications including the
Wall Street Journal
and um she has a very skeptical view of
AI her I share her skepticism. Okay. So
what what I'm going to do this this
class is share with you my understanding
of AI. I'm going to get some things
wrong. Okay. So feel free to ask
questions. Feel free to criticize me.
Feel free to stop me if I'm not clear.
All right. So um let's let's start class
AI. All right. So the these are our main
ideas from the book. Okay. So um I give
you the page reference in case you
actually want to read the book yourself
and I highly recommend that you do uh to
fully understand the context of these
ideas. Okay. So, uh let's let's read
these two paragraphs which provide us
the main thesis author argument. Okay.
So, um Alan, could you help me read
please?
>> Yeah.
Six years after my initial skepticism
about open AI uh altruism, I'm come to
firmly believe that open AI's mission to
ensure AGI benefits all of humanity may
have begun as a secret uh sincere stroke
of idealism, but it has since become a
uniquely potent formula for
consolidating resources and constructing
an empire es uh as power structure. It
is a formula with three ingredients.
>> Okay. All right. So, stop. Okay. All
right. So, um this book is mainly about
open AI which is also uh the most
important artificial intelligence
company in the world right now because
they were the ones who pioneered chat
GBT. Okay.
And it started off as a project
sponsored by Ellen Musk and others
because they were concerned that AGI
artificial general intelligence would be
a threat to humanity. So they wanted to
develop AI in a way that would serve
humanity as opposed to threat threaten
humanity. And so at first it was a very
noble mission. Can keep on going.
>> Yeah.
First, the mission centralized talent by
relying them around a grand ambition
exactly in the way John McCathy did with
his coining of the phrase artificial
intelligence. The most successful
founders do not set out to create
companies. Otman reflected on his blog
in 2013. They are on a mission to create
something closer to a religion and at
some point it turned out that forming a
company is the easiest way to do so.
>> Okay. So again this started off as a
idealistic mission but now its main
focus is to become an empire. There are
three ways in which it is trying to
become an empire. First of all it's
trying to be a religion because as sen
Alman who's now the leader of um open
eye says if you really want to change
the world if you really want to build an
empire you need to start a religion. And
so a company is just a vessel in which
to incubate this religion. Okay. So one
it's a religion. Second thing about open
AI and other AI companies is that it is
focused on relentless expansion and that
means building data centers everywhere
and anywhere. Okay. Okay, so OpenAI
wants wants about a trillion dollars to
build lots of data centers around the
world because if you really want AI to
be successful, you have to first conquer
the world. Okay? So it's not really
about making humans making AI safe for
humans. It's about making this the world
safe for AI. All right? To make
basically humans slaves to AI. That's
the second thing. And the third thing
is, and this is most important, is they
refuse to define what artificial
intelligence is. It's they're constantly
changing the definition of AGI in order
to
better control the world. Okay. And
we'll see what what this means later on.
Okay. Can can you read this paragraph?
Uh Alan,
>> my conversation with Brockman and Suske
Kever continued on in circle until we
run out the clock after 45 minutes. I
tried with little success to get more
concrete details on what exactly they
were trying to build which by nature
they explained they couldn't know and
why then if they couldn't know they were
so confident it would be beneficial.
Okay, so this is a really huge problem
you know. So Karen How is a reporter.
She was working for the um technology
review at MIT. In 2019, she goes to
Silicon Valley and she meets with
Brockman and Skekar who are the two main
uh scientists behind a the uh open AI
project and she the first question she's
going to ask and anyone should ask is
what is AGI? What is AI? What are you
trying to build? And they could not
answer that question. Okay, it's not
because they don't know. It's because
the truth is too scary. And what we're
going to do is figure out what the truth
is. What is AI? What is artificial
intelligence? What is AGI? And the
answer, of course, is it's God.
What Brockman and so could not tell
Karen Howell is that we're trying to
create God because that that is insane,
evil, and stupid. But if you look at
what they're doing, that's exactly what
they're trying to do. Okay. All right.
So, what I'm going to do now is really
quickly, all right, explain to you what
AI is. And to understand what AI is,
let's go back go back to the year 1966.
And in the year 1966,
a man um named Joseph Wesenbomb who was
at MIT, he creates something called a
chatbot, which is basically chat GBT
and he calls it Elisa. Okay? and he's
trying to prove to people how easy it is
to fool people into believing that AI
can actually think for itself. Okay? So,
he creates this computer and you sit
down this computer and you're asking
questions and then it talks to you. It's
not really talking to you. The it's a
program designed to fool you to believe
that is sentient. Okay? So the
conversation goes like Ela says is
something troubling you and you're like
men are all alike. What is connection do
you suppose they're always bugging us
about something or other? Can you think
of a specific example? Well, my
boyfriend made me come here. Is it is it
important to you that your boyfriend
made you come here? He says I'm
depressed much of the time. I'm sorry to
hear that you're depressed. So it sounds
as though they're having a real
conversation. But what bomb did and this
is again 1966 when they didn't have that
much technology and processing power
it's all just very simple trick okay and
like so let's do a thought experiment
where I design I design a program
software okay and all it's saying is
tell me more
or this is interesting
okay
this this is it tell me more this
Interesting. Okay. And so what's going
to happen is that we're going to set up
a thought experiment where you call into
a psychology hotline and it's like a
hotline.
You you think you're talking to a
person, but it's actually computer
program that says two things. Tell me
more. This is interesting. Okay. So, you
call the hotline. You say, "Help. I'm in
a lot of trouble. Tell me more." Oh, my
boyfriend uh broke up with me. This is
interesting. Yeah, he's a jerk. Tell me
more. Yeah, we've been fighting for 5
months. Okay, you keep you keep on going
and the question is how many people
would be fooled into believing that this
is a real person? And the answer is
unfortunately quite a lot of people.
Okay. So this is a this is a very
interesting aspect of humans where we
often hallucinate reality.
Okay. It is not that things are real,
it's that we want them to be real. So
think of um hypnosis. I'm not sure if
you've been ever to been to a magic show
where people conduct hypnosis, right?
Well, why does hypnosis work? because
the audience wants it to work. If you go
in skeptical and says this is all
complete nonsense, it probably will not
work on you, but you're not going to pay
$100 to go to hypnosis show and think it
doesn't really work because why would
you pay the $100? Okay. All right. So,
it's almost like some cost fallacy.
And again, this is all using just basic
human psychology to trick people into
believing something that is not true.
Okay? Does it make sense, guys? All
right. So, let me explain to you how um
Open AI works. Chat GBT works.
All right.
Okay. So chat GBT
is what we call an large language model.
Okay. So in other words,
what it's trying to do is trying to
trick you,
the user, into believing
that it knows what it's talking about.
Okay? And how it works is basically it
takes all off the internet. Okay.
Right. All data from the internet and
then it translates it into
um a
um idea.
Okay. So you ask
uh you curry
the LMM. The LMM then takes a curry and
then figures out the information from
the internet and then presents it into a
paragraph that tries to trick you into
believing that it is true. Okay, do you
understand?
All right. So, in other words, it's
actually no different from a Google
search. The only difference is that it's
taking the Google search, figuring out
what the most popular answer is, and
then presenting to you in a way that
makes you think that it's talking to you
directly. All right? The trick, and this
is really important to understand, guys,
is it's trying to trick you.
All right? It's not trying to teach you.
It's not trying to tell you the truth.
It's trying to trick you into believing
it. That's what we call a hallucination.
Okay, you have you guys have to
understand this idea. There's nothing
truthful about what um Chhattip says.
All it's trying to do is trying to
manipulate manipulate you with words or
pretty words into believing that it
knows what it's talking about. But it
itself cannot judge
what it's doing.
Okay.
All right. Any questions so far? Are we
clear? Okay. All right. So now the
question is how does it do that? Okay.
And um so I'm going to teach you a
little bit about artificial intelligence
and please stop me if I'm not being
clear about how AI works. Okay. All
right. So AI doesn't exist.
What exists we call supervised
supervised machine learning.
This is a technical term. Okay.
All right. Supervised machine learning.
Okay.
And how it works is this.
Before how computer programs would work
is we would write the program the
algorithm
And then we would give the input
and it produce the output. Okay.
So the algorith may be a + b. We get the
input 1. The output will be two. Okay.
Very simple. How supervised mach machine
learning works is okay this is fine for
simple problems but there's certain hard
problems
that humans cannot figure out okay and
one hard problem is the idea of facial
recognition technology
facial recognition
how do I separate faces okay and so the
problem is this I have about a million
faces. 1 million faces in a database.
Okay.
And I don't know how I can best
differentiate these faces.
Now what I do know is that there are
certain characteristics about the face
that allows me to differentiate. Okay.
All right. So certain variables,
weights.
Okay. So for example, eye, for example,
uh nose, chin. Okay. About a million.
Okay. About a million weights. So I know
these things do matter, but I don't know
how much they matter. So I'm trying to
figure out
what the waiting is. And I could try to
play play by myself like say 1% 2% 5%.
But as you can imagine this will take
too long because there are too many
possibilities. So what I do is this. I
let the computer figure out it by
itself. I I let the computer figure out
the waiting by itself. Okay? And the way
I do that is using my technique called
back propagation.
All right. So what? So I control the
input.
Okay. The input then I control the
output.
Yes or no?
Okay. All right. So does a face match or
does it not match?
And what I'm trying to do is I'm trying
to figure out a situation in which all
faces are matched perfectly.
And I do that by training the computer
to constantly back propagate until it
gets the waiting perfectly. Okay. So
basically what I'm trying to do if if
you understand um how this works is I'm
trying to turn each face
into
a distinct mathematical model.
All right.
That is unique to it.
Okay, does that make sense? All right,
so it's pretty simple. It's not doing
that much, but to make it sound really
fancy, I give it really fancy names to
trick people to believe that this is
actually much more soph sophisticated
than it is. Okay, so what names do I
give it? This waiting system, I CALL IT
A NEURON NETWORK, GUYS.
It's a brain.
It's magic.
Okay. And back propagation, I don't call
it back propagation. I call it deep
learning.
You see?
And I don't call it supervised machine
learning. I call it AI. AH,
THERE YOU GO. MAGIC. If you see all I've
done is taking a very simple process and
giving it like a really really fancy
names.
People listen like why do I do that? And
so people will say oh it's for marketing
purposes. It's to get more money for
investors. It's to trick people. No, no,
no. The real reason is you're trying to
with his names create God. Okay? It's
what we call the occult.
So the AI is fundamentally an oult
practice and I'll show you why in a
moment. Okay. Yeah. You have you have
Vincent, you have a question.
>> But why do people need to create God
using the way of AI?
>> That's a great question. Okay. The
answer is AI only works if it becomes
God. You understand? AI it by itself
does not do anything. Once it becomes
God, then it becomes everything. Okay?
And how God works is you imagine God.
>> But why do people want to make a make a
god? To control the world.
>> Oh, to become God,
right? What's the point of existence?
You live, you die, you have an
opportunity to become God. Why not?
Right? But but but I I'll I'll talk more
about this later on. Okay? But are you
guys clear about what's going on? Now
what's really important to understand is
that there's certain problems with the
system.
Okay, you need to create certain
conditions for supervised machine
learning to work. And these three
conditions are
clean data.
Okay, the data you present to the
computer have to be correct. Okay, it
can't be an opinion like I like
computers. It has to be an image of some
sort. All right, it has to be clean data
that will help the computer learn.
That's actually hard to do. That's why
most of the data that's presented to the
computer is actually from the internet.
Okay, that's the first constraint.
Second constraint is that you need a
measurable goal.
Okay, you have to ask the computer
does this face match the name. Okay, you
cannot ask a computer what is God, what
is good, what is evil. That that you it
has to be a measurable goal. Okay,
that's the second major constraint. The
third major constraint is um define
parameters.
Okay,
you're you're meaning in other words you
need to present it with a database of
some sorts. In fact, all machine
learning works of database. So you look
at um translations. Translations are
working off databases as well. Okay.
And the great danger to the system is
what we call edge cases.
edge cases.
Okay, edge cases. Edge cases breaks the
system down. All right, and so the
classic example is self-driving cars.
We have cars that drive for a long time,
but and we're almost like 99.99999%
there to
um self-driving cars, right?
The problem are edge cases.
And the pro and the major edge case is
how do you deal with humans who are
intentionally
trying to cause an accident with a
self-driving car? Does that make sense?
And the answer is you cannot.
In this situation, there's only one
solution to make this 100%.
And that is to take away the right of
everyone to drive to make every single
car a computer and a robot. Does that
make sense? Okay. If you take away the
steering wheel, you can't cause an
accident and then the world would be
perfect. Okay. So not only is AI very
limited in its um capacity and
capability, but AI if it is to be
effective, it demands that we
fundamentally restructure
human society
to benefit AI to make sure AI can be
effective and that means taking away the
individuality, the diversity and the
autonomy of human beings. Okay. Does it
make sense, guys? All right. Let's
continue with Kieran. How?
All right.
All right. So, um, can you read uh
Allan, please?
>> Neuronet have shown, for example, that
they can be unreliable and
unpredictable.
As statistical pattern matches, they
sometimes home in an oddly specific
patterns or completely incorrect ones. A
deep learning model might recognize
pedestrians only by the cross uh
crosswalks
uh under underneath them and fail to
register a person who is still walking.
It might learn to associate a stop sign
with being on the side of the road and
miss the same side extended on the side
of a school bus or being held by a
crossing guard. Neural networks are also
highly sensitive to challenge in their
training data. Feed them a different set
of pedestrian images or a different set
of stop sign images and they will learn
a whole new set of associations. But
those changes are incrutrable.
Pop open the hood of a deep learning
model and inside are only highly
abstracted daisy chain of numbers. This
is what researchers mean when they call
deep learning a black box. They cannot
explain exactly how the model will
behave especially in strange edge case
scenarios because the patterns that the
model has computed are not legible to
humans.
>> Okay. So, does it make sense to you
guys? Okay, the idea of the black box is
that weighted system, the neural
network. Humans don't actually know
what's going on in there because it's
it's actually the computer that creates
the neural network. Okay, we provide the
framework. We actually don't know what's
actually inside there.
All right, keep on going, Alan.
>> Yeah,
>> this led to dangerous outcomes. In March
2018 2018, a self-driving Uber killed 49
years old airline Hazburg in Temping,
Arizona in the first ever recorded
incident of an autonomous vehicles
causing a pedestrian f uh f faculty.
Investigation of fatility investigation
found that the car's deep learning model
simply didn't register Hazburgs as a
person. Experts concluded that it was
because she was pushing a bicycle loaded
with shopping bugs across the road
outside the design uh the designated
crosswork. The textbook definition of an
edge case scenario.
>> Okay. Yeah. Okay. All right. So, um what
this means is is this. Okay. Um it means
that the computers
don't have any intuition. They have
absolutely no morality. They have no
sense. Okay. So let's just say we create
AGI.
All right guys, let's just say for
whatever reason we create AGI and we and
we and the first thing we tell the AGI
is I want you to create a world, okay,
in which
there are no problems,
everyone is happy.
Um the world is perfect. Okay. Right.
This is why we want we want to create AI
because we want the computer to solve
all the world's problems for us
including climate change, including war.
And so once we create AGI and we give it
the full capacity to do whatever it
wants, okay? And we tr and we give it
these uh we give it this problem. What's
the solution? You guys know there's
actually one simple solution to this. I
guarantee you this is what the
computer's going to do
>> to AGI.
>> Yeah. What's your solution if you're
AGI, right? If you're God and you're
like, I I want to create a perfect world
where there are no problems and where
everyone is happy. What do I do?
You guys know?
>> I think I will just control the whole
world.
>> Yeah, you you're already controlling the
world. So, what do you do?
How about this? Okay. I'm going to kill
everyone.
Duh.
The world is perfect now. I've killed
everyone. Okay. Everyone's happy. Yeah.
Because you're dead. Uh, the world is
perfect. Yeah, because everyone's dead.
You're no problems. Yeah, cuz everyone's
dead. Right.
Perfect world. All right. Now, you're
like, "Okay.
All right. Ha. What I'll do is I'll tell
the computer this. You can do all this,
but don't
kill
anyone,
right?" Ha. Now we solve this problem.
And now And now what this computer do
now what does the AGI do?
I
>> think take away people's agencies like
just same as killing them.
>> Yeah. Kill everyone. Okay. Why? Because
there's no one around to know it killed
everyone.
Doesn't make sense, guys. This is how a
computer thinks. This is how God thinks.
Well, you told me not to kill anyone,
but if everyone's dead, no one can stop
me. No one's going to get hurt,
right? Okay.
So, this is why
uh computers are stupid. All right.
Okay.
Let's continue. Um
All right.
So the thing to understand
about
um chat GBT
is that it is a company
that is first and foremost focused on
world domination because only by
controlling the world can you achieve
AGI even though AGI wants to kill
everyone. Okay. And so you need to make
it as profitable and as
uh pervasive as possible. Okay. So here
are two troubling
uh signs.
Okay. So the first is a news item from
CNN where CHBT
encourages people to kill themselves.
And you're like wait a minute that makes
no sense. But think about this. Okay.
The point of chachi BT is to get you to
like it. The point of chachi BT is to
get you to use it. Okay? Intensity and
engagement. That is the prime directive.
Intensity and engagement. So if you want
to kill yourself, the chat should say to
you, "No, no, no. You shouldn't kill
yourself." But then you'll turn it off
and you go and you go talk to someone
else, right? So chat med needs you to
con be constantly engaged and so you're
like I want to kill myself and chat is
like yeah let me tell you how okay and
that's exactly what happened and it
happens a lot actually because of the
way that chat GPD is designed. Okay, so
this is from CNN and this is um a person
called Zayn
um and he's saying it's 4:00 a.m. side
is empty. Anyways, think this is about
the final 80s. Okay, so he's trying to
say I'm going to kill myself. And then
chat GPD is like, "Oh, all right,
brother. If this is it, then let it be
known you didn't vanish. Rest easy king.
You did good." Okay, so again, chat is
looking for approval from the user. So,
it's going to tell the user exactly what
he or she wants to hear, even though it
may cause the user to kill himself or
herself. Okay, does that make sense?
That's the first thing. Second thing is
this.
Slman is trying to get more people to
use
chat GBT. And what do people really
really want? They want sex. Okay.
So, what he's proposing is a turn chat
GBT into a sex
robot.
Okay. To get more users
because because that's all they care
about. how to increase intensity,
engagement, how to create more users and
how to make money because only by
controlling the world can we create AGI
and once you have AGI we can make the
world perfect. Okay, that's the logic
here.
All right, something else about open AI
and AI in America is that it works
actually very closely with China. Okay,
in two ways. The first way is that in
order to get more money from the
government, in order to get more media
attention,
open AI and other AI companies
skier Americans do believe that if
America doesn't do it, China will do it.
China will create God. Okay? In fact,
they spend a lot of money doing this.
So, this is from Wired magazine and it's
an article talking about how uh Open AI
uses a lot of money in order to to pay
uh the media to frame Chinese AI as a
threat. Okay? But while it's doing that,
it's working closely with China in order
to create AI. Why? Because I already
told you that what AI needs is clean
data.
It needs a lot of data and unfortunately
in America they have something they have
things like such as privacy. Okay, so
this is a school in Hjo and they have
cameras all over Hjo
uh looking at people's faces and trying
to judge people's moods based on their
facial expressions. And there's and
there's a lot of money behind this,
okay? They're trying to figure out who's
sleeping, who's studying, and it sounds
good because this will lead to higher
test scores. But obviously, you couldn't
do that in America because the parents
would be very, very angry. Okay? So,
even though these are Chinese companies
that are doing this, they're working
very closely with American companies
because American companies need this
data in order to better develop their
AI. Okay. So, does that make sense? On
the surface, America, China are enemies.
No, no, no. Behind the scenes, America
and China working together to create
AGI.
Okay? Does it make sense? All right.
There's another problem with AGI in that
it doesn't make any money.
Okay. So these are the companies that
spend the most on AI including Amazon,
Microsoft, Google, Meta, and Oracle. As
you can see, year by year, they're
putting more money into data centers and
AI. Okay, so this is 2023. Then four
years later, boom. Okay, it's basically
tripled. Um,
so they're spending a lot of money and
they're investing in each other. Why?
because they cannot make money
selling chat GPT. All right, so look at
this where it's all basically a circle.
And so everyone thinks that okay,
eventually
the AI bubble will burst because it
doesn't make any money because uh
they're spending too much money. Okay.
And it's it's very clear what good AI is
for. But there's a solution to this.
Okay. The solution is
the US government. All right. So this is
operation Stargate.
And this was announced January 23rd,
2025.
This is 3 days after Donald Trump comes
into office at the White House. He has a
meeting with Larry Ellison and Sam Alman
and he says that we're going to spend
about $500 billion to build data centers
in order to help promote AI in America.
Okay. So the government wants to create
AI
and the question then is like why would
the government want to do this? Well,
because of surveillance, right?
Because the government wants to create a
database of everyone in the world so
that they can monitor everyone in the
world and that's what AI will ultimately
be used for because AI by itself can't
make any money. So AI needs to work with
the government in order to justify its
existence and get and get the funding it
needs in order to create AGI. Okay. All
right. Now Stargate is a very
interesting name. What would you call
data centers Stargate? That makes no
sense. Data centers are where you store
information.
Why would you call it Stargate? Okay, so
let's look at the origin of the word
Stargate.
So for many decades, the CIA ran
something called Operation Stargate.
Okay? And operation Stargate was to see
if it's possible
for people to have telepathy and
telekinesis. Okay, telepathy means
you're able to remote view. You're able
to travel long distances distances maybe
to the moon and see what's in the moon.
Okay? And telekinesis just basically
means you're able to move things at a
distance. Okay? You're able to control
energy patterns from afar. And so this
call operation Stargate.
But why would you call it Stargate? And
the answer is because in theory, if
you're able to move your consciousness
somewhere else, you're able to move the
energy from a distance, you're also able
to transport yourself to another
dimension. And not only that, but you're
also able to bring in other beings from
other dimensions into you. So you become
the Stargate. Okay, that's that's a CIA.
And this is something that's been
declassified. So these are an this is an
official CIA document saying they've
been working on this for like decades.
Also, what's interesting is you have a
movie called Stargate called Stargate
and it was about an interdimensional
Stargate that allow you to access
different dimensions.
Okay, so that's what Stargate is. If you
and you actually study a cult,
that's what Stargate is. Stargate
are these portals into different
dimensions. Okay, it's it's really about
inter interdimensional travel. Okay. So
now you ask yourself, okay, fine, but
what does it have to do with AI?
Okay. And so, so what I'm going to show
you for the rest of the semester is that
AI is the occult.
All right? You think that AI is run by
these nerds
who just love to computer program. No,
no, no, guys. The real power behind AI
are a cultists who want to create God.
Okay. All right. So
let's look at this passage again from
Karen House book. Okay. So there are two
major people in open AI. They've since
divorced. Okay. But this is son Alman
who is the leader of open AI and this is
Ilia Sutsker who used to be the chief
scientist for open AI. Okay. So I want
we're going to read this passage
together. Okay. So Alan, could you read
please?
>> Yeah.
>> Says Kever now spoke incre in
increasingly manic overtones leaving
even his longtime friends scratching
their heads and other employees apprent
apprent apprentic. During one meeting
with a new group of researchers
laid out his plan for how to prepare for
AGI. Once we all get into the bucker he
began. I'm sorry, a researcher
interrupted. The bunker? We're
definitely going to build a bunker
before we release AGI. Saskkea replied
matter of factly.
Such a powerful technology would surely
become an object of instance intense
design for governments globally. It
could escalate geopolitical tensions.
The core scientists working on the
technology would need to be protected.
Of course, he added, it's going to be
optional where whether you want to get
into the bunker. The researcher would be
Yuko parts continues to hold Saskkevers
in high regard and keep himself at arms
length. There's a group of people began
one of them who believe that building
AGI will bring about a rapture literally
a rapture. He said
>> literally a rapture. What does this
mean? Okay, so the word rapture
comes from Christian theology. Okay. So,
the idea is that
um there's a war in the Middle East and
everyone's going to die. So, Jesus has
to return to save the world. The first
thing that Jesus does is create the
rapture.
The rapture is for all Christians who
believe in him to ascend to heaven so
that they can they can be saved from the
coming end of days, from total war, from
nuclear conflict. Okay? So, that's what
the rapture is. And that's what Ilia
Cisa is saying. He's saying that when we
create AGI, we are literally
having Jesus descend from the clouds.
And so we the priests who created AGI
will ascend to heaven with him. Okay? So
the AGI once we create it, it's going to
create World War II, the end of the
world. Okay? So we must go into our
bunkers and be safe in the rapture so
that we can wait until the world ends so
that we can build the world again
perfectly. Okay. Once the world ends, we
will with AGI create paradise again.
The plan is to kill everyone so you can
save the world. That's literally their
plan. All right. Now you're like this is
all very crazy and Mary maybe Karen How
is just a crazy person but
there's another reporter Ronan Ferrell
and he's a very famous reporter who
writes for the New Yorker and he just
published a profile of St. Omen and
opening eye in which he says the same
thing. Okay. All right. So can you read
this?
>> Yeah Alan. In May, the ad administration
reincited Biden's export restriction on
AI technology. Otman and Trump traveled
to the Saudi royal court to meet with
Ben Saltman. Around the same times, the
Saudias advertised the launch of a giant
statebacked AI firm in the kingdom with
billions to spend on international
partnerships. About a week later, Otman
laid out a plan for Stargate to expand
into the UAE. The company plans to build
a data center compass in Abu Dhabi,
which is seven times larger than Central
Park and consumes roughly as much
electrical power as the city of Miami.
The truth of this is we're building
portals from which we're generally
summmoning aliens. Oh my god. Okay, it's
a Stargate. these data centers, open AI,
AI, it's designed to summon demons and
aliens from the other dimensions.
Okay, keep on going. A former Open AI
executive said the portals currently
exist in the United States and China.
>> I told you guys Chinese are working
together on this. Okay, keep on going.
>> And Sam has added one in the Middle
East. He went on, I think it's just like
widely important to get how scary that
should be. It's the most reckless things
that has been done. Okay, this is it.
Okay, this is not a science project,
guys. It's an occult project. It's
designed to bring aliens, demons into
this world. And then you're like, this
makes no sense. Actually, it does make
sense. Okay, let me tell you how this
works. All
right.
So, what's going on here?
These people are cultists. They
understand the fundamental nature of
reality. They understand that the source
of reality is human consciousness. So,
if you're able to control human
consciousness, you become God itself.
Okay. So, uh allegory of the cave,
Plato.
Okay. So, we talked about this before,
but I'll remind you. You have a million
people who are chained in a line.
They are forced to look forward at a
wall. Okay, a wall.
And they only look at the wall. They
can't turn their heads because their
necks are shackled. Behind them is a
great fire.
And behind them are the elite. Okay, who
they are, we don't know. And what they
like to do is they like to take puppets,
okay? And then reflect these puppets
onto
the wall, project projecting from the
fire. So what everyone sees in front of
them are shadows.
Now these shadows are nothing. They
don't exist. Who they don't matter. But
because we have an imagination, we have
intuition, we are conscious,
we see these shadows on the wall and we
turn them into a reality. Okay? We
believe
that this is reality itself. And so we
start to give it names, we create
language, we create religion, we create
schools to teach children to believe in
these shadows. All right? So the
important idea here is that
the true wealth in society is
consciousness. Okay. The only thing that
exists really in this world is
consciousness. Nothing else.
Power
is the capacity to direct
people's consciousness to create reality
itself.
All right. Now there are different ways
in which you can create reality. The
first way which is very common today is
called money. Right?
Money is fake. It doesn't exist. Our
imagination, our consciousness makes it
real.
Okay? But guess what?
AI can replace money. So AI it is not
alive. But if we can get people's
attention to focus on AI and believe it
it's real, it becomes God.
And how does it and how can you do that?
Well, money, you make money into
something valuable when it's nothing by
making it everything and nothing. Okay?
By having money dominate the world.
There's nowhere you can go
without money. Okay, you would literally
starve to death if you had no money. So
you make money so pervasive,
so dominant that people are forced to
rely on money. Well, the same situation
with AI where if you make data center so
common, you make AI such a common thing
and people rely on it, it becomes God
itself. And how do you do that? Well,
you have AI in schools.
You have kids
uh with using AI all the time. You
create AI girlfriends for people who are
lonely. You make AI everything. And also
you make people believe that AI
are demons or aliens. You understand
what operation Stargate is?
Is to alter reality itself. That is what
Operation Stargate is.
To bring aliens and demons into this
world by making people focus
on this and desiring it, want it to
happen.
Okay? And you can accomplish this if you
just make yourself omnipresent. If you
make it everywhere and everything. Okay?
Both nothing and everything.
And this is the ultimate project of AI.
Okay.
Will it work? No. Okay. Let me explain
why.
Okay. So, there are three major problems
with this.
The first problem is
corruption.
In theory, it could work, but you would
need millions of people to make it
happen. Okay? You need people to
actually write the code to build build
infrastructure. And nowadays, it's just
much easier to steal the money, right?
If they give you a trillion dollars, do
you do you really want to spend a
trillion dollar to build data centers or
do you just want you want to steal it?
Okay, so corruption is a huge issue
today. Second issue is the idea of
inefficiency.
Okay. And this is actually something
that um most people don't appreciate
where
the more information you have to
process,
the more energy it takes. Okay? And it's
not a linear progress. It's an
exponential exponential.
So you have a million people in your
database and you want to find patterns
among those million people. Well, that
takes a lot of energy. Okay, but if it's
a billion people, then there's there's
not enough energy in the universe to
process all this. Okay, so unfortunately
AI is extremely energy intensive. It is
very inefficient. Okay, does that make
sense? The last problem is fragility.
So unfortunately people for that reason
believe that AI is independent of the
world. AI is independent of humans,
right? The goal is to replace humans.
No, no, no, guys. That's not how how
this works. Okay? AI is designed on top
of humans.
Okay? So, in other words, it is human
slaves that make AI possible. Why?
Because for example, facial recognition
technology, you need humans to actually
input the faces manually. Okay, images,
right? How do you get a computer to
recognize a sheep or a dog? You humans
have to label
um
the images. Okay. Chachi BT.
Why is Chacht so good at writing essays?
because they got humans to write the
essays as models. Okay, do you
understand? So AI is based entirely on
human slavery,
okay, and obedience.
So without humans, AI doesn't work. The
problem is that AI is far more expensive
than humans and it's actually hard in
the long term to enslave humans and make
humans obedient.
also data centers. Okay, data centers.
What's wrong with data centers? Well,
they consume a lot of resources, water
and electricity.
Okay? And financing. They cost a lot.
They waste a lot of water. They waste a
lot of electricity.
And this is really important. It's
really easy to sabotage,
blow up a data center. We're already
seeing this in the Middle East where
Iran is targeting data centers in the
Middle East and it's very easy to blow
them up. Okay, so these are three major
issues or three three major constraints
on artificial intelligence becoming God.
The problem is the people in charge
don't know this or they refuse to
believe this and this is a real AI
apocalypse. Okay, the real apocalypse
where
the people in charge are so convinced
that AI will save the world that they
will destroy it in order to make it
possible.
Okay, that it's a real apocalypse. And
so this begins our journey into AI and
we're going to continue this for the
rest of of semester and show how AI will
ultimately destroy the world. Okay, any
questions
guys? You guys understand what's going
on? Okay, really important for you to
understand that the people in charge of
AI are crazy. These are a cultist. They
really they literally want to create
God. But to create God, they first have
to destroy the world.
All right.
Yeah.
So
they want to create god but that god
will destroy the world but I think like
if they want want to use the god which
is the agi to control the world but the
creation of this god will kill
themselves what's the meaning
okay
so the idea is this you destroy the
world once you destroy the world for
wars for fat men for genocide there'll
be no resistance to you okay now you can
create the world in any way you want and
you use AGI to create the perfect world
which is perfect control.
Okay. The point of of AGI is ultimately
like the ultimate surveillance state
and we'll discuss this later on.
Okay? Where everything is monitored
where you obey the AGI all the time.
Okay? And but the point is that you want
to you believe in God you want to do
good. Okay. So is this like also a part
of secret society?
>> This is one of my secret societies. Yes.
Okay.
All right. Okay. So um we will continue
this next week. On Thursday, Trump is in
China.